<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
<title>PodSni dot co dot uk</title>
<description>PodSNI's HOME PAGE</description>
<language>en-gb</language>
<link>https://podsni.github.io//rss.xml</link>
<atom:link href="https://podsni.github.io//rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
<title>Pancasila</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/pancasila.html</guid>
<pubDate>Jum, 19 Mar 2021 12:53:47 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="pancasila">Pancasila</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>Ketuhanan yang Maha Esa</li>
<li>Kemanusiaan yang adil dan beradab</li>
<li>Persatuan Indonesia</li>
<li>Kerakyatan yang dipimpin oleh himat kebijak dalam permusyawarantan / perwakilan</li>
<li>Keadilan sosial bagi seluruh rakyat indonesia</li>
</ol>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Neuromancer and the dubious perentage of Cyberpunk</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/neuromancer-and-the-dubious-perentage-of-cyberpunk.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sel, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="compilations-of-definition.">Compilation’s of definition.</h1>
<p>Arguing about what is or isn’t Cyberpunk is tedious, however I find myself in this endless slog of a debate regularly. I like Cyberpunk no matter what it actually is. With this in mind I want to define what I consider a reasonable definition not of cyberpunk but of rules that must not be broken in order to maintain “Cyberpunkyness”™ :D (Fuck me, that sentence was a ramble.)</p>
<pre><code>1. Must be the future but too far into the future and we get dystopia sci-fi. </code></pre>
<p>Cyberpunk must always be on the horizon of our children’s lifetime. It’s that fear that invokes something in us. Some simmering dread that its already started and we cant stop it (Because… well.. yeah.)</p>
<pre><code>2. If space travel exists, it must be Newtonian in nature. </code></pre>
<p>Warp drives and worm holes dull the edges of Cyberpunk with hope for a new world. This world is all we have and for Cyberpunk to hold it must be on the brink of collapse. Any second now, the food runs out, the electric goes off and no one cares that you have a cool robot arm.</p>
<pre><code>3. High technology and Low quality of life being standard while the 1% live outside it. </code></pre>
<p>We are all the underclass in Cyberpunk. It’s the story of the death of 99% not the heroic 1%er who will save us all. I know, It’s grim.</p>
<pre><code>4. Cyberpunk is a setting not a story telling style. Get over it. </code></pre>
<p>It’s a backdrop to a story. The story its self doesn’t much matter. Be it a noir detective story or a gang war. Cyberpunk is a setting. With very few exceptions there does not exist a “Cyberpunk narrative”.</p>
<p>The exceptions include:</p>
<ul>
<li>William Gibson’s Neuromancer novel (Not the whole trilogy)</li>
<li>Total Recall, yes, THAT movie (<em>really, yes that one!</em>)</li>
<li>Some people smarter than me will swear that the first Deus Ex video game should be on this list.</li>
<li>William Shatner’s Tek war Novels (This one is a joke, not its not. I don’t know. No. Yes… Leave me alone.)</li>
</ul>
<p>There’s a couple more but who has time…</p>
<pre><code>5. Cyberpunk is an 80s vision of the future, ergo, cyberpunk is quintessentially 80s in tone.</code></pre>
<p>I know, people have some issues with this one. Let me break this down. In the 80’s when people thought about what the world would be like when their kids were old they saw neon and leather with fast cars, awesome robots and mega corporations ruling our lives. They saw the cold war being a lot warmer and technology was out of control. Japan seemed like it was going to take over the world with the personal stereo and home computer. Cyberpunk is William Gibson’s vision of the future that he cast out while only just managing to not be living in Orwell’s 1984. If we look to the future now we get something deeply darker that is simply masquerading as that Cyberpunk future we all secretly want. It’s not the same.</p>
<pre><code>6. Cyberpunk is an end not a beginning. It&#39;s not the sign of things going south, they done and gone south already.  </code></pre>
<p>Much like Dark Souls is a world that is hearing its own death rattles echoing off its walls. Cyberpunk is a vision of our own world once the hope is taken out of it. It is a dead collapsed world. It’s a pre-apocalyptic synthetic nightmare. A world where self interest is the only thing left. A world where all optimism has been left to rot because it no longer serves the human condition.</p>
<h3 id="do-not-email-me.">Do Not email me.</h3>
<p>I know you disagree with these ‘rules’ that’s fine. I don’t care, don’t email me. They are the guidelines that I use when thinking about Cyberpunk as a conceptual setting. Still mad about rule number 5? Fuck off! I’m right on that one. Don’t email me. DO. NOT. EMAIL. ME. ABOUT. THE. ABOVE.</p>
<p>(I know, I’m getting emailed about that)</p>
<h2 id="the-lineage.">The lineage.</h2>
<p><em>Okay, everything on this website is my opinion. I claim no expertise or insight. Because of this, take the following with a grain of salt…What does that phrase actually mean? I should look that up, I won’t.</em></p>
<p>Cyberpunk was born on the 1st of July 1984 when Neuromancer was Published. William Gibson created something that spawned a genre of fiction that didn’t quite fit into anything else. It was later given the Monica “Cyberpunk”</p>
<p>Sure, there were things that came before that were Cyberpunky. But Gibson made something so good that it had to be something different. It was Cyberpunk in its first <em>and</em> final form.</p>
<p>Sure, we had the Blade Runner movie that came in ’82, but that was a pre-punk visual soup that was retrospectively given the mantle of punk. At its release it was just science fiction film noir.</p>
<p>But I’m getting ahead of myself…</p>
<p><em>this is a list of shit that came to mind when I thought about this stuff. NOT every work on the road to cyberpunk.</em></p>
<pre><code>1927 Metropolis (Movie)</code></pre>
<p>Fritz Lang created the awesome metropolis. I’ve not watched it for a long time now but I can tell your that the classes were divided by the sea of privilege and technology was exploding. We don’t have cyberpunk yet but it’s the first time we put the ingredients into the bowl. Class divide isn’t exclusively Cyberpunk but it is required in order to be Cyberpunk.</p>
<pre><code>1956 The Stars My Destination (Novel)</code></pre>
<p>I did a <a href="https://hexdsl.co.uk/posts/book-club-the-stars-my-destination-by-alfred-bester.html">Book Club post</a> about this one a while back. Didn’t talk about the Cyberpunk angle. So that’s an oversight I guess. In this book we have the required class divide as well as high technology. The most striking thing in this for me (regarding Cyberpunk at least) is the nihilism of the lead character. His own personal mission matters more than anyone else’s life or reasons. During the course of the book he becomes wealthy and renowned but in the end revenge and oblivion is his only goal. It’s got some serious proto-cyberpunk vibes to be at least. Also, damned fine book.</p>
<pre><code>1968 Do Android&#39;s Dream of Electric Sheep (Novel)</code></pre>
<p>My dude Philip K Dick. Wrote this story about a dude who wanted a sheep (yep) and as all things penned by Mr Dick, it’s fucking great! Ahead of its time and written like a fever dream. This is a classic work that a lot of people seem to think they can skip because “I saw the movie” - well NOPE! This is vastly different work to what became Blade Runner. Its way more of a direct comment on the nature of life and how that is reflected in social norms. Sort of, anyway it’s NOT Blade Runner. It’s a grade ‘A’ quality science fiction story but lacks the visual imagination that we came to recognise as Blade Runner. It also lacks the focus on oppression to be really Cyberpunk.</p>
<pre><code>1977 Star Wars (Movie)</code></pre>
<p>Star Wars: A New Hope. A movie that put a brick in the road that leads us to “real” cyberpunk. I know, You are shook. Well.let me make the effort to make my case.</p>
<p>Many things led to Star Wars being a thing. Its influences are broad and far reaching (whatever shit Lucas thought was cool) but the visual disparity between the fashion and architecture of the rebellion and the Empire is striking.</p>
<p>The Empire are all hard plastics and classical lines. The rebellion are all flannel and metal. The striking difference between the two is similar to Cyberpunk depictions of the upper class, the 1% having more elegant classical fashion while the underclass literally wears whatever works at the time. Even the architecture represents this with clean white vs war torn junk.</p>
<p>The Empire have giant ships and unlimited resources that they use to hold an iron grip on the universe. The rebellion have some busted X-wings and a lot of spunk. Much like the operations making sure the rest of humanity never have chance to better themselves.</p>
<p>The war is over. The Empire won. They don’t fight because they think they actually stand a chance. No no, they are holding the line today in hopes that they can live to hold the line tomorrow. It’s only when they luck out and a Magic Skywalker man comes and fucks shit up that they suddenly have a real shot. That Death star was going to obliterate them, it wasn’t called a ‘Fun Star’. They had lost hope, it was all they could do to just keep fighting because they had no other options left.</p>
<p>I honestly think that this changed the narrative of popular science fiction. We suddenly not only wanted the underdog to win but they stood no chance and we still waved our light sabres for them. One man changed the narrative. Its not Cyberpunk, not at all cyberpunk. It did however show the divide and do so in a deep visual way that splashed a little with a neon glow of the engines and light sticks.</p>
<pre><code>1977 Judge Dredd (Comic)</code></pre>
<p>Judge Dredd, started life as a few pages in 2000AD but eventually become a monster of series in its own right. Its Cyberpunk as all heck, NOW. But in ’77 is was a story of dystopian justice. Its hyper-violent and gritty but lacks the key visual components to send it over the line. Dredd is a judge and executioner but not much of detective. It’s and empty unimaginative war zone that’s a washed out Cyberpunk imposter. Great for what it is but we are not there yet.</p>
<pre><code>1981 Valis (Novel)</code></pre>
<p>My boy Philly K Dick at it again. This time he tells us the simply baffling story of VALIS. Honestly I can’t even begin to break this one down but it is in part about a satellite that may have gained conciousness (or not.) Valis is about religion madness and obsession but there’s something deep in there that feels like a little crumb on the road. You should read it and you will know what I’m talking about. I should re-visit it for a Book club post. I may do that. Good idea me! Also that Satellite, not unlike Wintermute from Neuromancer.</p>
<pre><code>1982 TRON (Movie)</code></pre>
<p>Tron. God. I love Tron. I know its terrible but it speaks to me on spiritual level… Anyway it merged sentient AI, Neon and nonsense in a way that we have not seen again until Tron Legacy. Its visual style including its interesting use of negative space put another firm brick in the road to punkyness.</p>
<pre><code>1982 Blade Runner (Movie)</code></pre>
<p>This is the movie that lesser bloggers than I (lol) credit as the first true cyberpunk work. Its true that this is basically that but its a poor entry when it comes to wider world building. I don’t think its truly become cyberpunk yet.</p>
<p>I have no intention in breaking down one of the most well known movie’s of all time. Don’t worry.</p>
<p>Blade runner did an exceptional job of being visually rich and grim but for me its the fact that our view into this world is that of a cog in the machine of oppression, that alone prevents this from really being a real cyberpunk work because we never see it from the point of view of the people who live in it. Deckard (Wait, was he called that? I don’t remember) is a police man and a killer. He maybe in a Cyberpunk looking world but our hero is nothing less than an actual part of the problem. Its like saying that Casablanca is a war movie because there was a war happening in the background. Cyberpunk was happening around the story of blade runner but we never once get to bask in its glory.</p>
<pre><code>1984 Neuromancer (Novel)</code></pre>
<p>“The sky above the port was the color of television, tuned to a dead channel” - Neuromancer first line.</p>
<p>Finally the meandering road comes to its conclusion with one of the best books ever written. Neuromancer is a work of genius (That I plan on doing a proper post about once I do my yearly re-read) It takes little nuggets from all the things that came before it boiling them all down to their essentials and simmering them until they are ready.</p>
<p>The world is richly explored through the first few chapters and we see the state of things through the eyes of the lowest classes. We see that they hang on to the slightest advantage imagining that it will some how make them special or unique. Under it all they know that hey are simply trying to stave off their final end for just another day, to simply exist for the next.</p>
<p>Our lead character (Case) imagines himself to be in danger at the start of the book. Being paranoid and defeated. Ready to give it all up because he thinks he has attracted a harbinger of death (Molly). Eventually he gives himself to his fate. This marks the start of Neuromancer, where any other book would have ended. For This story we start after the character things its all behind him. We see a new chapter in his exhausted tragic life.</p>
<p>This book is not a work of cyberpunk because of its visual imagination, or its story, or its characters, or its technology. Neuromancer is Cyberpunk in EVERY way. It was this vision, this overwhelming consistency that led to it being the first truly cyberpunk work. No matter how you looked at this, it was something else.</p>
<p>No other work managed to so wonderfully show a world quite like the one that Gibson crafted. He not only had a grasp of what it was he wanted to make but the skills to forge it.</p>
<p>Remember the controversial rule 5 I made at the start of the post? Cyberpunk is an 80s vision of the future? Well yeah. It is. This book was the thing that solidified that as a thing. It has to be an 80s vision because it was the 80s when Gibson crafted a new world. When he decided what exactly this thing WAS. It was his vision of the elusive future from that point in time, with the baggage and attitudes of that moment.</p>
<p>Neuromancer was the shining example of a genre that it pulled from the simmering pots of older works and it did so totally and completely. It was simply too good to ignore.</p>
<h2 id="and-then">And then?</h2>
<p>Once Neuromancer was with us it took 20 years or so for it to really soak in. Even now there are debates across the internet as to what IS and IS NOT Cyberpunk. Its not something I actually care to dip into but I can tell you for certain that up until the universe allowed Gibson to bring forth Neuromancer there was nothing that was quite Cyberpunk. It was the standard by which all things Cyberpunk must be judged.</p>
<p>People often talk about the next great Cyberpunk ‘thing’ but personally I think its a setting that, although I love it, is destined for the oblivion it promises. The reason new things don’t look quite right as Cyberpunk works is because that time is behind us. Much like 50s futurism became retro-futurism and 70s science fiction became classic sci-fi its well past time to say Cyberpunk is dead. It has to be, because the empty meme “Cyberpunk is now” is actually a reasonable commentary on the genre. We have self driving cars (sort of) as well as more computing power than any human could need. We have 3d printers, cooperate spy’s masquerading as voice assistants in our homes and computer maps in our cars. We live the Cyberpunk future more and more every day and from our point of view we dodged the nihilism and oppression that Neuromancer promised. I wonder, if in 30 years time someone will look back and ask, did we really? Because as far as I can see, all me are really missing is flying cars and a robot arm or two.</p>
<p>Given how few works are truly Cyberpunk I wonder if it was ever really more than a backdrop to other things. Was it ever a genre. Was Cyberpunk ever actually born or just a trailer to a movie that was never made.</p>
<p>We need to cast out a new vision of the future. We need to see what the future may hold when we look out from the technocratic Olympus we live on and ask not what’s next for Cyberpunk but instead what can we see from here. What is next? What is our vision of the future. Because Cyberpunk is dead.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Book Club Deaths End by Lui Cixin</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/book-club-deaths-end-by-lui-cixin.html</guid>
<pubDate>Rab, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="does-it-ever-end">Does it ever end?</h1>
<p>Death’s End is the third instalment of ‘The Three Body Problem’ trilogy. The trilogy is not an easy read, its at times an oppressive slog. It’s not cheerful. Its not bright and its not optimistic. But it is wonderfully well written. Obviously the credit for this goes to the writer, Liu Cixin but we have to have to send quite a lot of thanks to Ken Liu who translated this work from its original Chinese into English. The translation is naturalistic and flowing. Honestly it did not at all read like it was a translated text. Great work my dudes!</p>
<p>I am not a smart man. This was made more obvious than ever when, 200 pages into Death’s End, I realised that I was not reading the first book in the Trilogy, I was reading The last. Not my finest moment. I know, ‘How does that even happen?’ I hear you scream. Well, the trilogy was recommended to me by a friend in a voice chat. It sounded good but, as always I try to avoid too much ‘exposure’ to stories before I read them. If you own a Kindle (which I do) and you search for ‘The Three Body Problem’ it will by default sort it in order of recency/popularity. So the book in the series that get displayed to you are in the reverse order. Being lazy I clicked on the first one that was on the Kindle, titled in the store as ‘Deaths End: The Three Body Problem.’</p>
<p>I honestly thought it was written somewhat cryptically on purpose and by the time I realised my mistake, I was 200 pages into the 595 page slog. So screw it, I went ‘ride or die’ on it and slogged on.</p>
<p>As it turns out this book isn’t a direct continuation of a story its more a third part in the sense that it is influenced by the events of the earlier portions and takes place in the same universe. I was able to decipher most if the events through the exceptionally well written flow of the work. I honestly think that by the end I had pretty much got it all. History and outcome, political motivations and people. It’s all subtly re-capped through events.</p>
<p>It takes actual effort to read and you will not be dipping in for a few pages. This work will demand your attention. It’s a slow and surgical read that expects you to keep up. Also, in case you are bored of reading already, it’s bloody good!</p>
<h2 id="the-premise.">The premise.</h2>
<p>Now, I’m not someone who cares about spoilers in the traditional sense, I try to go into books ‘untouched’ but I don’t obsess about not known things. That said, this entire post will be as spoiler free as possible because this work is dense and I honestly can’t break it down in a way that will be useful.</p>
<p>Its the future, humans are in a state of war with some aliens called Trisolaran’s and our ‘hero’ Cheng Xin spends her time being a mild mannered aerospace engineer. Things happen and she has to work on a planetary defence project. The aliens are on their way and they know EVERYTHING because they have invisible spies on earth who can instantly transmit our plans home. The spies are called Sophons and they are cool AI things that the writer makes an effort not to explain in too much detail.</p>
<p>Eventually she sends a man’s brain into space, in hopes of getting some intel! - That actually makes sense when explained in the book.</p>
<p>Some other things happen and Cheng Xin has an adventure in time and space via the power of Cryo sleep.</p>
<p>And that’s all the plot you are going to get out of me.</p>
<h2 id="the-execution.">The execution.</h2>
<p>Fuck. Just… Fuck… This thing is a real, proper science fiction novel the likes of which I haven’t seen since the 60’s. It respects its reader enough to not spoon feed and it respects its science enough to explain the principals on which its based and does so in a naturalistic way that doesn’t feel forced.</p>
<p>The characters are rigid and dedicated but not in a badly written way. They are wooden in a quite direct and intended delivery all the way through. Each person we encounter in the entire novel is dedicated to the goal of saving the human race and that is a motivating fire that pushed them to be all business, all the time.</p>
<p>There was a moment early on when I thought it was a result of cultural differences between Chinese and English story telling styles, or just the writers individual style. Then I met the character “Sophon” (Not the previously mentioned Sophon spies that we can’t see but an individual woman) She was an tornado on unpredictability. Her demeanour never matches her goal and her methods are borderline insane. I loved this character, she is the perfect woman, while also being deeply disturbing. Honestly a wonderful antagonist (for a bit.)</p>
<p>Another character I enjoyed was Ai (艾AA) a warm young woman who becomes cold at times because thats whats required of her, some times coldness being the only choice a person could make in times of struggle. She is both the soul of the work (at times) as well as being the eyes voice of our species (as Cheng Xin seems to hear it.)</p>
<p>Structurally the story reminded me of the classic ‘A Canticle for Leibowitz’ but was a stronger narrative because the lead character is with you from start to finish.</p>
<p>While the work is oppressive (and it really it) the overall experience as you read seems worthwhile and feel like its going somewhere. It has a point and its makes it elegantly. This point is that we need to work together and humans are idiots who’s self interest is destroying us as a planet. But it doesnt reach out slapping up with this point. It illustrates it through story. Ironically there is a portion of the book dedicated to a fiarly tale that has hidden meaning. Deaths End its self is somewhat like that. Its a parellell that a lesser writer would congratulate them selves for right away but this novel lets you unravel this your self and is all the more wonderful because of it.</p>
<p>The one thing that put a big downer on the whole thing, for me at least is that it didn’t really nail the ending. I won’t spoil it, obviously. I would have liked to see more of a pay off to the events. It’s almost like the writer went “yeah, that’ll do” and just stopped. There were at least two other places it could have ended that would actually have made it more emotional and poignant.</p>
<p>Also there is an event in the last act of the book that I’m fairly sure was supposed to shock and delight me. I saw it coming miles away. Not sure if I was alone there. I’ll have to talk to some other people who have read it.</p>
<h2 id="the-post-book-cool-down.">The Post book cool down.</h2>
<p>The moment I finished the last page of this book, I felt like a weight had been lifted from me. Finishing this book is like ending a hard day of work. You feel better for it and you need a little time to recover. That said, I picked up the first book and started slogging through it the very next day. I feel like its a book that rewards you for sticking with it and I owe it to the characters to see exactly how we got to the point we did at the start.</p>
<h2 id="do-you-recommend-it">Do you recommend it?</h2>
<p>I loved it, but not until it was over. I felt like it was something I needed to get through and at one point regretted ever starting it. But over all it is something that I won’t soon forget. It really is the best example of “hard” science fiction I have read recently. My love of harder edged science fiction is the main reason I mostly read older books. The main difference is that the older books have a pretty real vein of optimism and hope going through them that this work was missing by design.</p>
<p>This story would not have worked with a super hopeful lead character and thats its main defining feature. Oppression is a features of the style of this work, in a way that is integral to its gravitas. When most book are all down in the dumps to seem cool and Emo its a thing I hate but Death’s End would not have been the same work if it were anything else. Partly because its not trying to be cool and Emo. Its honestly a reflection of its self, it would have been vastly different if you felt like it was a throw away romp.</p>
<p>If you think you will make it through the Three Body Problem, don’t start with this book. But when you get here, you won’t be let down.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Why I Dont talk about things I dont like</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/why-i-dont-talk-about-things-i-dont-like.html</guid>
<pubDate>Jum, 11 Des 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="critique">Critique</h1>
<p>When I read a book, or play a game that I don’t enjoy, the bit of my brain that wants to talk about said thing just doesn’t kick in (Unless its bad in a <em>really</em> interesting way)</p>
<p>Usually I want to talk about the things that I enjoyed because:</p>
<ul>
<li>I’m enthusiastic about them.</li>
<li>I want other people to love the things I love.</li>
<li>I want to signal boost the things I enjoy.</li>
<li>I want the people who make the shit I like to make money. So that they make more shit for me to like.</li>
</ul>
<p>I do sort of worry that the perception on my Blog and/or YouTube channel is that its all fluff and no critique. I worried about it a lot actually. The truth is that my brain gets to its opinions and ideas by obsessing over things it enjoys. When I don’t like a thing, it simply doesn’t get mind-share.</p>
<p>I talked about some Arthur C Clarke stuff I read an didn’t enjoy a while back but it was interestingly uninteresting to me and that game me something to noodle on, and eventually blog about.</p>
<p>I also don’t think its entirely bad to be a hub of positivity on the internet. When people see a new blog post they are like “oh, cool, something Hex liked, something I may like!” not “ewe”</p>
<p>Creators and writers like Jim Sterling are pretty great at ‘Hating’ things, its a skill. A skill that I don’t really have and don’t want. I want to enjoy things and not waste time on things I don’t enjoy.</p>
<p>That said, even when I enjoy things, I’m not blind to its flaws. I think I do a reasonable job of outlining the bad in the things I talk about but overall its usually a thing I enjoyed. Sometimes/usually in spite of its flaws.</p>
<p>Its been a tough month for me, personally. I had Covid. There was a death in my family and honestly, I wasn’t okay for a little bit back there. I’m fairly sure that my habit (addiction?) of focusing on things I enjoy and always looking for something new to enjoy was the thing that stopped me falling into a hole of sorts.</p>
<p>It’s not even optimism or naivety. I just love to like things. I want to fill my brain up with all the cool stuff. I don’t want to waste energy on shite.</p>
<p>Not sure if I had a point here. Just felt like sharing some thoughts. I guess that’s what a blog like this is for.</p>
<p>Hex out. Be cool, Stay in school.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Book Club EXTRA Stranger in a Strange Land VIDEO</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/book-club-extra-stranger-in-a-strange-land-video.html</guid>
<pubDate>Rab, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="stranger-in-a-strange-land-post-but-now-theres-a-video">Stranger in a Strange Land post but NOW THERES A VIDEO!</h1>
<p>I wanted to try my hand at Book Club post in video form, here is it.</p>
<p>This video currently isn’t listed on YouTube, not sure if my usual audience would enjoy it. I may make it listed depending on what you guys here think.</p>
<p>All comments welcome (as always)</p>
<div class="xpeng">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XlGYkhN_Mtc" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>
</iframe>
</div>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Book Club Benvari Mountains By Michael Chatfield</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/book-club-benvari-mountains-by-michael-chatfield.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sen, 26 Okt 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="for-emerilia">For Emerilia!</h1>
<p>I accept that at this point, I’m hooked on this crap. Honestly. Its like the author is manipulating me some how. I know its easy reading LitRPG crap. But… God, I love these characters. I read this one, the second volume of the Emerilia series in basically two sittings. Its shorter than the first one but the right amount of words for the story that is told.</p>
<p>This volume tells the story of the Party (now known as Party Zero by their Guild, the Stone Raiders) making the journey to Benvari Mountain so that Dave can complete his training as a Master Smith.</p>
<p>The early portion of the book introduces Suzy, Daves assistant from when he was Austin, back on Earth. She has ventured into the game after realising that there was something up with his “shell” on Earth. She knew he played and saw his avatar on a live stream (ref first books fucking epic ending) while she could see him in “real life” figuring something was amiss. She logged in.</p>
<p>Suzy quickly gets clued into events and becomes Emerilia’s second “Bleeder” (The shitty term for someone who knows that its not a game and doesn’t need to return to Earth, ever.) She quickly starts levelling up and integrating into the world. The Party set off to Benvari along with two human form dragons and an AI that helped bob create the world given physical form. Yeah. It’s still fucking stupid. Like the first novel this one gets by on its characters who are all lovely people who are constantly trying to do the right thing.</p>
<p>There’s also some time spent fleshing out the Stone Raiders and making sure you know they are going to be a large part of the story going forward. This is a wise move and they are missing from most the book. Off on a different part of the world while Dave and the party study and train.</p>
<p>Upon reaching Benvari Mountain Dave starts his training. This is the bulk of the story. Dave training. There’s essentially no villain in this one. Nothing really “bad” happens and its just like a novel sized training montage. I loved it. I loved that nothing of real note happened and that it was entirely the author basking in the world he created.</p>
<p>If I have to be really critical of this volume, the writing really lets it down with regard to Dia and her seemingly casual attitude to being separated from her lover for months. I think the intent here was to define her as a strong person who looks always forward and doesn’t dwell on her personal feelings when the party has its own goals. But, it comes off like she doesn’t give a shit. Also There are some moments in combat portions where I literally have no idea whats happening. I just sort of powered through until it was all over.</p>
<p>The one thing the book does really well though is make you REALLY understand how powerful Daves Smithing and Rune skills are. He can create just about anything he can think of and I have no doubt that this will be a major focus on the next book (I already started it! Its the most most addictive reading I’ve encountered in years!)</p>
<p>This is like the wonderfully warm calm before the storm that we know is coming and I am excited to tag along.</p>
<p>So, yeah, not much to say about this one. I can see a lot of readers bouncing on this one because of how little actually happens but those who (like me) enjoyed the heck out of it will be well set for the next volume.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Book Club The Trapped Mind Project By Michael Chatfield</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/book-club-the-trapped-mind-project-by-michael-chatfield.html</guid>
<pubDate>Kam, 22 Okt 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="litrpgs-are-my-jam">LitRPGS are my Jam!</h1>
<p>There is a category of book called the Literature Role Play Game (LitRPG) the basic premise is that a character is either stuck in a video game or reality <em>is</em> a video game and our hero figures it out. Some times its neither, its just a video game like setting, but we have character sheets and “skills” for no real reason.</p>
<p>LitRPG novels are essentially low hanging fruit in the modern age. They are usually badly written trash with no depth or real soul.</p>
<p>I fucking love them!</p>
<h2 id="about-this-one.">About this one.</h2>
<p>I had not read any Michael Chatfield before. This being the first in a series of 10 (11?) books seemed like a safe read. It was at least good enough to spawn a whole series so it was bound to be fun if nothing else.</p>
<p>The novel is set in the world of Emerilia this is the <em>real</em> world. Earth the place we all live is actually a high speed VR-type experience that the alien race in control uses to “educate” and “train” us. Then when we log into VR to play Emerilia, thats actually us logging out of VR and into reality.</p>
<p>The aliens to this to use humans to fight aggressive species that are a potential enemy to them, they use Portal technology, Nanobots and science thats just “magical” to get this done.</p>
<p>Yeah. It’s low brow. I know. <strong>But</strong> it also has great characters, well established rules and it’s remarkably compelling for the nonsense it is.</p>
<h2 id="are-you-an-idiot">Are you an idiot?</h2>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p>I read a lot of hard edged science fiction that challenges me as well as opens me to new ideas. Science Fiction that is borderline philosophy stuff. I love it, and it generally makes my life better in some small way. LitRPGs on the other hand are wonderful palette cleansers and generally joyful experiences.</p>
<p>This one however is way better than the trash I usually read. Way more compelling than I expected.</p>
<p>The story follows “Dave” or at least, that’s what his “character” in Emerilia is called. On Earth he is known as Austin and he’s is a billionaire who hates his life. He logs into Emerilia to just relax. Not interested in fighting mobs or doing quests. He just wants to build a house.</p>
<p>Spoiler territory events happen and he meets a gnome names Bob. Bob is essentially a god. He is the creator of Emerilia and he tells our hero all about what reality actually is. Turns our Dave, or Austin at least is important to the simulation of Earth. He has become to important that if he where to vanish the entire world economy would collapse. Because of this the AI that runs earth simply “Took over” when he logged into Emerilia, or out of the simulation.</p>
<p>This is the first time someone pivotal to the earth sim has also been a gamer. The term bob uses for this is a “Bleeder” because Dave/Austin exists in two worlds.</p>
<p>It really is basically nonsense.</p>
<p>The book grabbed me because of the wonderfully delicate tone it takes with Daves progression in the world. We follow along while he builds his house and makes new friends. The hill his house is on is settled by Dwarfs and Elves and soon becomes a little town. Its incredibly warm and human. Many LitRPGs rush to make the main character a power house. This books is not power fantasy, its friendship fantasy</p>
<p>Dave eventually becomes a Blacksmith, meets a girl, learns to fight, learns to cook and hangs out in Emerilia deciding that as he doesn’t have to log out, he wont. He lives in Emerilia now as one of the people.</p>
<p>The People who where born on Emerilia are referred to as NPC by the players then as they get to know them, they move over to POE (People of Emerilia) even this tiny change shows the love the writer has for the world.</p>
<h1 id="this-sounds-wholesome-but-boring.">This sounds wholesome but boring.</h1>
<p>Eventually some “players” (Ass holes who think that Emerilia is a game… Because it is to them) set in motion the return of a powerful citadel that promises to destroy, well, the world.</p>
<p>Dave and his buddies have to raise an army, organise the players and take on the big bad. They know exactly how much time they have and what needs to be done. They just don’t realise the scale of the enemy.</p>
<p>The bulk of the book is Dave learning to live in Emerilia and be ready for the fight. He works hard on his armour, learning how to use magic and how to fight. Its entirely character development and progression. I loved every moment of it.</p>
<p>The story is pretty consistent and doesn’t fall into the trap of forgetting its premise early on like some do. It’s constantly playing to its strengths and doesn’t at any time change or forget the rules it laid out.</p>
<h2 id="so-we-talking-epic-master-work">So we talking epic master work?</h2>
<p>Gosh no! The writing is often a little on the weak side and Mr Chatfield commits the crime of repeating him self quite a bit. The characters and the world are so good though, that I forgive it all. I instantly started the second volume!</p>
<p>The last time I was this ‘into’ a series that I <em>knew</em> was a bit trash was the Magic 2.0 series I read last year. A series that I’ve since re-read about three times. Some times I just for this type of story.</p>
<p>I’ll check back when I finish the next volume (I have all of them on my kindle. This is the start of a truly epic binge!)</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Book Club The Stars My Destination by Alfred Bester</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/book-club-the-stars-my-destination-by-alfred-bester.html</guid>
<pubDate>Kam, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="tiger-tiger">Tiger! Tiger!</h2>
<p>Sometimes I worry that I read too many books with the word “Stars” in the title. This one I literally did not choose for the name though. I had a vague recollection of a book I bounced off when I was a teenager. All I remember was that there was a main character who could teleport. Oddly I even remembered the word the book used for this;“Jaunting.”</p>
<p>I’m not sure that I even remembered this when I first gave the books opening a “sample read” (I like to check if my mood matches the authors vibe, stops me bouncing off things) as soon as I saw the word “Jaunt” I knew that this book was going to be eating a few evenings of my life.</p>
<h2 id="a-jaunt-through-the-plot.">A Jaunt through the plot.</h2>
<p>This book was published in 1956 and some of the questionable dialogue is very much “of the time.” Its a little uncomfortable in places. Yeah, another one of those. I seem to encounter a lot of dodgy shit in old sci-fi. Anyway…</p>
<p>Its the future, maybe the 24th century. Mankind has been in the stars for a while, or at least in the space of the local star. Its never made clear how widely the pesky humans have travelled. Our local solar system has been tamed though that’s for sure. The Inner Planets (referred to as IP in the book) and the Outer Planets (OP, who guessed it? Yeah! Go you!) are at war. It’s the backdrop of the story though, Alfred Bester doesn’t waste our time with anything as mundane as an epic fucking space war!</p>
<p>Humans have mastered personal teleportation (Jaunting.) They have done this as apparently, an evolutionary step. The theory is that you think about a place you have been, concentrate and with all your will you “thrust” yourself there. Then you arrive. That’s it. The science is never actually explained in a way that makes any sense. I think that this is intentional.</p>
<p>Rules are nice and simple too, you have to have been there and memorised the location your self. The location is referred to as “coordinates” but it seems more like you can just take a look around and remember the general position. Its kept thankfully very vague because Bester knows that its not interesting to get bogged down in this stuff. Also you can take with your anything you can carry while walking. So no cars, but if you lift a bicycle up, you should be a able to take that. You can’t Jaunt while drugged in any way. Getting a hit on the head will short your ability out for a while and you have to know both where you are and where you want to go, In relation to each other. Oh and It cant be off world, or in space. You can’t teleport while on a space ship, or from a planet to a ship.</p>
<p>One last bit, Some people can go up to 10 miles, some up to 1000 miles and everything in between. The maximum range seems to be related to “will” and <em>maybe</em> intelligence, its not really stated. Oh, and most people can do it pretty effortlessly.</p>
<p>This makes of an interesting setting. People hide their houses from view so that no one else can Jaunt in. Some don’t even have doors. You can commute to anywhere for work and its the only form of personal transport that matters. Interesting stuff right? Yeah it is!</p>
<p>Even this interesting setting is not the focus of the book though. In this book we follow Gully Foyle. The last man left alive on a space ship that was attacked. He uses every trick in the book to stay alive and when a ship comes close it sees him. It abandoned him to his fate. The ship VORGA becomes a major motivating factor for Gully. He becomes obsessed with destroying this ship and making its crew pay for abandoning him. Its the motivation he needs to survive.</p>
<p>He eventually finds his way to an inhabited asteroid where some mad isolationist tattoo his face and try to marry him to a random woman. He escapes this quickly and begins a fast paced adventure that takes him to many an interesting and entertaining place.</p>
<p>He goes to prison, does a heist, becomes a billionaire, kidnaps a telepath, takes revenge as required and gets super powers. Oh, And at some point he seems to be stalked by a flaming ghost…. Yeah. A lot happens.</p>
<p>The book is fast paced to say the least. Actually a lot faster than I usually enjoy. There are moments when we jump forward in the characters life by a few months and it takes some time to get used to the new reality we find him him.</p>
<p>Gully starts as a tough and uneducated space worker and evolves into a cold calculating genius of sorts. His transformation is very natural and you can really see why he feels the need to get the skills that he does. Its a shame that the gaining of these skills is done between chapters (this is where the jumping forward in his life come from) and I would have loved to read about his methods for getting to these new places and situations. Its not a short story collection though its a single very strong narrative that feels like it has bits missing by design.</p>
<p>There few characters in this. There’s Gully himself. Robin a ‘One way telepath’ (Transmit only), A wonderfully blunt and jaded woman names Jisbella and the people trying to capture Gully. Who are quite well fleshed out in their own rights.</p>
<p>I wont spoil the later portions of the plot though. I think its best discovered.</p>
<h2 id="this-structure-sounds-familiar.">This structure sounds familiar.</h2>
<p>Its pretty obviously based on the book The Count of Monte Cristo (1844-1846 Serialised, by Alexandre Dumas) A book I’m not fantastically familiar with (I knew the story form a movie… Don’t judge me, I added it to my reading list)</p>
<p>I think this constant jumping forward and leaving parts of the journey a mystery is partly because Bester was trying to ape the structure of the Monte Cristo story. As I said, it really did work for me.</p>
<p>I feel like Gully himself is something of an inspiration for the Riddick character in those moving pictures but I have no way of telling (and a web search would be boring.)</p>
<p>This is one of the oldest books I have read that reads like a modern Movie. It’s pretty well put together over all.</p>
<h2 id="you-said-it-had-some-dodgy-ideas.">You said it had some dodgy ideas.</h2>
<p>There is something I hate about this book. Gully. The main character is a literal piece of shit. He’s a rapist, murdered, thief and general all round dick. I hated him. I feel like I’m supposed to think of it as a redemption story of sorts but I just wanted someone to murder the git.</p>
<p>Even when towards the end of the book he is the ultra civilised version of himself. Educated, reserved and focused on more than himself, I still hated him.</p>
<p>I feel like there are no consequences to his actions. He rapes a woman who later helps him. He steals and gets away with it. He leaves someone for dead who later treats him like an old friend. Over all he has a pretty shitty life but its all because he wont just get over his obsessions. You cant call that redemption. You call that a self destructive arse hole.</p>
<p>When the main character is so terrible its hard to not let that reflect on the message of the over all novel. That said. I read it all. I really enjoyed it but more for the setting and supporting “cast” than the plights of Gully. I wanted to know how it would all end while really hoping for someone to put a bullet in this fuck.</p>
<h2 id="narrative-thoughts">Narrative thoughts?</h2>
<p>The odd gaps in the story are jarring and could have been better handled. Some really interesting stuff is glossed over like it doesn’t matter and there are times when I felt like I had missed a page. But over all. It was solid. Odd, but solid.</p>
<h2 id="you-recommend-this-or-not-then">You recommend this or not then?</h2>
<p>Yeah, my hatred of the main character aside its really well written. I read it fast because its written fast. I feel like it was in a rush and it was fun to tag along. If you can either enjoy hating Gully or see his point you will enjoy it. If you can’t stand him and don’t enjoy that feeling then stop early on, it doesn’t get better. He really is a total and utter shit.</p>
<p>I’m going to charge my kindle now. Bye.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Book Club Pattern Recognition by William Gibson</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/book-club-pattern-recognition-by-william-gibson.html</guid>
<pubDate>Min, 30 Agu 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="yes-i-am-aware-of-mr-gibsons-opus.">Yes, I am aware of Mr Gibson’s opus.</h2>
<p>This book was published in 2003. William Gibson wrote it (I know, Blowing your mind with FACTS!) The last time I read a new William Gibson novel was about 15 years go. Maybe more. It’s odd to me that I don’t seek out more of his work considering that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuromancer">Neuromancer</a> is one of my favourite books ever.</p>
<p>I should really to a “Book Club” post about Neuromancer specifically. Also, that gives me an excuse to re-visit it, yet again. I didn’t want to wite this and have people only read the opening, then tell me how I should read “The Sprawl” trilogy. I am quite familiar with the author. I “love” at least some of his work and I “like” more. So please don’t read this thinking its my first ride.</p>
<p>Today however, we are here to talk about Pattern Recognition…</p>
<h2 id="words.-so-many-glorious-words">Words. So many glorious words!</h2>
<p>William Gibson knows how to write. Fuck me. He knows how to write. He spins a novel in a way that makes it read like poetry without being so boring as to strive for rhythm. His work reads effortlessly cool. Something about the way he puts the words on the page make you “feel” the places and the moods. He does things that will have you swear he is borderline supernatural. He was good when I read The Sprawl Trilogy but now (this one was published in 2003) he’s, well.. Back to “fuck me.” He maybe the most elegant writer I have ever clapped eyes on. He climbs inside your damned mind with nothing but mystique and a cool that is uniquely his own.</p>
<p>With all that in mind, it may come as an odd redirect that I didn’t really “love” this novel. I adore his writing style and the beats that keep the plot moving but ultimately I didn’t give a shit about the actual plot. I was there for my fix of his style not for the resolution of the story. I know, an odd mix of feelings.</p>
<h2 id="whats-it-about">Whats it about?</h2>
<p>Cayce Pollard (Case, I raised an eyebrow too, there is no connection) is a marketing consultant and hunter of new street fashions and movements. She is framed as being somewhat remarkable at what she does.</p>
<p>She lost her father in the 9/11 attack. And I do mean “lost” as in, he went missing but is assumed dead however this is a side story and emotional fuel for the character and not a real part of the narratives main thread.</p>
<p>She has an odd allergy like reaction to brand labels and trade marks. It is assumed that this sensitivity aids her in her job. Allowing her to see through the fake and embrace the authentic. Interesting concept that I really liked.</p>
<p>In her personal life she follows a series of web videos known only as “The Footage” that are around 40 seconds long and are uploaded randomly to assorted locations on the web. Remember this was 2003 so there is some period context for all this. The detailed descriptions of her logging on to the web, and using cyder cafés brought back some very nostalgic memories for me.</p>
<p>Eventually she is hired by “Bigend” yes… that name… The owner of a marketing organisation to “find” the “maker” of the footage.</p>
<p>In 2020 we would consider this whole thing an ARG and the puzzle would be solved by reddit in about an hour. But in 2003, it was a different time. The internet did not have the power and reach that it does now. I think in some ways this hurt the story. Gibson had to do things in such off ways where as now he could use GPS, wifi and global mapping to spin a much more intricate tale I think.</p>
<p>She then makes some logical leaps that baffle me a little. Makes some new friends. Has some out of context memories. Goes to japan to get her hair cut, and then to Russia to wait for a reply to an e-mail. Theres more narrative around this in the book. But my summery is quite accurate. I assure you.</p>
<h2 id="thoughts">Thoughts?</h2>
<p>The main plot, searching for the “Maker” is almost an after thought each event on the journey seems almost an after thought. Mostly we bask in the characters perceptual tangents and indulge in the descriptive wonder that Gibson uses constantly. It’s incredibly how consistently palatable the writing is given the density and verboseness of it. I would have been just as happy reading William Gibson’s diary I think. Imagine how deeply he could make me feel “putting on socks” and “buying a new jacket.”</p>
<p>The logical leaps that Cayce maker though are a little strange to say the least. At one point she really does go to Russia on the off chance some email will turn up and lies to her employer, who is an unexpectedly nice bloke, even though Cayce is convinced otherwise.</p>
<p>If any other writer had led me on such an ultimately pointless journey I would have thrown my Kindle at the wall and tried to forget how to read.</p>
<p>Also the obsessive mentioning of “Buzz Rickson” Jackets drove me mad. For a character who is obsessed with avoiding labels she banged on about her jacket like it was product placement. It actually may have been given that Rickson have a “William Gibson series” of jackets. Yeah. That rubbed me up the wrong way.</p>
<h2 id="so-should-i-read-it">So should I read it?</h2>
<p>If you have never read Gibson’s work, start with Neuromancer. It has it all. Its just THAT good.</p>
<p>If you have already drank from the well of Gibson, and liked it. Yes. Read this. As I said. I loved the journey even though the points along the way fell flat for me.</p>
<h2 id="closing-thoughts-sir">Closing thoughts sir?</h2>
<p>Gibson’s effortless cool and affinity for the digital makes me wonder why he doesn’t go way more sci-fi than this. It’s ultimately a mystery novel with a lot of technology. I want him to dig deep into the future and show me something wonderful.</p>
<p>I won’t be reading the next in this series but I had a wonderful time with this little dip.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Motivation and an Id</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/motivation-and-an-id.html</guid>
<pubDate>Kam, 27 Agu 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="making-videos-is-a-strange-ego-trip.">Making Videos is a strange ego trip.</h2>
<p>Whenever I upload a new YouTube video I am acutely aware of the inflated sense of self importance that this implies. “Look at this thing I made. For I am soooo learned. Revere my wisdom” is the inner judge that I hear sarcastically spitting at me whenever I press upload on any form of “educational” video. It’s less verbose when I upload an opinion on a game. In that case it simply shouts “Who the fuck cares what you think fat boy?” Yet, I still post.</p>
<p>There are two things that I need to tackle here in this dissection of my Id…</p>
<h3 id="why-post">Why post?</h3>
<p>I post because I think my videos are my way of sharing back in the free software community. I can’t really code well enough to be of use. No one wants a Dyslexic writing their documentation and I’m not good enough at trouble shooting to be one of those helpful internet forum angels. So, I make videos giving little “demystifications” or “overviews” of things when I see a need. The bulk of the time though, its my attempt at trying to be a good citizen of Linux by not going on about the technology, by not being that “Linux guy” but by promoting the platform with good vibes and showing people a happy Linux user playing the games he loves. My channel has its origin in that idea. When Steam first game to Linux people mocked it for “Having no games” and I wanted to prove it was a great platform. It all sort of snowballed from there.</p>
<h3 id="why-the-inner-heckler">Why the inner heckler?</h3>
<p>That question is not as easy to answer. One one hand, I KNOW for a FACT that there are better gamers out there. That there are actual trained reviewers out there. That there professional technical support teams out there. There are actual geniuses out there who are all over the YouTubes. What gives me the damned right, the arrogance to be wasting peoples time?</p>
<p>I don’t know, not really. On some level I see myself at that Linux “everyman” you know, proving that this can be home for anyone. Proving that anyone can make videos. Part of this whole <em>thing</em> is that I hope to inspire giants. I want to be the guy that sparks the interest of the next teenage Torvald. Maybe my outlook, demeanour or content will be a wonderful spark for something really worth while. Maybe.</p>
<p>Also the people I meet on my travels around this baffling internet enrich me. I have friends I would never have known. I hang out in discord and on IRC and maybe I give a little contact and warmth to someone who needs it. I think, a little that its a rightness in the world, in my world at least.</p>
<p>Ultimately. I like making videos. It gives me something to do. A motivation and a purpose beyond playing a lot of DOOM, or PUBG. It gives me that sense of worthwhile that I am otherwise lacking.</p>
<h3 id="and-every-good-blog-has-a-conclusion.">And every good blog has a conclusion.</h3>
<p>I never said this was a <em>good</em> blog. Actually, I started a sentence, a Heading no less with “And” a literary crime I assure you. The Ultimate conclusion that I present to my haters and to my hecklers, both external as well as the Id that heckles from within, is this “If you don’t like me, if you don’t like my content then do not watch/read/or look. Basically, Jog-on mate!”</p>
<p>I would however, appreciate it being noted for the ethereal record that I have no arrogance with my produced works. I don’t claim to be a hair more than an enthusiastic scribe of the internet, all be it, one that makes a lot of videos. If all were different and readers still existed I am quite sure that I would have never touched video as a form. Given infinite choice I would have been happy to write a little blog for all my days. The world won’t allow that any more though. People want delivery of moving pictures and noisy words, few have the patience or the inclination to read so many little scribbles.</p>
<p>Thank you deeply for reading my words and self justification. I hope to see you here again. Or maybe in the comments section that doesn’t exist on this site by design.</p>
<p>With love, Hex.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Book Club The City and the Stars by Arthur C Clarke</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/book-club-the-city-and-the-stars-by-arthur-c-clarke.html</guid>
<pubDate>Jum, 21 Agu 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="proof-that-big-ideas-can-be-boring.">Proof that big ideas can be boring.</h1>
<p>I don’t read much Arthur C Clarke because I read Rama and it was boring. I’ll call him ACC because I consistently forget how to spell Arthur.</p>
<p>About a week ago, I decided that given how much I have recently been enjoying older science fiction writers perhaps my tastes have refined or changed somewhat. I should revisit this master of the genre. The verdict? A grim one. Either ACC is over rated or what is considered to be “great” science fiction is shit.</p>
<h3 id="the-plot.">The plot.</h3>
<p>The books begins a billion years in the future in the city of Diaspar where humans have overcome death via re-incarnation with the help of the high technology and the god like Central Computer. The city offers many wonders but it is also the entirety of everything left alive on earth and the inhabitants are willing prisoners to its eternal sanctuary.</p>
<p>There comes a new human to this nation city. Alvin, the main character to this story who is a “unique.” Alvin is living his first life in this city. It starts where is is coming of age and is expecting to have a flood of memories from his previous lives fill his mind and soul. Instead he is told by his teacher Khedron that he is “Unique” and no memories will fill him.</p>
<p>Alvin’s uniqueness is very unusual and there have only been a few before. Everyone has a strong faith in the power and infallibility of the Central Computer who while running a while city also selects the best “mix” of people to be born at any given time. Hence, the assumption is made that there is a reason for his birth.</p>
<p>Alvin quickly sets about trying to find an exit to the city and “adventure” happens. Or at least that is how we are supposed to feel. ACC however is not good at writing adventure. He <em>is</em> good at writing grand ideas though and up until this point I was on-board.</p>
<h3 id="the-cracks-show.">The cracks show.</h3>
<p>While I have been told many times over the years that ACC is a genius of science fiction and his work influenced almost everything that followed. I am somewhat dubious.</p>
<p>He writes Ideas in a fascinating and analytical way that I respect. He sets up his grand plans and effortlessly expresses the scope he is trying for.</p>
<p>That’s his one trick though. That’s all he has in the tank. Alvin and the people he meets on his travels are not whole characters at all. They show no love, no passion and don’t seem to bond with each other in any meaningful way.</p>
<p>This problem of characters is also evident when something we are told is miraculous is happening to a character (Like when Alvin first glimpses the wider world) they appear to go “oh! HoW ReMaRkABlElelelele” and then be instantly acclimatised to there situation. They seem to learn new things and new skills between lines of the story and are as underwhelmed as I was at all the high science and magical adventure.</p>
<p>This novel could have gone from utter drivel to a captivating fable with a writer who was willing to take his time with the human moments. To express the awe and let the reader explore the implications of the events. Instead much like I expected we have events outlined and minimal character interaction. There is no joy in this work.</p>
<p>At one point early on, it is said that humans lost their teeth and nails in Diaspar because they were needless. A good interesting idea. not once does the main characters lack of teeth cause an issue. Not once can he not eat something or hurt his fingers when he’s out of the controlled environment of his home. Not once does any of this science lend its self to the fiction. It is simple a new fact that we take on and is forgotten.</p>
<p>Towards the end (and I’m trying to be spoiler light on this one) we explore the idea that with the loss of the ability to have children has made humans less able to love, less able to lust without the life cycle that they are supposed to have. But again this is never explored between characters.</p>
<p>Some of the people we meet have pretty impressive telepathy. This telepathy could be removed from 90% of the story because it is literally only there to facilitate a story point in the last events of the book.</p>
<h3 id="the-enemy-within.">The Enemy within.</h3>
<p>The idea of this book is that we explore some human problems, see some space and are in awe of ancient fallen empires. We are then challenged to see Alvin himself as a disruptive force in the Human world. I saw nothing. I saw no drama, I was a brief tourist in a high speed run through of some random worlds and had no context for the significance of any of it. I wanted to be swept away and instead I went to sleep.</p>
<p>One of the constant things in this story is a scale of events and time that is so vast, it goes from grandiose to silly. Diaspar was supposed to be founded a Billion years ago, we hear of empires that fell in just a millions years, we travel the stars a billion miles from earth (humm) and we hear of the thousands of years between rebirths of the humans in the story. The scale is just nonsensical from start to finish and I did not care about any of it. It was not relatable to me at all. Not even a little bit.</p>
<p>I’m not a stranger to grand ideas. I <strong>LOVE</strong> Asimov’s Foundation series where we jaunt from generation to generation at every point being given context via the earlier narrative. I cared about the falling Empire and rise of Wizards in that series. But in this book I was hostile towards the events. Asimov forces you to care about his characters not matter how brief a time you spend with them by making them real people with understandable motivations.</p>
<p>Alvin was born into paradise and wanted ??? some other thing… At one point he hypotheses that he is the re-incarnation (all be it a blank slate) of a major historical figure from A BILLION YEARS AGO. This idea is agreed upon by his one friend and again, this idea, fact whatever it is is proven to be totally without purpose.</p>
<p>The enemy in this book is the lack of drama and the tired attempts of ACC to beat the billion year old dead horse until it fucks off.</p>
<h3 id="my-conclusion.">My conclusion.</h3>
<p>The City and the Stars is a little more than a collection of really interesting ideas and half baked openings with no closure that matters and an ultimate ending that can be summed up by “maybe it will all work out in a billion more years!” I was infuriated by its empty soulless nonsense and annoyed that I forced myself to the end without deleting the title from my kindle a chapter in.</p>
<p>When I read Asimov, or Gibson or any of the other sci-fi greats the science is tempered with humanity, love, sex, romance, drive and consequence. When I read the work of ACC it is just a lot of really good but ultimately empty ideas that are best left to better bards to play with.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Book Club Stranger in a Strange land by Robert A Heinlein</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/book-club-stranger-in-a-strange-land-by-robert-a-heinlein.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sab, 15 Agu 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="thou-art-god.">Thou Art God.</h1>
<p>I have just finished it and I have <em>things</em> to say.</p>
<h3 id="grok.">Grok.</h3>
<p>The word “Grok” is the reason I read this book. The word Grok is taken to mean either “understand” or “know.” You may have encountered this word if you spend any time with “high end” ass hats. You see, casually dropping a foreign word into conversation is the behaviour of the sorts of people who like the smell of their own farts. Adding a world from a made up language is a special kind of masturbation even by “fart sniffer” standards. Yet. Many shrivelled winkles of people think its a perfect thing to do. As you can <em>grok</em>, I am hostile towards this behaviour. Also. If you use the word you have bloody well better have read the damned book!</p>
<p>Grok. A made up word. The only word of the Martian language that is actually explicitly used in this novel. The fact that some how its gotten into general usage by some basement dwelling freaks is astonishing to me not least because its meaning is at best vague. Do you have any friends who use “Smuf” on the regular? well, next time someone says “Grok” to me, I fully intend to reply with “Ah smuf, smurf, but I think smuf smuf smuft, then there is smuf to consider…. you grok? DO YOU SMUFING GROK THAT?”</p>
<p>Despite my hostility to using made up words in general conversation the word its self is not held accountable by me. I have never however been able to hunt down a definition that actually stands up to any scrutiny. The reason for this is that its a Martian word that’s used to express a relationship between things in a way that we have no world for on earth, and certainly not in English.</p>
<p>Depending on usage it can mean understand, know, intercourse, eat, consume, destroy, and a bunch more. The most common usage however on its own basically means to know something effortlessly on a spiritual level. So when some dick end tells me they “grok how to use” an application I will be even more irate. I’m pretty good with Vim but is it an effortless spiritual experience? No. Its a fucking text editor.</p>
<p>Also I will not be accepting its casual usage by someone who I suspect has no idea of its origin.</p>
<p>Its out of my system now. Ill continue…</p>
<p>It is this word that prompted me to add this to my reading list a space above “The Moon is a Harsh Mistress” Mr Heinlein’s arguably more well known work (I’ll get to that one soon. I promise.) Its been a blast. The book has some great moments and is honestly a joy to read although it does meander more than a little at times.</p>
<h3 id="the-plot">The plot</h3>
<p>Team of explorers get a ship as far as mars and as far as anyone know, die there.</p>
<p>Years later a proper space ship gets there and its like WHAT! a HUMAN!</p>
<p>Turns out the original team didn’t die on the way, they died on Mars. But not before jumping on the good foot and doing the bad thing. A baby is born and its raised my Martians (who are seemingly a peaceful people who don’t care about all the Human fornication around them)</p>
<p>Anyway, they bring that young lad back to earth. He doesn’t really speak any English (Or other earth based dialect) but he is smarter than most people and learns real fast.</p>
<p>What’s this? He is the legal inheritor to a vast fortune because his mom invented space! (okay, space ship engines) this makes him a problem for the government as its AMAZON levels of money. Oh, also.. He legally owns Mars because REASON OKAY!</p>
<p>Some stuff happens! He ends up in the care of a Doctor Jubal Harshaw. An older man who is grumpy, seemingly a bit of a perv and apparently a literal, for real genius himself. He helps the boy get whats owed to him by starting a legal fight with the world government.</p>
<p>All that was spoilers-lite and takes you up to the early “meat” of the story. The rest is well into that real spoiler territory.</p>
<p>The Man from Mars (Valentine Michael Smith, Mike as he is known) learns some things and has some things happen. The book blind sides you with a sudden reveal that he has “Super Powers” and can remove things from existence at will. Astral Project. Slow his perception of time, use telekinesis, never sleeps, control his own body on a genetic level and remember everything he ever sees or hears.</p>
<p>The fella is a little over powered to say the least. But he is a nice boy. People like him. It is said that his powers come from the fact that he thinks in Martian a language that empowers him to control reality by understanding it deeply (If he groks a thing he can change a thing)</p>
<p>Anyway, he has a lot of sex and starts his own church.</p>
<p>That little summery is the most basic version of the plot. But in a lot of ways it’s not the plot that kept me hooked on this novel. The writing is rigid and often inelegant. The story takes place in three wildly different “bits” of the Martian man’s life and it seems to have random but infrequent flashes into “heaven” that are literal nonsense the likes of which I have not read since “the Illuminatus trilogy” or whatever that Robert Anton Wilson thing was called (again a good book with some stupid narrative)</p>
<h3 id="the-good.">The Good.</h3>
<p>The Man from Mars - Valentine Michael Smith has a pretty interesting journey from confused alien to skilled speaker an all the people in his life sparkle with wonderful individuality. He is humble and lovable while being maybe the most dangerous man on earth. He learns things in ways that come across reasonably and his Martian motivations are constantly explained and justified to the reader. While written in formal rigid style at times the story has a wonderful way with the characterisation.</p>
<p>I’m not even sure this is a science fiction novel. It’s set in “the future” sure but the Man from Mars is just a device for exploring religious faith, scientific knowledge and the questions that our concepts of objective morality really gloss over. It could quiet easily have been Man from the future, Man from Heaven, Genetic experiment Man. Doesn’t matter. Not even a little. He is a device for generating circumstance and the conversations that follow it. I liked that. A lot.</p>
<p>This book has no villain and that is a nice change to the normal. Oh and it invented the idea of Water Beds (A little aside for you there)</p>
<p>The story puts forward a Martian idea that once you “share water” with someone, they are your “brother” (regardless of gender, Martians don’t have gender) and once they are your “brother” you are family forever. You will die for them, kill for them and follow their every wish. They do the same for you. It’s a founding idea that Mike has that is at the core of his beliefs.</p>
<p>It also puts forward the idea of a “fair witnesss” someone trained to observe, remember and report EXACTLY what they saw and heard. Admissible in court and a very respected profession. The point is made that when recounting things when will give only factual information and make NO assumptions about things. I love this idea. Its sort of daft when we have recording equipment but I love it anyway.</p>
<p>Most of the book is not action or adventure. Its conversations, long conversations between characters. Some explaining things to Mike, Some talking about him and rationalising his actions. Its deeply philosophical and is very willing to question “modern” American civilization and Taboo. Often the writer puts himself in a position where he has to both defend and attack morality and reason. Its fascinating to me because the conversations are interesting on their own and because as a reader you know this is essentially the writer talking to himself. I still have no idea what side of all this Robert Heinlein supports. I have a few guesses but its not explicit.</p>
<p>As the book goes on it get braver in its questioning and its derived answers. Mike realises that out ability to think clearly is tied to language and Martian is a more complex and refined language hence the speaker is gifted with “abilities” because he is better in touch with reality. Thinking in Martian is inherently going to make you better at everything. He teaches his first real love and travelling companion Gillian a little Martian and she begins to see the world differently.</p>
<p>I have been somewhat interested in the idea of more complex language effecting ones personal reality ever since I first read Grant Morrison’s Invisibles. There is something poetic in the idea and I find it captivating.</p>
<p>Eventually Mike “Groks” Humans and has a good old laugh at us. I mean that literally. Once he has “Groked to fullness” he is overwhelmed with laughter for the first time in his life. He then slowly decides that he can help a lot of people by sharing his knowledge of Martian and the book jumps about two years into the narrative.</p>
<p>Its this point that the tone changed from polite critique of social norms to full on free-love new-age throw it all out and fuck everything.</p>
<p>The “nest” as its called is a temple of sorts where the members of the church live. They practice nudity, open sex with multiple partners and a belief that they do all this because they are closer to enlightenment. The book is pretty specific that they <strong>are</strong>. The sex writing in the book is quite tasteful and mostly can be read and enjoyed even all these years later. Mostly, but ill come back to that.</p>
<p>The little cult is a joyful place where people all just love each other free from modern morality. They never get sick, they hardly sleep and they accept each other totally. Its how we all should want to live if you ask me.</p>
<p>All this happens in the highest “level” of the church because you cant accept this pure angelic life style until you learn Martian. Learning Martian makes you better. Angelic seems to be the right word.</p>
<p>There are a lot of characters in this book. I have not talked about many, the reason for this is that it’s the ideas that are important not the people having the ideas. But the character of Jubal Harshaw was one that I adored. He is at first introduced as a grumpy airbag. Surrounded by beautiful women he introduces as his secretaries. He lives in a big house with a pool. His household is free and has basically no rules, no clocks and no TV.</p>
<p>It soon becomes apparent that Jubal is a genius who is a qualified lawyer, doctor and a part time writer. He has a political past that is barely covered in the story but hinted at a lot. He’s always grumpy, seems to be set in his ways and those girls really are his secretaries.</p>
<p>His works flow is simple, he has an idea for a book, poem or article. He shouts “font” and one of the girls starts writing down what he said. At some point it will be written up, edited and sent to some magazine, publisher or news organisation. This is all done by the girls.</p>
<p>Jubal starts off by refusing to help Mike and Gillian but soon finds himself drawn into the boys life. He’s a wonderfully written character who manages to be rude and arrogant in the name of justice and rightness. Such a flawed but deep man. Eventually he becomes the unwilling patron saint of “the church” and its referenced and the only man alive who can “grok all things” without learning Martian. His innate understanding of things carries him further than most humans simply because he thinks about things.</p>
<p>The way Jubal runs his “house hold” is only a little step away from the free and pure “nest” that the church lives in. He was pretty close to enlightenment before he even met Mike, or at least. Thats the implication as I read it.</p>
<p>I think it would be easy to say that Jubal was the writers fantasy projection of himself but I don’t buy that theory at all. Most writers are within all their characters but in this case I think Jubal represents the writers own regrets while the girls in the book reflect his hopes and their forgiveness of his bad tempter his own internal conversations and struggles.</p>
<p>The religious morality of the book reminds me in no small part to Wiccan faith but taken to a more open and honest extreme than you would fine any Wiccan admitting to striving for. The basic teachings are there. All things have a soul of sorts, God/Gods are in all of us (We are all gods of out own) and love, emotional or physical should not be a thing that we feel shame for. Oh and faith brings control of reality in one form or another.</p>
<h3 id="the-bad">The Bad</h3>
<p>The book meanders a LOT and a modern editor would have stripped it down quite a bit, making it more punchy and circling points less. As I said earlier, its mostly conversations and things to make that conversation happen. Many of the events are far less interesting than the discussion that result.</p>
<p>There are some lines in this novel that are to say the least indelicate and the opinions one woman in the novel has about rape and it often being the fault of the victim are not okay. The writer is very wrong and is projecting shitty opinions even for a book from the 1960s. There are some moments where the motivations on the female characters lead me to wonder if Robert Heinlein has ever met one. But over all from the point of view of those in this story and the way the world was when it was written back in ’61 I forgive a lot. You almost have to when reading old science fiction. The writers often think they are being edgy but are just being strange and shitty.</p>
<p>Also, Mike is free from the human morality trappings but its continually said that he is “not a homosexual” maybe its because I’m reading this many <em>many</em> years after it was written but the books obsession with only putting your winkle into lady holes contradicts a lot of the Martian teaching in this book. Its a little odd. If Mike wants to be gay then that’s fine. No one will care. At least not in “current year”</p>
<p>There are also moments where Mike seems to outright disrespect the women in his life (Calling them whores and such like) while everyone including those women respond as if he is being flattering. Quite odd. If this was supposed to portray a loving in-joke or banter it missed the mark for me.</p>
<p>I’m no prude and I have no issues I with multi person relationships as a way of life as long as its all equal and respectful. In this religion mutual respect, free will and agency are founding ideals but the introduction to it is a little heavy handed. It goes from “I should start a Church” to lets have sex with these people! Now her, now here, now we are all nude allllllll the time. It could have been handled better considering how slow the conversations are, it could have got there in a smoother way.</p>
<p>There are these moments when it is suddenly in “heaven!?!?” and angels are talking. Total bollocks and needless. Literally BORING but thankfully it doesn’t do it a lot. So honestly fucking strange though and without reason. It makes the book worse by being there.</p>
<h3 id="the-ending">The ending</h3>
<p>The ending of science fiction is often the make or break moment and this one has quite a telegraphed ending (I wont go that spoiler heavy) But over all an optimistic one.</p>
<p>It also arrived at its ending quite suddenly and it feels a little like Mr Heinlein suddenly ran out of ideas and wanted a quick exit.</p>
<h3 id="the-verdict">The Verdict!</h3>
<p>I liked it a lot. Despite the flaws in the narrative an bad politics at times. The core story and main characters are loverly. It makes you question things and leaves you with a warm glow that makes you want to greet everyone with “thou art god”</p>
<p>I think I have some more specific thoughts about some of the things raised in this book but I have to let all this noodle about for a bit.</p>
<p>I will read again on day, I’m sure.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Book Club Timeboud by Rysa Walker</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/book-club-timeboud-by-rysa-walker.html</guid>
<pubDate>Rab, 12 Agu 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I read a lot. And as not one person actually reads my website I decided that I’m going to start talking about books when I bloody well want to. Today’s book…</p>
<h1 id="as-spoiler-free-as-i-am-able-to-be.">As spoiler free as I am able to be.</h1>
<p>I have not before ready any Rysa Walker. I didn’t even know who she was until I stumbled over this book when searching good-reads for recommendations. Her writing style is wonderfully verbose when required by more sparse as the action set in. A literary tool that many writers simply don’t use, or are unable to use. The pacing of this book is excellent. I have nothing but compliments for this.</p>
<p>The Story its self centres around Kate Pierce-Keller. A teenager who is living a pretty standard life for a teenager in the America of young adult fiction universes. She meets with her estranged grandmother and notices some strange jewellery that seems to glow.</p>
<p>Some things happen, then…</p>
<p>Seemingly un-related to anything she has a “dizzy spell” and poof! Her whole reality has been replaced but she isn’t effected. She is now a stranger in a world that is seemingly doing quite well without her. Oh, except there’s a now a new major religion in the world.</p>
<p>With no place to go, she returns to her grandmother, meets a boy falls in love and attempts to learn to use the “medallion” (afore mentioned glowing jewellery) to write this time line. The time travel takes her primarily back to 1893 World Fair where she has to puzzle out the order of events to complete her mission.</p>
<p>Kate is conveniently qualified for her new tasks being an enthusiastic martial arts student. Oh she is pretty good with computers too. And she seems to be above average intelligence… As well as being genetically predisposed to using time travel technology. Yeah. Don’t think about any of this too much. It’s supposed to be a fun read not a documentary.</p>
<p>Over all The Book is an easy read. My knowledge of American history is vague at best but I followed the story. I assumed most events were fictional but after finishing it I had a look at the font of all human knowledge (Encarta ’98… I mean, wikipedia) and way more of it is rooted in actual history than ever would have guessed.</p>
<p>Its a huge complement to the writer that I enjoyed the book without the historical nostalgia that was no doubt expected.</p>
<p>I Enjoyed the love story(s) that were the main focus of all the character moments in the book as well as the “A” plot. It was in fact a fun read.</p>
<p>The two love interests are both well rounded characters who both have dubious motivations. Mostly it comes down to young men wanting to help a “hot girl” but manages to pull it off in a way that isn’t creepy or nonsensical over all.</p>
<p>The writer expressed a weak understanding of the technology she invented for this book. Whenever you write a time travel story you HAVE to make sure the reader understands how the stuff works (or at least the effects it has on the world) These magic time travelling “medallions” were not a chunk of technology as it is expressed, they are literal magic. The writer works hard to try and shoehorn in a science but honestly, not one line of the psudo-technological world building stands up to any sort of thought.</p>
<p>At one point its said that you must stay near a Medallion or you will be erased from the timeline that doesn’t have you in it, then its said that actually no, as long as you were protected when the “changes” happened then you will be fine. Then its contradicted again… I have no idea how this is supposed to work. Quite literally would have been better for the characters to have said “We have no idea how this works, just assume its magic”</p>
<p>Also the book constantly touts a villain who never once appears in this story instead promising his appearance in the next. A little infuriating but didn’t detract from the “current events”</p>
<p>Then there’s the problem of the dialogue. While its mostly snappy and well written there are times when it leave me at a loss of what they are actually on about. Characters motivations of a mess at times and logical leaps are made the kind that I have not witnessed since point and click adventures were considered good.</p>
<p>Its hard to think of this book as real science fiction though, its not very scientific and most the “action” takes place in the past, or in a rather nicely described family home. Its teen-romance with a sci-fi dip. I liked it but it wont sate your lust for hard sci-fi.</p>
<p>All these critiques a side. I really enjoyed the book and instantly started the second one. The character of Kate is adorable and I really was invested in her adventure. So much so that I instantly started the second book in the series.</p>
<p>I enjoy young adult fiction (Teen fiction) and find it relaxing to read while engaging for its innocence. This book is a solid read that I have no doubt lands way better to its target audience than me, who is just an interested outsider.</p>
<p>If you have thoughts on this title or theres a book you want me to take a look at for this blog then please do email HexDSL@Posteo.net</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>The Hunters Garden PART 2</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/the-hunters-garden-part-2.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sab, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-hunters-garden.-part-2">The Hunters Garden. Part 2</h1>
<p>Hello one and all. I have decided that as no one has messaged me regarding the Hunters Garden, I should keep putting it out relentlessly until you love it.</p>
<p>I have not recorded an audio portion of this one as. Honestly, the last one was not very good. No one seemed to really be attached to it, I’m skipping it.</p>
<p>As for the content its self, This episode we have Howard and Mike slowly becoming actual friends, we meet a new character and learn a little more about how the garden works….</p>
<h2 id="birth.">Birth.</h2>
<p>Howard opened the garage door all the way, the sounds of the city streamed into focus and for the briefest of seconds it was over powering. “What do we do now?” I asked. Howard zipped up his coat, it was cold outside, “Well” he began, “It knows where you live so I suppose we should go to your flat.” I could see his logic but I thought he had over looked something. “Won’t the police have been there by now? Maybe still be there?” I asked. Howard pulled out yet another cigarette. “Tom takes care of that sort of thing.” He took a deep drag of the now lit cigarette and continued as he exhaled “Just like he sent me to look for you. That’s what he does.” We started walking as he added “He makes sure society, you know, the masses, don’t get in the way of our job.” That seemed a fitting purpose for someone of Tom’s temperament. He had struck me as calculated and methodical from the moment I had seen him. Compared to everyone else that I had met in this new world he was by far the least jaded. Or at least not as pissed off as everyone else seemed. I wondered to myself if this life, whatever it was, attracted this sort of temperament, or if it created it.</p>
<p>My flat was quite some way away, “Why don’t we just get a cab?” I asked. Howard shook off my suggestion, “We walk whenever possible. If we are on the streets then got a better chance of stumbling across one of them.” Howard’s confidence and demeanour made his unnerving statement sound almost reasonable. I looked up at the morning sun “Daytime? Vampires?” He actually smiled a little “Oh, Vampires don’t like the light, but they do tolerate it from time to time” I found myself slowing down at that revelation and had to speed to up a little to stay in polite conversation distance “What do we do when we find one?” I enquired sheepishly. Howard petted his satchel and said with a little smile “Oh, Vampires? We kill them before they kill us.” At the time I could not understand how it was possible to be so sure of yourself. I was (on some level at least) looking forward to seeing Howard show off skills. Even though I knew it would mean we were both; I, would be in mortal danger.</p>
<p>The streets were never empty in the city. It was just getting wound up for the day. Commuters bustling past. Some with headphones on, oblivious to us. Most rushing by and grabbing coffee. We were barely on the edge of the city’s heart but even here the cogs of the modern world could be seen. The morning was crisp and little cold. We kept walking. I felt like an outsider now. Not a man who lived here, lived here for years. I was not quite attached to this world now. I assumed this was the shock of the recent events taking a toll.</p>
<p>It must have taken us an hour or so of reasonably brisk walking to get to my home. Just as predicted, there was no police presence at my house. There was one or two officers still at the sight of the attack though. “How long where we gone again Howard?” I asked. “I don’t know exactly. It took us a while to walk to the nearest Garden entrance. Then an hour or so go get here.” Howard answered as he threw his cigarette end into the road. He took a good look at my building from the edge of the street.</p>
<p>It took me a moment to process what Howard had said. I shook my head as I spoke “Yes, I know that. But we were in the garden all morning and I have no idea how long I was asleep for.” Howard shook his head back mocking me a little, or at least that how it felt “Look, kid; I doesn’t matter how long you’re in the garden. You arrive back just as you left” I mused about the reality of that. How long would have passed in the garden before we returned? How did all this work. I opened my mouth to ask about all the practicality’s but Howard got there first “Don’t ask. It’s ancient magic. Not the kind of thing that us <em>mortals</em> can ever really understand. It works. Accept it. There’s no point trying to figure it out.” He had obviously had this conversation enough times that he had that stern question stopping reply in the barrel without even thinking. He was back to eye balling my building before he had finished the first word. Howard’s experience <em>again</em> shone through, and was starting to feel a little intimidating.</p>
<p>As we climbed the damp concrete stairs to my floor a realisation hit me “The police took my stuff, I don’t have my keys” I barked with frustration. Howard sighed with irritation. “Stop thinking like a civilian Mike.” We pushed the rough old fire door open that separated the staircase and the hall. I almost ran to my door. Oddly pleased to be back at a place that felt like normality.</p>
<p>The door was a pastel blue with a silver metal handle and a bronzed letter box that didn’t match that handle at all. There was a single long and stained maroon carpet strip running the length of the corridor. Other than that it was all the same concrete grey. The rest of the doors had matching letter boxes. Not that it mattered. The post was collected downstairs in the entrance hall. I tried the door, knowing it would be locked. I was more trying it for effect, to illustrate to Howard that we were locked out than to actually gain entry. “I should go see if the caretaker has a set of keys” I said as I started back towards the staircase “He has an office in the basement”</p>
<p>Howard lifted the flap on his bag. Fished around for a moment and pulled out a rather long and very thin blade. “I think I have a solution that doesn’t involve six bloody flights of stairs.” He then effortlessly stabbed the dagger into my lock. He twisted. The door opened. The lock however was destroyed. “Great, and now I’ll need a new lock” I gestured my hands towards the door to signal my annoyance. “You do realise that you don’t live here any more? You do get that right?” said Howard as he pushed into my tiny flat judgementally looking around. It hadn’t occurred to me at all. I hadn’t thought about what happened after this one Vampire was gone. I had just, assumed that life would go back to normal. I was not ready to leave my life behind and join a war that I cared nothing about. I didn’t think that telling Howard about this feeling would have been a good idea.</p>
<p>Howard sat in my arm chair and started picking up all the things around him. My little coffee table was piled with crap. Empty cans. Old magazines, A Laptop, even some cold Chinese food containers. He looked out of place. Up until now I had not seen my new friend interacting with the ‘real’ world like a normal person.</p>
<p>“So…” I muttered as I made started making coffee in the little open plan kitchen. “Vampires? You’ve not told me much about them, all the story’s true?” I asked, more to make conversation than anything else. Howard didn’t answer.</p>
<p>We didn’t speak again while I made crappy instant coffee for us “I don’t have any milk. You want sugar?” I absent mindedly said as I double checked the grubby fridge. “No milk. No sugar. Just strong” he called back. I walked the coffee over to him “I don’t think its as good as the Garden will have.” I apologetically muttered as I handed it over. He looked happy, just a little. He actually seemed a little pleased about the shitty coffee. He looked up at me from the armchair “When all you ever get is perfection, a cup of dicey tasting brown goo can be a wonderful change.”</p>
<p>We sat, basically in silence for quite a little while. Howard wasn’t a man interested in small talk. After a few short sips of coffee, that I was fairly sure was too hot to drink. He took knife and a stone from his bag. He started sharpening the blade while he looked out of my window. “So we wait?” I sighed. “I’ll wait. You do whatever you want.” he replied. I was starting to realise that Howard’s demeanour occasionally slipped. His stern words and direct nature were occasionally punctuated with a warmer tone. Like he was working hard to be aloof with me. I decided that I didn’t understand this man at all. I also decided if I would be at least vacationing in this world then I should get a few things together.</p>
<p>I looked for a backpack or satchel in my bedroom, to take one or two things along, maybe make all this less painful overall. Howard had started rummaging about in my refrigerator. He called through “Yeah, so. Nocturnal evil. Not massive fans of crosses, garlic and running water.” Was he beginning to warm to me? I heard him open a can of something. I had beer and a couple of ciders on the counter. He must have decided it a better option than the coffee. “They can come out in the day but they just don’t see too well. If they have to they can hide in society. Moving about like normal people, just with worse eyes. Never seen one sleeping though” Howard spoke about Vampires like he was describing cattle or rats. To him they where targets nothing more. “So what about coffins?” I called as I reached under my bed, “Not sure where that one came from to be honest.” That was a first, there was something about the enemy that Howard has no answer for after all. I pulled the old dusty rucksack out from under the bed and brushed it down. No spiders. A win, finally.</p>
<p>I considered Howard’s wisdom for a moment and came up with another question “Coffin would be where you wake up when you first become a vampire maybe?” Howard replied quickly and sternly. “No, you have that wrong. Sometimes when a Vampire takes a soul the body keeps on going, and a body with no soul is just a new born Vampire. Some are born vampires. No one gets buried.” I walked back into the living room to get some clarity on this matter “So, some people just aren’t using their souls?” I asked expecting to get shot down again. Howard took a bite of a sandwich he had finished making from the remains in my kitchen. He swallowed and answered with his unique eerie sincerity “Yes, that’s right. Some people are born to become vampires and that soul they have is just an anchor that slows them down. Soon as they lose that the change happens fast” He took another bite then continued “You get to recognise them eventually. Their nothing more than well behaved evil. Until they loose that anchor” Howard’s tone was serious and dark, his next line hammered home his point perfectly “Sometimes I think that its best they to become a Vampire. Can you imagine the atrocities that could be done by a thinking feeling human? At least vampires have simple needs.” I thought it best not to work this topic any longer and wondered off to find some stock for my rucksack. “Of course. The word Vampire is really a general term for any daemon that feeds on souls. There’s not just one type. Not all start human.” He raised his voice as he heard me moving things around in the other room. “We don’t much bother with the ones that don’t bother us. If they’re not eating people, well souls. Then its not really a high priority for us.”</p>
<p>I found myself realising that there was a lot more nuance in the monster world than it had first appeared. I took my toothbrush and one or two other items that I thought I may need, including a spare wrist watch and my ageing laptop. I also felt that the remaining cans of larger from the fridge deserved a space with me. Looking back it seemed so childish to take these material things, as if they really mattered. As for the wrist watch, there’s day and night, every other way to measure it is a waste of time.</p>
<p>I had more questions, and as Howard was, for whatever reason now willing to talk I pushed forward. “Do they have, like friends and jobs and all that?” I sat on the sofa and packed away my laptop charger. Howard finished his can. “Sort of” he said. “They seem to have packs some times. And with all packs there are alphas. But past that, I don’t really know. Not that chatty.” He stood up to inspect the view from the window a little closer. His sandwich was finished now and the shook the crumbs onto the floor.</p>
<p>A few hours passed. A little quicker now we were talking. With him offering more than single phrase answers. I was still not used to my weapons. I adjusted them and I tried various ways of concealing them. Nothing seemed practical. Howard was sitting in the arm chair watching cartoons on television, smirking at my awkwardness. Eventually, he took pity on me “Just shove ’em in your belt” I did, it was practical but not exactly hidden “Yeah, if I want to get arrested as soon as we leave here, this is definitely the way to go.” Howard changed channel on the TV and opened the last can that wasn’t already stashed in my bag. “I see the training is as good as ever then. Those weapons you have are from the Garden. The wind hides them because they are…” Howard paused as if trying to find a word that was descriptive enough “lets say magic” I looked at one of my daggers. It didn’t look very magic. In fact it looked old and a little battle dented. To be honest I still wasn’t sure I even knew what to do with it. “Magic hu?” I observed as I stuck in back into my belt. Howard nodded, “Yeah, for now lets say magic. If you turn out to be any good at this I’ll go to the trouble of explaining properly” I knew what that meant. It meant that he didn’t see the point in explaining anything to me because he was still of the mind that I maybe be dead in my first real fight.</p>
<p>We sat and watched the television for hours. We even ordered pizza in the afternoon with the help from an emergency credit card that I kept in my wardrobe. Howard never said very much that had any relevance. He would comment on the crap television show we were watching but it was obvious that he didn’t want to get to know me any more. I think is earlier chatty moments where a result of him forgetting to distance himself. Distracted by a comfy chair and a TV. I suppose that was a complement, the less he knew about me the less it would matter if or when I got killed.</p>
<p>The hours ticked by and eventually the lack of any real conversation broke me. “I’m shit scared you know.” Howard lit his last cigarette. He had smoked two packets while we had sat there and watched the terrible shows that he had deemed worthy of not flicking away from. He seemed to really like cartoons for some reason. He looked at me for a long second “I know you are. We are all scared to start with. Nothing I can say will change that. Look, when this mother fucker who took your life turns up here; kill him, don’t be sorry. Just kill him… Then, I think it will all be just a little bit easier” I wasn’t sure that it would be easier, I wasn’t sure if I could fight, I knew I didn’t want to though.</p>
<p>We walked to the local shop and got more cigarettes for Howard. I walked to the checkout and paid for them. Apparently Howard didn’t carry money, that didn’t surprise me. I was right there at the checkout, the lady looked at me and didn’t say a word about my two huge knives. They were right there in plain view. Hanging from my belt. Howard was right, things where different for me now. It was empowering to know that I was standing in a shop with a handful of people, two weapons right by my hand and no one could see them. It made me feel powerful, safe. I was told that it worked as a warning system. If some one took a double take at my weapons there was a good chance they where a hunter or a vampire. I kept a keen eye. We walked back to the flat and watched more TV, the conversation was kept to a polite minimum.</p>
<p>Eventually it began to get dark. I sat at the window, I knew it was a ‘void’ I knew that I would see him coming, I wasn’t sure how dark it needed to be before he would risk coming out. How dark it needed to be for it to be able to see well enough to hunt. To hunt me. Howard was still watching TV, relaxed, enjoying him self I think.</p>
<p>It had been at its darkest for hours before I saw it coming, the beast, the thing that knew I had seen. It was coming. It was moving slowly in the shadows but it was there. It hugged the wall of the building across the street, eyeing up my window. I assume it saw me too. “I see it!” I exclaimed softly. Howard just sat there. He glanced to the street. “I know Mike.” He said, finishing his drink and stubbing a cigarette out in an empty can he was using as a makeshift ashtray.</p>
<p>Within a few minuets I couldn’t see it in the window any more. I knew it was inside my building. Howard finally decided that it was time to move. He stood relaxed in front of the sofa. He turned the TV off. He stretched his neck from one side to the other, like a prize fighter warming up before the main event. He began to loosen his arms with a shake to check his muscles where still in order.</p>
<p>I heard the thing, coming. It was coming to kill me and all that stood in its way was a tall thin man who smoked too much and was almost definitely a little drunk. It’s shadow was in the doorway. Tall and stocky. Moving with elegance. Then as the shadow slid into the room. The beast, the Vampire filled the opening. I had not seen it this close before, it was over six feet tall and it’s massive wings sat behind it pinned like a cape, it wore denim jeans filled with holes and smelled like rotting meat. It’s body was chiselled like the mightiest of body builders or the finest of lions. Its skin was a mottled grey. It’s face was what I noticed next. It’s face was as human as mine, albeit grey and dirty. It was completely hairless and lacked the will to make that face make any expression at all. It looked dead when it didn’t move. Like a shark before it kills. It didn’t look like a man, not really. More like the remnants of a man. Calling it the remains of a victim would have been more apt I suppose.</p>
<p>The thing seamed to growl when it saw Howard. Its mouth opened a little like it was trying to show its teeth, like an angry dog. It lacked the facial dexterity to really pull it off. It knew that this was not going to be the easy pickings it had planned for. The beast spoke with a voice that did not match its body, it sounded human and even warming “Are you a Hunter?” it asked, Howard just looked at it. He had no desire to get into conversation. The beast looked at me next. I must have looked pathetic clutching weapons I didn’t even know how to use and hiding behind my guardian. The beast smiled at me, or was it trying to bare its teeth again? It really was oddly hard to tell.</p>
<p>The stand-off lasted only a few seconds. It was the beast that made the first move. It lunged forward with a definite supernatural grace that was was defiant of its bulky mass. Instead of showing a weapon or even punching the thing, Howard simply stepped aside. It had come for me. Howard never intended to stop it. What was happening? Was he just there to document my death?</p>
<p>It was the electric tingling in my wrist that I noticed first. In the fraction of a moment I had to process it. I felt like the little blue charm on my wrist was crackling with static and energy, shining as bright as sun. I felt the teachings it held sink into my mind. In that single second that lay between me and the beast I felt myself turn from a scared child into a skilled warrior. As a warrior, what did I do? I stepped aside. As the thing fired its self towards me I simply stepped aside. It didn’t have time to stop it’s self from smashing through the window, it almost hit the floor before its great wings stretched and with a single mighty flap and the same grace that it charged at me with, it flew back to the opening. As it came to a landing I knelt down, with timing that I never knew a human could have, I pushed both daggers up wards into the air piercing the things heart. Using its own momentum to seal its fate. It fell out of the air and stone it dropped. It fell against the television crushing the thing. There were little sparks coming from the debris under it. It was dead. I had killed it, and it was easy.</p>
<p>I looked at the charm on my wrist, it was white and pale, the energy had gone from it. It looked like a little costume trinket that child would wear now. Drained of any magic, I assumed. I pulled it off my wrist. The leather ties snapped and I tossed it at the corpse.</p>
<p>Howard gave me a clap, “Looks like you have got what it takes then.” I took a long look at the corpse I had just made. I had not killed anything before, aside from the occasional troublesome bug that is. “It was the charm, not me” I replied without thinking as I wiped the black blood from my weapon. “That’s only partly true. Only about twenty percent of people can absorb charm’s” Howard sounded apologetic. There had been about an eighty percent chance that his stepping aside would have condemned me to death. Even though I now realised that the best way to deal with the forward motion of a stack of meat like that <em>was</em> in fact stepping to the side. In fact I too had instinctually stepped away the moment the little trinket on my wrist had shared its wisdom.</p>
<p>Eighty percent chance I was going to get thrown out of a window and die. I mulled it over for a moment. Howard got a little extra information in, thinking I was going to be angry at him “The first charm has to be absorbed as a reflex, there isn’t a way to test without real danger” I thought about that again. I didn’t care… I was a hunter now.</p>
<p>I looked around my home, there was a lot of damage and blood sprayed about the place. I realised that this place could mean nothing to me now. I had absorbed the charm and the foundations for a life as a hunter had been laid down within me. I knew that the little charm had actually changed some part of me but I didn’t care. I knew that attachment to my life was a hindrance and I was better off without it. I also knew that it was the charm that had made me believe this. It was a strange feeling, like awaking from a sleep that had lasted my whole life and thinking how silly that dream had been. Anything was possible for me now. Making sure my weapons where clean was now far more important than the state of my home. In fact, looking around that place I was ashamed of the shallow existence that I had lead. The whole time as I thought these things I was also aware that it was a perspective that has been pushed into my mind.</p>
<p>I snapped myself out of my internal reflections. “What do we do with the body?” I asked. Howard smiled “Waiting for it to turn to dust are you?” He was right, I suppose I was. Howard lit a cigarette, took a deep drag, then he flicked it at the corpse. It lit up instantly. “The dead ones burn real well, it’s the lack of moisture. Even the bones burn, but we don’t really need to worry about it. We just kill them” I picked up my bag, pushed the daggers back into my belt. We walked away as my home began to burn, “Other people live here you know” I pointed out as we walked out of the building. Howard shrugged it off “They all have fire escapes” he seamed heartless at first but he took time to call the fire service at the pay phone at the end of my street. Maybe he did care.</p>
<p>We headed back to the garage, this time while we walked Howard was more talkative. He actually took time to share his knowledge. Now he knew I had the ability to use these charms it was like I was a real person to him. Maybe before that I was just a potential decoy. He told me about the Garden and how the ancient hunters had made a deal years ago with the last living pure daemons to get access to the Gardens, safe places to operate from. There was more to the story but it was far more than Howard himself knew at the time. The old pure daemons where not like the beast we hunted they were basically gods. The name ‘daemon’ was given to them after some war that fractured most of them into these monsters we now had to deal with.</p>
<p>We entered the Garden again. Stepping from the dark city into the light of the summer sun. It felt like coming home after a long time away. I suppose in many ways it was. Everything in the Garden was as it should be, by comparison the city was a shadow of a place with nothing to offer us.</p>
<p>It was a common sight in the garden for weary hunters to wonder into view covered in blood but in this place wounds where not as real as in the city. In that wonderful place blood and cuts seamed to matter far less. Just being in the garden was a form of healing. Usually by the time that we had walked to our rooms the worst of broken bones where just a stiff muscle and those cuts and clashes that had covered us in blood where just grazes that where best ignored. As for ripped and torn outfits, somehow the laundry service in the garden cleaned those away too. The strange thing really was that no one acknowledged these little miracles and it was just taken as every day life for hunters.</p>
<p>After we both cleaned up in our rooms we met Tom by the little chairs by the back of the house. I was wearing a grey tank top and some long track shorts. Howard wore a casual white shirt and some boot cut jeans. I think the casual attire seemed fitting and a little celebratory. And, I don’t think either of us were in the mood to try and impress Tom. We ate burgers and drank tea. There were some tents in the garden now offering food and drink. We felt a connection Howard and I. Now that he knew that I was able to absorb the charms I was a new recruit to him not an irritation. I guess I was Howard’s partner now. Like buddy cops on an adventure. We talked about my future. Tom told me that now the fist Charm was absorbed my training could begin. He also took a moment to apologise for the danger he had put me in. As he spoke I realised how cold it all had really been. They could have faked an attack and activated the Charm like that but if it had not have worked, I would have been a liability. They would have been stuck with me. Letting a vampire kill me was the easiest solution for them. As it happened the Charm worked and I had been baptised in blood. This realisation tainted Tom’s warm smile.</p>
<p>Howard and I spent what seamed like months training in the little Dojo. I could absorb or as Howard called it ‘drain’ the charms now by getting my adrenalin flowing and working up a sweat. Howard let me drain more Charms than I could count. Some where tiny ones teaching me specific techniques for blocks or counters. Some where massive and contained whole tomes of knowledge about vampires and their history. It was like the information was being placed into my mind as I sparred with my partner. The best I can explain is that I had known these things and learned these skills a long time ago, the charms where just helping me remember. Draining them was an obsession for me. I wanted to be the best Hunter. Not only so I could stay alive in battle but so I could keep people safe. After all that was what my new life was all about. I couldn’t help but feel like this new life was a gift. I felt confident and powerful. I knew that when I returned to the city, I would be a predator.</p>
<p>As much as I enjoyed seeing the little stack of empty charms build up. It was exhausting. I had to keep training physically to let the charms wisdom soak into me but at the same time it was a mental workout. The headaches and fatigue were all part of the normal training side effects I was told. Even if it were more than that then simply being in the Garden for extended periods of time cured every medical issue that the Hunters had even encountered. I noticed that there were no hunters wearing glasses.</p>
<p>I asked about Toms occasional limp I had noticed once or twice. Howard and I were sparring as usual. “He spends a lot of time out of the garden.” Was Howard’s response to my observation “The old ailments come back” he continued as I went for a low sweep of his feet. He hopped over my attack and countered with a kick aimed at my head. I rolled away and I effortlessly returned by my feet. “We hardly ever actually make contact any more. Why do we keep training even when I’m not draining charms?” I asked, a little out of breathe. Howard laughed aloud as another of his kicks ended with a theatrical spin. “Well, Mike my friend. After years of civilian life, you need all the exercise you can get!” he gestured to my sweaty brow and proof of this. We were starting to find a beat with our back and fourth now. Mostly me claiming I was already as good a hunter as him (all the time knowing that it was a total over statement.) While he would tell me that I had spent too long as a civilian and wasn’t cut out for this life. The banter was like a warming glow in my day.</p>
<p>I few days after my initial training sessions I was shown a library that was in the back part of the house. It was truly massive and had the kinds of books you see in old horror movies. Leather bound and hand written in flourishes. I spent each of what I considered to be my evenings reading the diaries and mission reports of hunters long retired or killed. I wanted to know everything I could about this world. It was liberating and wonderful and because it was always the middle of the afternoon in the Garden I could spar and train as hard as I could, take a bath and read in this wonderful Gothic room until I could keep my eyes open no longer. Then every morning when I would wake up it would be just in time to meet Howard in the garden for breakfast. Howard was fond of Fruit but I had discovered that one of the buffet tents usually contained appetising bacon and eggs.</p>
<p>Every few mornings Tom would wonder over with a cup of tea in hand. He would ask about what I had learned and offer stories of other hunters missions. I was starting to feel very happy with my life.</p>
<p>One sunny morning (whatever that meant) Tom had a job for Howard and I. He had written an address on a peace of paper and there was a photograph of a woman. “This woman is our enemy, she feeds vampires. Take care of the matter” That was exactly what Tom said. The photo was black and white and of a happy looking woman. Slim and confident looking. She wore a dark suit and looked oblivious to the camera. We had no other mandate or information than that. Howard said that Tom was in favour of giving hunters room for interpretation. I was just pleased to be given a task. This was my first real mission. I was a hunter and this was my task. But was this woman to be killed? Were we to murder a human? I shared my concern with Howard. “I have been given a lot of missions that sounded sketchy but they have never ended in any ways that stopped me sleeping at night.” He got up to leave. I followed him. Instead of heading to to the house he made a b-line for one of the food tents that was always dotted around when people were eating. We casually greeted the catering staff as we talked about to the tent “Where do we even hire all the staff from anyway?” I asked. Howard glanced back at me “We don’t. They are all Hunters.” “What?” I explained “Hunters cook the food in the buffet tents every day?” Howard nodded as he grabbed an apple while briskly walking to the back of the tent. “Look, you know how time works here. After doing this for a while you will want to help out in other ways. Trust me.” He said all this in quite a matter-of-fact way. “But training, hunting, mission?” I barked. “Mike. Time doesn’t work here. Not sure you noticed this but things are screwy. People get bored and stick to the stuff they enjoy. Help out in different ways.” I was still a little confused “but don’t we have an enemy to fight?”</p>
<p>Howard had reached his destination, a large storage shelf at the back of the catering area. There were at least six or seven people working in this area, none with weapons on show. As he assessed the shelves he spoke “I had a mission go bad a while back. Needed some time to decompress. I almost died. I was outnumbered by some big fuckers. When it was all over I took some time off hunting and peeled some potatoes for a bit. It’s good work in here and no one is trying to eat <em>you</em>.” He took a long box from the shelf. “What are we even doing in here?” I asked. Howard shook his box at me “Where did you think I got my Cig’s from?”</p>
<p>I stopped off at my room to get a jacket and some proper boots. Now I was closer to being a properly trained Hunter. I didn’t want to be in combat without the right foot wear and trainers were not good for fighting. Howard looked around a little “Do you do anything in here? This place has no personality at all, Its the same as the day you moved in. Have you even turned that laptop on since we got here?” He gestured to the bag I had brought back from my old life. “No”, I said. “Do you see a power socket in here? And I doubt that the Garden has a wi-fi!” Howard ate a bite from his apple “I don’t know anything about computers. I barely know what one <em>is</em> but if you want or need this wi-fi then the garden will have it. Also, you don’t need to charge batteries here.” He said as he chewed.</p>
<p>I honestly hadn’t considered that this amazing magical place could have modern world internet and a computer would just feel out of place. “You should go see the technical guys on the third floor” Howard finished as he took another bite of his apple. <em>“We have tech guys?”</em> I queried. “Ha! You must love that library if you’ve not even had a proper nose about the house” he added.</p>
<p>We left my room and I turned to head to the patio. “Time for a new lesson” Howard said as he gestured to the other hall. We walked to the far side of the house, near the library. Instead of going straight ahead to where I had been making my regular pilgrimages we turned down to the left, heading for where I knew the rear garden area was. Before we made it to the rear patio door though we turned again and down one or two steps. I had seen the staircase in the main hall of the house but three or four steps down seemed out of place.</p>
<p>All the doors in the house were heavy and large but this one was the first I had seen that wasn’t painted white. It was striking metal with no markings at all and a bar across it like a fire exit, not a little brass handle like the rest of the house. This door at the end of those few steps made me realise how little I had explored the house. “How did I not notice this?” I exclaimed. “Don’t feel bad. The house, the Garden. It has a way of making you miss things until it becomes relevant to you” Howard pushed the bar down as he spoke and the door opened under its own power.</p>
<p>Inside the room was a lot larger than I expected. Impossibly large. I was in an aircraft hanger but with rows and rows of storage shelves. They were high too. There were a few free standing ladders on wheels and a few people with clipboards who looked like they were cataloguing things. The place was busy and loud. There was a massive door at the back of the huge room. It was open and I could see tall thick trees out side. Not the Garden at all. I was in awe. “Just when I think this place makes sense it all gets bigger again…” I trailed off as I basked in the sight of the whole thing. Howard nodded in agreement. “Wait until you meet the Gardener” he joked as he gave me a friendly slap on the back to snap me out of my moment.</p>
<p>We walked towards a large table with a tall woman standing next to it. She looked like she was in her early thirties and wore the more serious military looking jumpsuit that I had seen a few hunters opt for. She signed something on another woman’s clipboard and handed her some papers. We woman left and the tall woman spotted us. “Howard!” she exclaimed. Stretching out her long arms to my friend. He gave her a mighty hug. Her hair was long and dirty blonde, fixed into a lose knot at the back. She wore a little more make-up than I had seen other hunters wear and her nails were painted in a striking purple.</p>
<p>“Mike, I would like you to meet my dear friend Anne. She runs this little office” Howard looked a lot happier than usual. I shook her hand politely. “Ah, Michael. The new guy!” She spoke with a shrill voice but her tone was warm and friendly. It tells you a little about someone when you are introduced as ‘Mike’ and they instantly respond with ‘Michael’. I’m not sure what it told me about her but I noticed it. “I swear, they like to keep the warehouse a secret just to watch all the new recruits look as shocked as you do right now.” She smiled gleefully. “I get a kick out of it too, if I’m honest.” She was nice. I liked her instantly.</p>
<p>“I’ve not seen you around the Garden, or the house have I?” I replied. It was a little to make small talk and a little because I really hadn’t seen her before. “No no. The Warehouse services multiple sites and we have our own sanctuary.” The words had a casual ring to them but the implication was anything but “What?” I almost barked. Howard had one hand on Anne’s shoulder. It didn’t strike me as a flirty gesture, more the relaxed interaction that comes with a very old friend. Howard smiled and gestures towards a metal chair near the table.</p>
<p>“Right, as I said. Lesson.” Howard began as he pulled in his own chair. The table was covered in documents and clipboards containing what looked like inventory reports of some kind. There was a very rugged looking laptop directly in front of Anne. Howard took a cigarette out of his packet almost subconsciously as he spoke. Anne shot him a look and he put it back as automatically has he had removed it. “We have to get supplies right? Before a mission we may need some gear. A new weapon. Specific equipment for the journey. Maybe we need some cash for this one? Maybe we need to make sure a vehicle is waiting for us. Oh, the Dojo. Those weapons get replaced as we break them. The food deliveries, tools, equipment. All of it. It all comes from the warehouse.” He nodded at me as if being firm with his words was going to make it all make more sense. Something he did often. He continued “Well. All the Gardens” Anne interrupted with the word “Sanctuaries” Howard carried on talking. “Whatever, They all need supplies. All the <em>sanctuaries</em> need stuff. Well, rather than them all sourcing it themselves, they all come to this place. It’s a room within all the Garde..” He stopped himself before finishing and selected a new word “Within all the Sanctuaries. And its the only overlap <em>we</em> get with other hunters.” Anne rolled her eyes and added “Operatives” sternly.</p>
<p>I sat and looked in awe at this place again. “There’s more than one Garden?” I asked. Picking it out as my first question of many to come. Anne smiled and put out a hand to stop Howard talking again. “Yes. Every hot spot area has its own sanctuary. And its own operatives who are trained and optimised to deal with regional supernatural threats.” Her voice was less warm now and more like someone giving a presentation. I had not heard anyone use the term Supernatural in reference to vampires. I had also not heard the words ‘Threat’ or ‘operatives’ being used before. She continued “A long time ago, it was decided that we would centralize resource management and logistics. This place, the warehouse was set up as a stand alone supply chain.” She spoke like middle management, not a Hunter. She was nice but she was obviously not in the same fight as the people I had been spending time with.</p>
<p>She continued on about how the sanctuaries supplied healing, and the crystals that trained us. What wasn’t supplied was food (Other than the fruit trees that grew in the Gardens) weapons, clothes and other such consumables. The ‘structures’ as she put it were supplied with the garden but could not be built on or changed in any way. Which explained all the tents that were in our Garden.</p>
<p>I also gleamed that all of the ‘Sanctuaries’ were not the same. Ours was a wonderful Victorian house with rolling hills but the warehouse was in a forest of some kind and it seemed like early evening. Anne also mentioned the unfortunate team that got stuck with a cave, and rain.</p>
<p>Our conversation (lesson I suppose) carried on for about an hour. Mostly me asking questions that were either replied to with Anne’s clinical observations or Howard’s signature ‘Ancient Magic’ line. Either way. I had a much clearer idea of what I was part of now. Up until this point I had assumed that our Garden and its hunters were the only people out there taking on the war. The last thing that was explained very clearly before our lesson was over was that all of the <em>sanctuaries</em> were independent and had no knowledge of other teams locations. No method to communicate at all with each other. We were all alone and the only back-up we had was the supplies that Anne organised. Anne also made clear that she was under strict orders not to share a single event or name between groups. Howard quickly added that we were free to talk to anyone else we bumped into here though. Just in an ‘off the record’ way.</p>
<p>When Howard and I stood up. I assumed we were leaving. The tone shifted to actual business. “Well, its been wonderful chatting as usual Howard” Anne was being more professional now “But I know what your here for. It’s fixed.” Howard Grinned. It was a grin of actual joy. Anne gestured to a young man at the far side of the closest shelf. The man left and a few moments arrived at the table with a wooden box or chest would be more accurate. He placed it down in front of Howard and waited for him to open it. Howard (still grinning) opened it up. The lid opened towards me. It wasn’t until he took out the contents that I knew what it was. Howard pulled out a large Hand gun. It was silver and had an oak coloured handle. I didn’t know a lot about guns and no one in the garden had spoken much about them. This was was an old six shooter like cowboys used. It was quite a bit larger than I expected a gun like that to be. “We use guns?” I asked, or exclaimed I suppose. “No” replied both Anne and Howard at the same time. After a brief and lustful look at the gun, Howard flipped it around in his hand like a sheriff in a western and slid it effortlessly into a holster on his right hip. A holster I had failed to notice up until this point.</p>
<p>“We don’t use guns. But you do?” I asked. Howard Smiled and patted his pistol like it was a pet. “I’m the exception. It came with me when I was recruited.” he adjusted the holsters belt loop a little “It got busted up pretty good a while back. Anne here called in a favour with a friend of hers. Got it fixed for me.” Anne admired it on his belt “The bullets are pretty hard to find too, so he doesn’t get to fire it as often as he would like” she looked at Howard affectionately. “I think he has it more as a security blanket at this point.” She then nodded to the young man who delivered it. He scurried away with the box the moment Howard had taken all the ammunition out of it.</p>
<p>“The other reason you were here though? I assume your looking for something for Michael?” Anne queried. Howard nodded and said “Yeah. He’s still using Training Knives at the moment.” Anne scrunched up her face in disgust. “Ewe.” she said absent mindedly. She tapped some button on her laptop then reached for a clipboard in the pile closest to me. She flipped some papers over and asked me “So you like the knives?” I took them out from my belt “They were given to me on the day I arrived. Not given it much thought really.” Anne took them off me and put them on the corner of the desk. Again, looking a little disgusted with them. “You know we literally have any hand weapon you would ever want and they still pass newbies the worst stuff they can find. How any of you don’t die on day one is beyond me.”</p>
<p>Howard was still distracted by his new (or old) toy and was adjusting it to get it to sit just right. He had also put some of the bullets in little loops on the belt. “He’s trained in all the usual stuff. He likes staffs but has more natural skill with those daggers actually.” It warmed me a little to know that Howard had noticed that I liked staffs. We didn’t really talk about preference while we trained. I needed to be effective with every weapon the training room had. Preference hadn’t come into it. “I suppose if they throw duel knives at every new recruit they will get it right at least once.” Anne added. She nodded a little then barked “DX3, Slot 4” at Howard. “Get it yourself and then clear out. I have a delivery coming in any second now.” Howard nodded, looked at me and said “DX3, slot 4” We walked down the seemingly huge arrangements of shelves. It reminded me of one of those secret storage facilities you see in movies. Then it occurred to me that this was literally exactly what it was.</p>
<p>We used our extensive knowledge of the Alphabet to navigate to the third DX aisle. Slot four was a glass drawer on the edge of the shelf. Howard opened the drawer and for the third time that day, grinned. “She really does have the best Toys.” He gestured for me to take my new weapons. In the drawer, on a bed of what looked like ash were two old looking knives, daggers really. With curved blades edged in red with ornate handles. Decorated with brown and black leather tied in crosses. The tips of the handles were their own tiny blades also edged in red. There was a familiar looking charm between the two. “Wow” I said “Nice.” Howard nodded “And assuming you get along with them. They are yours.” I Took the charm first and tied it to my wrist strap. I had gotten pretty good at this. Every charm I had drained had lived on my wrist for a little while and it was a little embarrassing asking for someone else to tie it for me. Everyone else could do it with one hand so I had learned too. “It should be a little one. Just the finer details of how these specific blades are best handled.” Howard said with a little reverence in his voice. “Anne must like you.” He added.</p>
<p>I reached in with both hands and took both blades at once. They were heavy but felt good to hold. I tapped the flat part of one blade with the point of the other to see what the red edge was made of. It looked like it was red crystal, just how it looked. The Blades felt amazing to hold. None of the training weapons ever felt truly dangerous. These would have felt dangerous in anyone’s hands. I pulled back my jacket to push them into my belt and smiled to myself when I realised my belt had changed. It wasn’t the simple leather with silver buckle that I had put on. It was a thick leather with an old chunky metal clasp. There were red metal loops on it that I already knew that daggers would hang in perfectly. I flipped the blades in my hand and slid them both into the loops. There was a satisfying clink as notches in the blade lined up with the loops to secure them. “Ancient magic” I said, with a laugh in my voice. Howard Nodded “See, I knew you would get it eventually.” We both laughed and made our way to the door we came in though. We gave Anne a wave as we left. The hall of the House was a little warmer than the warehouse had been. I was glad to be back.</p>
<p>On the way back to the front patio we stopped off at Howard’s room. He had not invited me in. He slipped in for a moment and emerged with his jacked and bag. Seemingly stocked for the mission. I then wondered if Howard had really just popped into his room. How local was this time ‘thing’ that the garden did. Could he have had a full nights sleep in this time? I would think about this later.</p>
<p>We walked out past the front wall of the garden before Howard used his ‘void sticks’ to take us to the garage. Walking away from the main area was traditional I was told. Howard could open a portal anywhere but leaving for a mission was an important part of the whole ritual. Howard’s portal opened exactly as last time but this time I embraced the sickness, as I swiftly switched from one place to another. Thanks to the training I had received I knew how to cope with uncomfortable feelings and nausea. I took a deep breathe and held it inside, by the time I let it out the feeling of sickness had passed. This was a good start. I was returning to the city as a professional. I instantly noticed that the weather was the same as last time we were in this world. To me it had been weeks. Maybe more. But to the city I hadn’t really left at all.</p>
<p>To be Continued…</p>
<h2 id="next-time-on-the-hunters-garden.">Next Time on The Hunters Garden.</h2>
<p>Next time we join Howard and Mike its game face time. The Mission is in action and its time to see if Mike learned as much as he thinks he did. As well as asking ourselves if the mission its self is a just one or not.</p>
<p>Feedback actually quite welcome…</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>The All time top 20 SO FAR</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/the-all-time-top-20-so-far.html</guid>
<pubDate>Rab, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>MY top 20. Not your top 20. Not “THE” top 20. MINE.</p>
<p>There is no order. Some of these are not even very good but they stick with me for whatever reason.</p>
<p>There are some Bonus things too… Also this is a list that reflects my mood RIGHT NOW, this is subject to change like the wind on a summers day.</p>
<h1 id="games">GAMES</h1>
<ul>
<li>A Short Hike</li>
<li>Bayoneta 2</li>
<li>COGMIND</li>
<li>Doom (1993)</li>
<li>Doom (2016)</li>
<li>Dungeons 3</li>
<li>Excite Bike</li>
<li>Final Fantasy 14</li>
<li>Flashback</li>
<li>Minit</li>
<li>Nier: Automata</li>
<li>QUAKE (The First one)</li>
<li>Sayonara Wild Hearts</li>
<li>Shining Force</li>
<li>Star Traders: Frontiers</li>
<li>Super Mario Odyssey</li>
<li>The Maw</li>
<li>XCOM 2: War of the Chosen</li>
<li>Zelda: Breath of the Wild</li>
<li>Zombies Ate my Neighbours</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="bonus-movies">BONUS: Movies</h2>
<ul>
<li>Casablanca</li>
<li>Heathers</li>
<li>High School Musical 2</li>
<li>Jaws</li>
<li>Mean Girls</li>
<li>Pump up the volume</li>
<li>Scott Pilgrim</li>
<li>Spider-Man: Into the Spiderverse</li>
<li>TRON</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="bonus-books">BONUS: Books</h2>
<ul>
<li>All the Gentleman Thief stories By E. W. Hornung</li>
<li>Foundation By Isaac Asimov (First 3)</li>
<li>Masters of Doom By David Kushner</li>
<li>Off To Be The Wizard By Scott Meyer (actually all six books)</li>
<li>Planetary By Warren Ellis</li>
<li>Rebel Code By Glyn Moody</li>
<li>The Invisibles By Grant Morrison</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="bonus-music">BONUS: Music</h2>
<ul>
<li>Mean Girls (Musical) - The Broadway Cast Recording</li>
<li>Future Nostalgia - Dua Lipa</li>
<li>Boys - Charli XCX</li>
<li>Tooth and Nail - Dokken</li>
<li>Joey Yung - JPOP</li>
<li>Circus - Britney Spears</li>
<li>Nevermind - Nirvana</li>
<li>Simply… Blue Eyes! - Frank Sinatra</li>
<li>NSW - Ninja Sex Party</li>
<li>Running with scissors - Weired Al Yankovic</li>
</ul>
<p>Thats all. Good bye for now.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Not Forgotten you</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/not-forgotten-you.html</guid>
<pubDate>Kam, 21 Mei 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a little longer than I intended to get the next part of “The Hunters Garden” released. Not because I’ve been slacking off but because I wanted to re-work a section of the story. I remember when I originally wrote it, I was never happy with the main characters training section, it seemed a little bland and uneventful. At the same I didn’t want to make a montage. Anyway. Its almost done. Give me a few days and it will be posted.</p>
<p>It’s important to me that people know that the delay is not due to my lacking interest in the project. It’s simply finding time in my day to get it actually edited.</p>
<h3 id="feedback">Feedback</h3>
<p>Very few people have messaged me regarding the writing project and as I don’t have metrics at all on the site I have no idea how many people have read it. If you get a chance please drop me a toot or a tweet or whatever to let me know :D that would be great.</p>
<p>Hex out!</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>The Hunters Garden PART 1</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/the-hunters-garden-part-1.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sen, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="a-hunters-garden-part-1">A Hunter’s Garden: Part 1</h1>
<p>I wrote a book. It was years ago and up until the start of the year, I had basically forgotten about it. Then when I switched back to using Dropbox I found it in a very old, very dusty folder. I read it. I liked it but <em>hated</em> the ending… I deleted the ending.</p>
<p>The plan is to edit it, a little at a time and post it as I go. At some point I’ll Have to write a new ending from scratch. Once I do reach the end however, I’ll re-work a few chapters and post it as a complete work for you.</p>
<p>For now you will have to read it as I post it (and I won’t be committing to a release schedule.)</p>
<p>I was unsure as to if I should post this here or on my http://Pixelfridge.club website. I decided that more people would probably see it here. If it proves a popular experiment it will continue here. If not, Then it will migrate to the other site.</p>
<p><em>Everything beyond this point is work of fiction and not to be confused with an item of news. Any resemblance to the real world is imagined by you.</em></p>
<p>Here it is…</p>
<p>I made an audio version but I think this one is best read (Because I am not good at recording this type of format)</p>
<audio controls style="width:100%;">
<source src="http://hexdsl.co.uk/hunter/Hunters_Garden_Part_1.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
</source>
Your browser does not support the audio element.
</audio>
<p><a href="http://hexdsl.co.uk/hexshards/Hunters_Garden_Part_1.mp3">Download</a> - Right click and save it.</p>
<h2 id="a-hunters-garden">A Hunter’s Garden</h2>
<h3 id="by-hexdsl.">by HexDSL.</h3>
<h2 id="intent">Intent</h2>
<p>I planned on opening in the usual way these things do, by talking about the rain or the moonlight or the smells of the city at night, and the truth is that any of those would have done just fine but I have chosen to do something different, I have chosen honesty.</p>
<p>My name is Michael. No, no I can’t go through all of this with my real name, that’s too much honesty even for me. My name is Gabriel. No, that sounds stupid, okay, how about I just stick to Mike, yeah. Honesty.</p>
<p>My name is Mike. And I kill vampires. Wow, that really does sound cheesy, an old friend once told me that you can’t tell people you fight monsters because you sound so deeply fucking stupid. She was right. Well there’s no other way I can say it without sugar coating it or talking in some complicated abstract way. I guess that whatever I could come up with has already been the topic of some overly romanticised teen literature. Yeah, cheese or no cheese, here’s the truth, with no romanticised crap to shine the nasty bits.</p>
<p>My name is Mike and I kill vampires. This is my story, oh crap, what now, am I setting myself up for a fucking movie-of-the-week. No, shit, this is going badly, I’m going to stop over thinking this now and just get the hell on with it.</p>
<p>My name is Mike. I kill vampires and I’m recording this because I have fuck all else to do and I’m scared, for the first time in… Well, as long as I can remember. I’m scared, and I regret that there’s no one I want to talk to one last time, that there’s no family to mourn me and there properly wont be any friends left to bury me. In my final hours I’m using this voice recorder app to explain it all. Why? Because I hate that my profession is little more than the topic of TV shows and fantastical books.</p>
<h2 id="honesty-i-kill-vampires.">Honesty: I kill vampires.</h2>
<p><img src="../hunter/art1.png" /></p>
<p>It all stared something like six months ago to the outside world. Not that time means very much to me any more. I came home from work, it was about ten at night, and no, I didn’t come home to find my family slaughtered or a vampire in my bed. Nothing quite so exciting I’m afraid. I came home to my one bed-roomed flat in the middle of an area that resembled a land fill, the lift was broken again as usual so I had to walk up to the sixth floor. Into the sixth door of the sixth block of flats. Into my boring untidy home. I lived alone back then because I was looser with no girlfriend, not pets and no interests.</p>
<p>I put my fresh twelve pack of cider on the kitchen bench and turned the TV on. It was a ritual for me, after a long day at work I would come home, watch whatever brain dead spoon feeding distraction was on television. Drinking whatever was on offer at the store and wondering when life would start for me. Tonight I was fortunate, life <em>was</em> going to be starting.</p>
<p>I sat in my chair for a while switching between ninety’s sitcoms and music television. I must have fallen asleep, for a while at least. A sound woke me. The television was showing late night shopping advertisements and the can in my lap was warm. The large window at the front of my living room was open a crack and I could hear some arguing coming from the street below.</p>
<p>I was a little drunk still, and tired. The window was letting in both noise and a chilled breeze so I wondered over to close it. If I had have chosen to stay in the chair then my life would have gone in a totally different direction. I would have probably kept the same job for the rest of my days. Eventually met a girl who didn’t hate me and I would have grown old. Probably got run down by a bus in my twilight years. But no, I had to look out of the god damned fucking window.</p>
<p>You see, at the time I didn’t know it but I was living in a place that was in what I now know to be a ‘void’. A place that is in an ancient holly place, or a future holy site. Or in my case a cursed number. Six hundred and Sixty Six, the number of the beast is what people call it. I’m not sure if that’s very accurate but because of this I was able to see events with a ‘pure view’ as we call it. You see, If I had have lived in flat number 5 or flat number 7 then I would have seen an average every day stabbing. I would have seen a young man in the street get stabbed by a larger man. But no, I lived in flat six, on floor six of block number six. So, I saw what I should not have been able to see. I saw a huge winged creature put it’s hand into the chest of a young man and suck out his life… Suck out his soul.</p>
<p>I can tell you one thing, I was a little shocked, and then I did something that was really, really stupid. I banged on my window and shouted some very morally sound things, probably “Noooo” or “why god? why!” or some other shit. To be honest I cant remember exactly what I said but it’s really not important because the point is that I drew attention to myself, and when your in a ‘void’ the window works both ways. That unnatural beast heard me. Instead of looking up and seeing a man who has witnessed what he thought was a random stabbing it looked up and saw my true self. It saw all the things inside me that I never even knew where there. Infinite potential or wasted possibilities. I don’t know. I’m not sure how we look to them. But I do reckon that its good you never get to see your own soul. I must have looked good though because he started coming my way.</p>
<p>If you where looking at the event from outside its intricate layers you would have thought that the stabber <em>(is stabber a word?)</em> was going to silence a witness. If I had have lived in any other flat that may have been exactly what I thought was happening too. I lived in number six, and because of that I knew that a huge almost stone like monster that could suck a soul out of some one’s body was coming for me. I was scared.</p>
<p>I pushed across the blinds with a desperate panic. I turned off the TV and I backed away from that door. My heart was pounding like I had never known before. I had no idea what I was going to do or what that thing was going to do to me. I wasn’t even sure what I was waiting for. Would a monster knock the door or ring the bell? What was I going to do? Was I supposed to grab a knife? A baseball bat? You see so many movie’s you figure you’ll know what to do when something like this happens to you but, trust me, you panic. And if your a selfish useless slice of shit like I was then you hide and cry and pray to a god you don’t believe in. I sat on the floor at the side of the door, it seamed as good a place to cower as any other. I was Pathetic.</p>
<p>It turned out that monsters ring the bell. It rang the bell again, and again, and eventually banged at the door louder and louder. Soon it stopped banging the door and I stepped closer, and then closer to it. I was breathing so heavily that its a wonder it couldn’t hear me. Maybe he could. I was shaking all over and I leaned a little closer. I could see a shadow in the crack of light at the bottom of the door. The breaks in the strip of light told me that it was still out there. It rang the bell again.</p>
<p>I actually laugh to myself now when I think back to what I was. So scared and so confused. So sure that this was an impossible thing. I should have grabbed the biggest knife I could find from the kitchen and tried to kill the bastard thing. Or, turned it on my own pathetic neck, rid the world of such a waste of skin.</p>
<p>The crack of light cleared and I heard the footsteps of the thing leaving my ‘welcome’ mat. Then a few seconds later I heard the door at the end of the hall swing closed. I sat there for what seemed like hours, and then eventually I sat on my sofa. I cried, from confusion and fear. I cried like a child until dawn.</p>
<p>It was at dawn for for some reason I felt safe again. I looked out of my window and there was a police car and people by the body of the man I had seen killed. I had seen destroyed. I was sure that it was only a matter of time before the police would knock on my door asking me what I had seen. What would I say? What can you say after that.</p>
<p>It was just about then my mind cleared I was still scared to my core but that urge to live had kicked in. I had some how formulated a plan.</p>
<p><img src="../hunter/art2.png" /></p>
<p>Soon enough the knock came at the door. I could hear the pops and bleeps of a police radio from the other side. As I expected they where doing their job, I opened the door and was greeted with the polite “Good morning sir, I’m sorry to bother you but there has been an incident and we where wondering if you…” I’m not even sure I let him get that far before I blurted out the rambling line I had rehearsed in my head just moments before. “Yes! Yes I saw it all and the guy who did it saw me, he came here and banged on my door!”</p>
<p>What happened next was a blur of questions and answers and more questions, but the next thing that is really relevant to the story happened a few hours later, at the station. I had been through my story at least five times and each time I gave an honest account of what happened, but I use the word ‘attacker’ instead of monster and ‘attacked’ instead of describing how the victims soul was pulled into the hand of the monster. I even told them that I could not give a description of the ‘attacker’ because it was too dark, even though when I had looked through my window it was not that dark, it should have been but it wasn’t.</p>
<p>I was actually starting to relax. I was genuinely beginning to feel like I was safe. Surrounded by police and treated like a star pupil. I was after all the only witness to a violent murder. It was when they told me I could go home that the fear set in again. The police officer assured me that he would ‘post a man’ outside my door and I would be perfectly safe. Like that works in movies? He even started telling me how no one would try anything with a police presence at my house. Even if I wasn’t hiding from a monster I wouldn’t have trusted that one!</p>
<p>I was scared again, and when I was scared I was stupid. I had convinced myself it would come back for me. The thing would come back as soon as it was dark and kill me. It would walk away without a second thought. I was again without a plan and scared. I told the police officer how I would rather stay at the station and that I didn’t feel safe going home but he assured me that the attack was totally random and the knock at my door could have been anyone. He was even amused at how scared I was. That’s when the desire to live made me do something that I am fairly sure saved my life. Or was incredibly stupid. I hit the wanker in the face. I hit him so hard that I broke his jaw and then when he hit the floor I kicked him in the ribs. Not proud of that one. Not even a little bit.</p>
<p>As you can imagine all of this was on the police station’s CCTV. I was cuffed and ruffed up just a little bit before ending up in a cell by myself. There was a lot of chatter and shouting around the station. I was surprised about the excitement to be honest. I would have thought that police officers got punched in the face often enough for it to be a normal occurrence but they where taking the whole thing very seriously. I hadn’t resisted arrest, I had apologised for my behaviour. I wasn’t violent by nature, not back then. I did feel bad about hitting the officer, but it kept me in the station for at least the immediate future. I figured it was a good move. Locked in a nice safe cell in a station full of police, the safest place I could be.</p>
<p>Other than the verbal abuse I was getting from the police officer’s, a loyal and protective bunch of public servants. I felt safe. I was fairly sure that the monster I saw wasn’t going to do a rendition of the Terminator and come into a fully manned police station to get me. Not even in the middle of the night. I slept well, oddly. I have no idea what time it was when I was woken up by the smell of smoke. Not the smoke of a fire but of a cigarette. I sat up fast and with a jolt. The aged mattress in my cell gave off a telling squeak. Holding cell’s are not what you come to expect from the education of television. They are tiled rooms with clean floors and a not altogether unpleasant chemically cleaned odour. Most of all there are not entire walls made of bars like you see in westerns. They have large metal doors with little windows covered by a sliding panel. Very civilized.</p>
<p>Anyway, I could smell smoke. It was dark and there was only a subtle light coming from the edges of the cell door, the moonlight streamed in from the little window. I backed into the corner of the little cradle like bed. The telling squeak sounded again. The door of the cell opened and the light form the corridor streamed in, it took a moment for my eyes to adjust.</p>
<p>I was scared, again. A feeling I was starting to adjust to. As my eyes cleared I could see a tall thin man dressed in jeans and a shirt standing in the doorway, he was smoking. The man sauntered into my cell and I knew there was no way he was a police officer. He was too relaxed and rugged, too elegant. He sat down at the end of my little mattress and took a long drag of his cigarette. “you’ve had a hell of a day haven’t you Mike” the worlds left him with an effortless charm. He looked to be in his early fifties and had the demeanour of a war veteran. Steely confidence and a little bit of madness in his eyes.</p>
<p>I swallowed hard, my mouth was dry with fear. “You could say that, yeah” I said. I wasn’t really sure what to make of this situation so I thought it was best to just be honest. “I only punched that guy so I could stay in the cell, its safer here” I added. The man took another drag of his cigarette and spoke again. This time with some laughter in his voice “No shit” he said “My names Howard. I know what you really saw Mike, question is, do you?” I was stating to feel better. This was it. This is how it’s supposed to happen. If you get into some fucked up super natural shit there’s supposed to be a powerful stranger. Someone to come and get you out of it. That’s how all the story’s go. I sat up “well, I saw a thing. It killed a man. It looked to me like that thing sucked out his soul. It was a white light that came from all over that guy and just got sucked into the scary bastards hand” Howard flicked his cigarette into the hall. “yeah, that’s about the gist of it I suppose.” He stood up and began to leave “come on then Mike, we had better get to work”</p>
<p>I followed Howard through the hall and to the desk where the night officer was sitting. He stood up and said, “hey, he can’t leave” the officer probably had more to say but Howard interrupted with a cold and somehow eerie tone “fuck off” the officer sat back down and pushed the buzzer that opened the door. Howard and I just walked straight out of the station. No one so much as gave us a second look.</p>
<p>When we got into the street outside, Howard changed some how, he looked older and less confidant. He began to talk as he walked down the street “What you saw was a vampire. A big one too. It knows you saw it. It has your scent. It’s going to hunt you down. Kill you and keep your soul.” At this point I was ready to believe anything. I was about to ask if leaving the safety of the station was a good idea when Howard began to talk some more. “I had to get you out of that station. I need to get you up to speed before it’s too late for you” I was worried. That didn’t sound good. Howard lit another cigarette and began to walk a little faster. He spoke again “Your flat is what we call a void, its the sixth flat, on the sixth floor or the sixth block and other shit like that. I know that doesn’t mean much to you but that makes it a void. A place that allows you to see through The Wind. Not this every day crap that you think reality. There’s a lot more underneath that.” He sounded crazy. Like the sort of people that write massive paranoid rants all over the Internet. He sounded like a rambling mad man, but I believed him. There was no other explanation on offer so it would have to do.</p>
<p>He talked for another twenty minutes or so. I won’t try and remember the exact conversation but Howard told me about Vampires. He explained that there are different types of Vampires but they all want to consume your soul. Some suck it out of you in your blood. Some, like the one I saw, just reach in take it. Some torture it out of you. They are all vampires. Some old. Some young and some don’t even know what they are themselves. The part that freaked me out was that apparently now I had seen something through a ‘void’ I smelled different. I smelled better to these vampires and I had to toughen up before I was lunch. I was scared again. I wanted to believe he was talking shit. I wanted to believe he was a lunatic. I believed every word.</p>
<p>We stopped walking. We where outside a garage. Nothing fancy. Just a garage where you put your car. It was small single car garage with a blue metal door, there where six garages. One was missing it’s door. There seemed to be teenagers getting drunk in it. Howard took a key out of his pocket. The key was old, it looked like the key to a castle but some how it fitted the little padlock that kept door locked. I literally can’t describe how it fitted. Even now I understand all the little tricks and tools. But I can’t actually describe it because its like your brain doesn’t actually want you to know some things.</p>
<p>Howard tugged at the bottom of the door and it swung up and open just like any other garage door. Inside the garage, there was no car. There was no oil stained stone floor or anything else that would make any kind of sense. There was a large green field, a blue sky and a man in the distance who appeared to be playing golf. Yeah. I know how it sounds.</p>
<p>This was a magical thing I was seeing. My mind had nothing to compare this to. I think that’s the key to dealing with impossible events. Don’t try to rationalise it. Just accept it as something new. Normal life does not give you a frame of reference for ancient magical workings.</p>
<p>It was the middle of the night in the city. It was dark and I was looking into a garage and watching a man playing golf on a sunny afternoon. It was impossible. I knew that I was about to sound naive to Howard but I didn’t care “What am I seeing? Is that the future or something?” Howard laughed “Don’t be stupid, if time travel was possible I’d just go and stop Eve eating that fucking apple wouldn’t I? This my friend is the Garden and your are very welcome here.” With that he walked into the garage and I followed.</p>
<p>I looked back to where I had come from. It was a swirling hole in the air, There was a static hum. Howard reached back and pulled on the garage door, as it slid closed the swirling doorway vanished. As the last glimpse of the city faded I noticed how dark and lifeless it looked. The humming faded. I felt sick. The change of air and light made me nauseous. Like waking up when light hits your face after a long night’s sleep.</p>
<p>“We’re safe now, vampires don’t exist here” Howard spoke with confidence and I knew I could relax. I had known Howard for less than an hour but I knew that I could trust him. If he said that I was safe then I knew I was. I had no doubt’s about this much.</p>
<p>The man that had been in the distance playing golf was walking towards us. As far as I could see in any direction there where massive rolling hills and blistering sunshine. The man looked to be in his early sixties and wore golfers clothes. He was shorter than Howard but just as thin. He looked a lot healthier than Howard though. He seemed to glow with warmth. As he got closer he put his golf bag down. He mopped his brow with a little white cloth and waved for us to come closer. We did. Howard shook the man’s hand and introduced me “This is Tom, he’s kinda my boss, THE boss” Tom nodded at me and with a well spoken voice he said “Hello Mike, I’m sorry you got dragged into all this”</p>
<p>The three of us talked for ages. I wasn’t sure where we where going, I was just happy to feel safe. These men seemed to know what they where doing. What I understood at the time was that Tom was like a vampire hunters manager. He sort of oversaw the ‘war’ as he called it.</p>
<p>As we walked across the rolling hills Howard and Tom tried to gently tell me about this new world I had fallen into. It seamed like no one ever signed up to hunt vampires. People like me just got mixed up in it when we stumbled on the right conditions to open a ‘void.’ Once we had, we where targets. We could either join the ‘war’ or get killed. I tried begging Tom to let me out of this unfair deal. He genuinely seamed to feel sorry for me but as he explained I really only had the two options. I could train to be part of the ‘war’ or I could go home and be dead before morning. Thinking back, it was nice of him to bother explaining it to me so gently. He should have told me to shut my mouth and be grateful that Howard had the time to save my pathetic hide.</p>
<p>I could see a building in the distance, it was a large white house with ornate little stone walls defining its gardens from the rest of the grassland. It was like a delicate historical manner house. The sort of place you go and visit when your on one of those boring school trips as a kid. There where people every where, some sitting at little metal garden tables with soft white table cloths drinking tea. Some dressed like it was a formal Victorian garden party and other’s in quite modern jeans and T-shirts. Most carrying assorted weapons. From swords and knives to staffs and what looked like wands. I had a flash of headache every time I considered what I was experiencing. I was inside a garage that was in what I assumed was another dimension or some other sci-fi trope. I was watching people wondering around a wonderful garden in the sunshine. But it was night time outside the garage and I was supposed to become a vampire hunter or die. My mind was blown. I had very little logical thought going on. I did manage to ask “What the hell am I supposed to do now then?” Howard looked at Tom then at me and with quite an honest and dry tone he said “It’s easy Mike, you try not to get killed.”</p>
<p>Tom had arranged a room for me in the large white house and instructed me to take a well needed shower and to get some sleep. Howard walked me to my room. The house was luxurious and as clean as the day it was built. There where ornate old fashioned light fixtures and expensive looking ugly carpets all around. It was like a living museum and had not one single sign on wear. Everything was pristine with out a single exception. The house its self was vast like it had been built to house a small platoon of occupants. It looked way smaller form the outside. No magical geometry, it was just a lot longer than it looked from the front.</p>
<p>Howard stopped outside a heavy looking white door with a brass knob in a corridor that had red floral wallpaper and vase next to the door. “This is your room now” Howard said. I looked at the door, there was no lock and no number, it was just a plain white door and an oversized knob. I wasn’t sure what I had expected but at the very least I thought I would be shown around a little. “Is there anything I need to know?” I asked sheepishly. Howard yawned a little, he was tired and did not want to tolerate my silly questions for much longer. “Just take as much time as you need and take what you like out of the wardrobe. I’ll be around when your rested” and with that, he walked off in a rush to get to sleep I think.</p>
<p>I looked at the door for a moment before opening it. I reached down to the large brass knob that protruded from it. The door was as heavy to open as it looked. Inside my room I was surprised to find a massive bed like you would see in the grandest hotels. No duvet. Layers of thick blankets were draped across it. It was decorated as I expected from what I had seen of the rest of the house. There was a large fine wooden wardrobe and a window that seemed to be screwed shut. There was also smaller door on the far side of the room. I quickly found that this opened to my own Victorian styled bathroom. It contained a raised bath on tiny metal legs and had one of those shower heads that was screwed onto the taps. There where towels aplenty and even an assortment of colognes with some shaving supplies. It was like this room had been laid out for a visiting dignitary. In the main bedroom the wardrobe was stocked with clothes and shoes. Lots of them. I didn’t investigate that too closely. I closed the thick curtains and crawled into the bed for the best sleep I had ever had.</p>
<p>There where no clocks in the house and my watch had been taken from me by the police when I was rightfully slammed into a cell. I had no idea what time it was. I slept for hours, I assume. When I awoke the sun was still streaming in through the gap in the curtains, I wasn’t sure what that meant but as no one had woken me up I assumed it was okay, and I had not slept past my quote. I took a quick bath as an indulgence. And because I didn’t really understand how the shower tap worked. The towel that I found next to the tub was the finest quality that I had ever felt. It was fluffy and soft but also heavy and large. Granted I wasn’t that well travelled but I knew quality, even then.</p>
<p>I was feeling rested and fresh. My jeans however did not have the same glow of freshness that I had acquired. I investigated that wardrobe in more detail. It was well stocked with various garments. The main door revealed shirts, of assorted designs. Mostly single colours. Suits, Cargo pants, Jeans. It was crammed full of options, all my size of course. This made me smile to myself and came as no shock to me. This place was as perfect as it could be. The deep drawers at the bottom of the wardrobe contained assorted foot wear, from classic dress shoes to the most modern running shoes. The more modern stuff looked oddly out of place. The chest of drawers next to the wardrobe contained an indulgent assortment of underwear, including an odd amount of socks. I took some fresh blue jeans of superb quality, a black T-shirt and a rather nice brown suede jacket. Granted my fashion sense was not at its best but I thought I looked good. I decided to stick with my own trainers, they where nice. I checked myself out in the mirror, I looked good. I passed my own test of style and to be honest at that point I didn’t care what anyone else thought.</p>
<p>I had not been told what to do next so I wandered through the house. There where lots of people, they all ignored me for the most part. They all looked like they where busy going to somewhere, meetings maybe? No laptops in sight.I did get the occasional smile and nod. I felt like I had been there forever. I eventually found myself walking out of some already open patio doors into the wonderful garden where I could see Tom, sitting in a little garden chair drinking tea, alone. He waved me over.</p>
<p>“Hello Mike, did you sleep well?” asked Tom politely as I sat down. “Yes thank you. How long was I out for?” his response really did come as no shock at all to me, in fact I think I half expected it “Oh. It doesn’t really matter, time has no real hold over us here. You slept as much as you needed, and that’s a good thing.” I had a feeling that my relationship with Tom was going to be filled with cryptic lines and half truths. I was not to be disappointed.</p>
<p>There was quite a range of fruits, cheese and bread on the little table. Tom told me to eat. Unsurprisingly the food was exquisite. Rich flavours and bold colours struck me with everything I sampled. I was starting to get the idea. Everything in the Garden was always going to be perfect. I asked the obvious question “What is this place? It’s like a dream” Tom smiled and poured me some tea from a little pot. There where still a lot of people in the garden. Some where obviously on the way somewhere and some where just sitting reading or like us taking tea and nibbles in the sun. Tom took a deep and filling breath “This place is, our sanctuary, Its anything we need it do be.”</p>
<p>Tom asked me about my life, he listened intently to all the events that had led me to this afternoon tea. He listened about how I had not been popular at school and how I went from pointless job to dead end job to no job and then to crappy job. He honestly seemed interested in me, no one ever had been before. He listened to how I came home and got drunk, and how I looked out of the window and saw that thing, that monster. How I saw the vampire kill a stranger. He listened to how I sat cowering in fear for the whole night. He did not judge me. He didn’t tell me I was a coward. He understood that I was a civilian and I was part of an impossible event.</p>
<p>He then went on to tell me about Voids and that any place that was derived from significant numbers or a holy patch of land from the past or future could, on occasion serve as a void. They could become a doorway under the right conditions. He explained that the reason I had never seen anything through the window of my flat before was probably because there had been nothing to see before.</p>
<p>He told me about the unseen hand that they called ‘The Wind.’ ‘The wind’ is the reason that people do not see these strange things every day. ‘The Wind’ is the ethereal misdirection that makes most people see impossible events as everyday ones. No one really knows how it works but you can rely on it to cover your tracks. It will make the slaying of a vampire in a public place appear to be a work of entertainment to the crowd. A chase between you and a pack of vampires to be looked upon like a policeman chasing a crook. ‘The Wind’ is natures lie that keeps the two worlds apart. Only after someone has seen through a ‘void’ for the first time is it possible for them to accept the world without ‘The Wind’ and even then, it takes dedication to see the world for what it really is.</p>
<p>One point was repeated to me over and over. If you are killed by a vampire you’re not just dead. Your immortal soul is trapped inside it until it dies. A person killed by a vampire is not at peace and will not move on. They are forced to endure in the darkness where every moment is a thousand years of torment. It’s this darkness that allows them to live for so long and with enough souls as fuel they will have limitless power. When a hunter kills a vampire they are putting the souls of all it’s victims to rest. This, I was told. Was work to take pride in.</p>
<p>I remember clearly the final thing that Tom said to me while we drank tea, it was haunting at the time. He took the last sip of his tea and leaned forward and said “I’m sorry Mike. You are part of our world now. Through no fault of your own. You are part of it none the less. Try not to get killed.” he leaned back again and added “If you must, then die well.” He lent further back in his chair and looked up at the perfect clouds for just a moment. He then stood up, smiled at me and walked away from out little table.</p>
<p>As he left he a called over a young woman who stood by the wall to the side. She was a soldier, she carried many weapons and made no effort to hide it her hair was in a neat pony tail an her jacket was a flattering fit. It was the kind of thick material, not really military looking but the kind of jacket you see those hunter types wear. Her leg wear matched, functional and well fitting. He spoke to her briefly, I couldn’t make out what was said but she briskly walked over to me as Tom slowly walked away. She was quite short and looked to be in her twenties. She did not sit down. “Mike?” I nodded “I’m going to get you combat ready. Come with me please” she spoke sternly, I followed her without saying anything. We went to the far wing of the house and entered what appeared to be a training room, or Dojo of sorts.</p>
<p>There where one or two groups of people training with swords and some practising martial arts. The room was large enough that you could play football in there if you wanted to. The floor had rubber padded training mats scattered around and what I assumed where wooden training weapons on the walls. There were also some very interesting wooden chests and cupboards around the edges of the room. I didn’t get to inspect them closely. There was one much larger cupboard in the middle of the wall directly opposite the entrance. It was slightly sloped towards the top and had a different look to the rest of the room. I was a rougher older looking wood.</p>
<p>The young woman, who had not bothered to properly introduce herself, handed me a leather wrist band that she had fished out of one of the chest while I was taking in my new surroundings. “Put his on” she barked.</p>
<p>The wrist band looked like a cheap TV prop, it was thick and chunky brown leather it looked mass produced and had some holes punched in it. It was about six centimetres wide and had a brown rough string tried to one hole. I realised this this would be how I fastened it. I put on the wrist band using the string and holes to make it snug. “What is this?” I asked as I messed with the fit. She took hold of my arm and tightened it a properly for me. “Just because you saw one vampire it does not mean your free of the wind. This is a training tool. It will help you see more clearly” I nodded, it seamed to make sense that seeing through this supernatural force would require some training, “How does it work?” I asked. The woman ginned menacingly “pixie magic.” I wasn’t sure if she was joking or not but thought it best to to challenge her further.</p>
<p>Then she asked me “Do you have any experience with weapons?” I answered honestly “No, I’m sorry. I’m more a Video games and pizza kind of guy than a…” she nodded and waved a hand as if to silence me. She took a small charm out of one of the drawers closest to her. She tied the charm to my wrist band. It looked like a blue crystal wrapped in a thin red string. It seamed to glow. “Your going to be a warrior soon. This charm will give you the knowledge. Then it will be gone” she said cryptically. I had no idea what that meant but I nodded.</p>
<p>She then handed me two small daggers. They where unimpressive to look at. The were simple straight pointy things with red fabric wrapped around the handles an tied off at the base. There was no other ridges on them but there was a sharp looking blade on each edge.</p>
<p>She asked if I knew how to use them, I shook my head while I admired them, studied them. I had never held an actual weapon before.</p>
<p>The woman took a sword from the wall and without warning he swung it at me. Shocked I stumbled back and instinctively I tried to block her attack by pushing the flat portion of my blade flat against my wrist and allowing the sword to impact that. Something that made perfect sense to me but I had no idea why at the time. I was actually oddly impressed with myself. I held the other dagger in the air ready to attack. I could see the blue charm on my wrist glowing vibrantly. It grabbed my attention away from the actual attack. I hadn’t had a close look at the charm before. It was a tear drop shape tied haphazardly but very firmly with the red string. The charm its self caught the light, or did it glow? It was quite pretty.</p>
<p>My training partner while still pushing against my dagger leaned in to catch a glimpse of my charm. She nodded and stepped back, releasing her attack stance and lowering her weapon. “You’re ready now” she said. “What? I don’t get any training? That’s it?” I must have sounded so desperate. She closed the doors to the cupboard she had opened. “we don’t train anyone here. You train yourself, we just give you the tools to do it properly” she put Her sword back on the wall and instructed me to go and find Howard in the garden outside. I admired the daggers for one last moment and offered them back to her. She shook her head “keep hold of those for a little while, until you fancy something a little more refined.” she then pushed them gently back to me. “okay, thanks. I think” I paused for a moment while I realised that I was likely to injure myself. “Do you have a box or something?” I asked earnestly. She sighed with very real irritation. She snatched them out of my had and effortlessly flipped them over in her hand. She the stepped a little closed and slid one into each of my jacket pockets. “were done. Howard is looking after you. He’s in the front garden.”</p>
<p>As I tried to find the right path back to the exit I had used earlier I was thinking to myself about the events of the morning. I stopped at a window in the hall an looked at my reflection for a moment. I wanted to fit in here. I didn’t want to die and I liked Howard. I wanted to pass inspection. My focus changed for a moment and I saw the people carrying weapons openly outside. I moved my daggers from my pockets and pushed them down the back of my belt so the handles were pressing into my spine. It probably wasn’t that safe but it would look a lot smoother when I pulled them out. Howard was bound to ask if I had everything I needed and I didn’t want to fumble my armed début.</p>
<p>Sure enough Howard was waiting at the door to the garden. He was smoking, as I had come to expect. I hand not paid much attention to how he looked last time we met but I did this time. He was wearing a black shirt and jeans with baseball shoes. He carried a black canvas messenger bag. His hair was grey and his stubble was too little for a beard but too much for a days growth. He was also quiet scrawny. There was nothing really remarkable about him. I had a feeling that this was by design.</p>
<p>“Are we ready to get your vampire now?” He asked. Howard seamed well rested now. I asked him what the plan was and he said that he didn’t like plans. We walked a little way away past the garden wall. Howard took two stick from his satchel and banged them together. The sticks looked like thick drum sticks with a short thin black ribbon hanging from each. In the time it took for him to strike them together again I blinked. Instantly I was somewhere else. I was standing in the garage, the door was half open and it was dawn.</p>
<p>The city Snapped into focus a few moments later and my ears were flooded with the sounds of my world again. I felt sick and a little disoriented.</p>
<p>There was no field. No Sunshine and no white house. I shook off my moment of confusion and then I tasted that air. No longer the crisp clean country air of the garden but instead the tainted oily air of a city. I was back where I belonged. Back in the real world. Back where there as no magic and no sword fights with attractive strangers. No tea with interesting gentlemen an most worryingly no promised safety from supernatural soul stealing monsters.</p>
<p>I was scared again.</p>
<h2 id="more-soon.">MORE SOON….</h2>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>New World Same Nerd</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/new-world-same-nerd.html</guid>
<pubDate>Rab, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<pre><code>      ::::    :::::::::::::::::::::: :::::::::
     :+:+:   :+::+:       :+:    :+::+:    :+:
    :+:+:+  +:++:+       +:+    +:++:+    +:+
   +#+ +:+ +#++#++:++#  +#++:++#: +#+    +:+
  +#+  +#+#+#+#+       +#+    +#++#+    +#+
 #+#   #+#+##+#       #+#    #+##+#    #+#
###    #################    ############</code></pre>
<p><img src="../images/itsfine.jpg" /></p>
<p><em>I cower from the evil day star, safe in my gaming hole.</em></p>
<p><em>you may want to skip to the last paragraph before reading this shit!</em></p>
<p>As the world locks down and nails boards over the windows for the Viral Apocalypse I am a little confused as to how little my life has actually changed. I still go to work (I have a job that is related to food supply chain, so no change for me) I come home, watch a show while I make and consume my daily meal. Then I sit at my desk to play/stream video games, and chat with my friends.</p>
<p>Some times I draw (Aseprite, I love pixels) sometimes I watch streaming media. Usually I listen to terrible pop music while I’m here.</p>
<p>My friends are on Discord, my hobbies take place at my desk. I am blessed with being an indoors-man at this time.</p>
<p>I do however worry about the people that are not locked in hermits like me. The people who crave physical contact and require a group to in order to be whole. The people who’s hobbies are sports, or events or even museums and talks. These people must feel caged during these times. I have been thinking a lot about these people recently.</p>
<p>I think its our job as veterans of the inside hobbies to educate and inform where we can. And I don’t mean, “go fourth an preach the gospel of the inside, cry true the evils of the day star” but to tell people of the thing that we do that allow us to not just “get by” inside but to thrive here. I have some thoughts. I will share them</p>
<h2 id="things-to-know-when-telling-people-about-your-hobbit-hole-life.">Things to know when telling people about your hobbit hole life.</h2>
<ul>
<li>Never invalidate someones indoor pass times: I know a woman who literally reads for 8 hours at a time and is super happy with it. Most of us read before bed. Or while we eat a bowl of steamed veggies (I want a bowl of steamed veggies right now…. Just saying.) What works for you maybe madness to someone else and you know, Uno Reverse.</li>
<li>Always Be ready to hear “you are a sad geek” because… Yeah, form their point of view… You are. From our point of view “but you watch tv all day, HOW is that better!”</li>
<li>There is always that person who thinks your lifestyle is a symptom of depression. I’m a happy dude with good mental health (I think) but someone is always feeling bad for me :/ its annoying.</li>
<li>Video games are for kids! And watching 14 hours of TV a day is for idiots so flip a coin Tina - don’t say that.</li>
<li>There are people who want to me miserable during lock down, they embrace it. Those people are not for you to help.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="things-to-do-while-the-earth-is-closed.">Things to do while the earth is closed.</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Watch a movie with friends:</strong> Find a movie on a streaming website. Get friends in a voice chat room (I prefer discord) someone (Matt in our case) says “3… 2… 1… go!” and everyone presses the triangle button to make it go. You mostly sit in silence and watch the movie. But the occasional comments from the person you are “sitting with” makes the whole thing more social!</li>
<li><strong>Online gaming:</strong> Some people don’t want to play Overwatch with you for hours. But some people have never played Overwatch… They may just need you to get them to try it and BOOM a new smack talking Hanso Main is born. Or, you know, Stellaris, Civ, whatever. The point is, new gamers can be born.</li>
<li><strong>Your friend Mike has never seen Star Trek:</strong> Mike isn’t going to want to leave the house for the next few months because he’s about to learn that the joy of Star Trek isn’t watching the shows or movies. It’s about arguing with you about it. Personally I think Voyager is mostly Trash and TNG is over rated. I also think Data was a pointless character who would have been greatly enhanced if the crew rejected him as an individual. Then slowly over the 7 year run, they thought of him more and more as a person. Eventually they could have told HIM that he was a real boy and all that. Rather than the “knock off Vulcan” we got.</li>
<li><strong>Porn:</strong> You could be dry on the inside by the time this is all over. Don’t over do it… but you know… if you are not a “user” of porn usually. You may like what this little site called “pornhub” has to offer. Personally I enjoy the offerings of the ‘Hentai’ category.</li>
<li><strong>Finally learn how to use a computer properly:</strong> There are a lot of people that leave comments on my YouTube videos telling me how they don’t have time to learn a Tiler, or how to configure a Suckless application. Those people have time now :) - Learn C, Python, Bash…. use this time to level up!</li>
<li><strong>I like to draw:</strong> one of the things that I love to do is draw little pixel versions of things in Aseprite. Maybe you would too. OR maybe this is a good time to learn the Cello. Find something you can obsess over or bask in while you are locked it… Like Animal Crossing :)</li>
<li><strong>Write a blog post</strong> I’m Just saying that while your daughter is doing school work, you may want to look supportive and not be seen to be playing Animal Crossing while watching Star Trek. You may realise that its better if it looks like you are working hard on something, not fucking around with Tom Nook. You may deicide that the best use of your time is to write a blog post but have no ideas so you basically ramble pointlessly for 1024 words now. yeah.</li>
</ul>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Upgrades and Otters</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/upgrades-and-otters.html</guid>
<pubDate>Rab, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="upgrades-rambles-and-half-baked-thoughts---an-opus.">Upgrades, Rambles and Half Baked Thoughts - An Opus.</h2>
<p>It has been a little while since I wrote a thing. It’s not that I have been sort of thoughts to write about but more that finding the time to tap those thoughts into Vim has been a problem. Not that anyone reads this <em>really</em> (lol?)</p>
<p>The last update was about the office carpet and re-shuffle. Since then there have been PC upgrades, games played and thoughts had.</p>
<p><img src="../images/2020-03-01%2017.03.48.jpg" /></p>
<h2 id="pc-upgrades.">PC Upgrades.</h2>
<p>I had a little money saved and managed to ‘gather’ enough together to get the parts I wanted. For the benefit of historical documentation allow me to show you this table.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>PART</th>
<th>OLD</th>
<th>NEW</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>CPU</td>
<td>Intel I7 3770</td>
<td>AMD R4 3600</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>RAM</td>
<td>DDR3 16GB</td>
<td>DDR4 32GB (Corsair LPX)</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>MB</td>
<td>Gigabyte ?</td>
<td>MSI B450 Mortar Max</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>STORAGE</td>
<td>126GB ssd</td>
<td>2x Crucual NVMe Drivers (1GB/500GB)</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>STORAGE</td>
<td>3 TB Rust</td>
<td>1tb 2.5inch Rush (for Archival)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><img src="../images/2020-02-22%2014.43.18.jpg" /></p>
<p>Things I kept from my old build were:</p>
<ul>
<li>Case - Aerocool DS Cube (MATX)</li>
<li>PSU - Corsair Builder 600</li>
<li>Graphics card - Gigabyte branded NVIDIA GTX 970 (Windforce cooler)</li>
</ul>
<p>The original plan was to keep the stock cooler but quickly I came to the realisation that I was a little hotter than I was happy with.</p>
<h2 id="with-great-hardware-come-great-re-install.">With great Hardware come great re-install.</h2>
<p>Once built, and having new hard drives it was time to install my OS on this wonderful little bundle of joy. I eventually got Arch all set up and properly configured with the help of Friend Drew (Friendo, Uoou) who cut down my install time by knowing things (We chatted via Discord on my phone)</p>
<p>I just say, on a side note the arch install guide is literally shit. They changed things, made things unclear and generally the whole thing would be a nightmare for a new user. Just make a fucking install script you nasty elitist hipsters…. For real, how does giving people a nice easy to use TUI Installer detract from what Arch is??? Hu??? How?? I get you gotta “learn how to” blah blah blah… I HAVE the skills to install Arch (Because its not as hard as meme lords make out) but I almost installed Manjaro because I had better things to do… .. .. rant over.</p>
<p>My OS is on my 500GB NVMe and my Home folder is on the 1TB one. I also put in my old 1TB 2.5 inch Mechanical drive to use as an “Archive” drive for OBS stuff, System Snapshots and basically anything that I don’t have to care about speed for. Its currently got 900GB free, so its not seeing much use. Still best to use it than to let it gather dust, I suppose.</p>
<p><img src="../images/2020-02-22%2014.43.12.jpg" /></p>
<p>As for Software selection, I went with my usual choices mostly.</p>
<p>BSPWM - A quality tiler but honestly DWM or BSPWM was a toss of a coin. They are both great and either would make me happy. Editor - NeoVim with my usual Config. Dots - Same old Git lab repo. Storage - Dropbox because its cheap. Games - Yes. File Manager - Ranger for most things and Thunar for editing. Problems - no.</p>
<p><img src="../images/2020-02-22%2015.23.41.jpg" /></p>
<h2 id="challenges">Challenges</h2>
<ul>
<li>Cant get google-drive-ocaml to compile.</li>
<li>Don’t seem to be able to convince my older appimage of KDENLIVE to use all 32gb of RAM</li>
<li>I find myself wanting a new mouse (Unrelated, I suppose)</li>
<li>I can not afford a new graphics card. Thats a shame because its the last thing I need for this to ‘feel’ like a new PC</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="../images/2020-02-22%2015.36.22.jpg" /></p>
<p>Anyway, all of this is my way of saying sorry. I missed a few uploads and have had some distracted streams. Normal service has now been resumed. Including this pointless Blog that NO ONE reads.</p>
<p><img src="../images/2020-03-01%2019.30.10.jpg" /></p>
<p>Thanks for Reading.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Vanity Carpet and 2 lost days</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/vanity-carpet-and-2-lost-days.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sel, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="vanity">Vanity</h1>
<p>Here is what my office looked like just a few days ago (well. A photo of it, I can’t project the character or spirit of the place…. Most pretentious think I’ve said ever, I know)</p>
<p><img src="../images/office1.jpg" /></p>
<p>It looks cluttered (I like cluttered) and has a brown floor. The flooring, you can’t really see here, is made of Carpet Tiles. These things have proven to be a terrible idea over the last few years for a few reasons.</p>
<ul>
<li>They travel. They are designed for perfectly flat office floors not rickety old 50’s floor boards. As such, they move around a little and its annoying</li>
<li>They are not as hard wearing as expected!</li>
<li>My house is old and the rooms are not as square as you would think, so there was a lot of patchwork around the edges.</li>
<li>They are a light brown. The worst brown.</li>
<li>You can’t really see on this picture but there <em>are</em> gaps between some times (because of the aforementioned “not square room” I assume. Some tiles oddly seem to have gotten slightly smaller over time… odd one that is)</li>
</ul>
<p>With all this in mind, it seeded like a good idea to change the shitty brown squares for a lush carpet!</p>
<p>I am not a rich man and when I get the idea to re-cover my floor it takes me a couple of months to actually gain the Gold required to make it happen. This week was that time.</p>
<figure>
<img src="../images/office5.jpg" alt="Your new Desktop backdrop?" /><figcaption aria-hidden="true">Your new Desktop backdrop?</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Here is the time line of events presented in the form of yet another GLORIOUS bullet pointed list (The bullet points just make it all seem so much more interesting, IMO)</p>
<ul>
<li>Saturday: commence “trinket” removal (All things removed being Tetris-ed into my Bedroom/My daughters bedroom/My Bathroom/just generally around my landing area… Is landing the right word?)</li>
<li>Sunday: Book/Furniture/Other removal - Leaving computers and desk. Removal of old shitty tiles of brown (Took ages)</li>
<li>Monday (Morning): up at 7AM. Remove computers (took longer than you would expect) and unscrewed some shelves that prevent the desk from moving out of its ‘nook’</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="../images/office2.jpg" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Monday (Afternoon): Carpet heroes arrive with my ostentatious master covering. Only one or two shots at my terrible taste were taken. After half an hour of hard work they rode of into the sunset leaving my life much improved.</li>
<li>Monday Evening/Tuesday-ALL-DAY: Return office to full working order as well as some sorting, ordering, binning, moving and tweaking.</li>
</ul>
<p>Once it was all back in and wires were <em>a little bit</em> more organised than they were before, in my opinion over 20 Million times better.</p>
<p>Here is an RL screen shot of the first moments in my finally restored palace of joy</p>
<p><img src="../images/office4.jpg" /></p>
<p>You may have noticed that there is not a nice desk at the other side of the room. It’s a bit of kitchen work top I had left over from when the house received a kitchen upgrade a few months ago. I slapped some cheap IKEA legs under it and called it a “desk”</p>
<p><img src="../images/office3.jpg" /></p>
<p>The new desk will mostly be for when I want to fuck around with old computers or maybe toasters, but it also doubles up as a nice little desk for my ‘other’ PC. My home server machine is slotted in next to it. Putting all my useful PC’s in one room without being insanely cluttered is nice. This desk also gives me a more sensible place to work when I’m peering inside PC cases.</p>
<p><img src="../images/office6.jpg" /></p>
<p>Over all, I’m thrilled at the results. The one down side is that my old arse house has old arse floorboards. Those boards are not actually straight or even. So the carpet looks “uneven” in a few places but this is a result of the lines tracing the contours of the floor. Should have thought about that before it got strips I suppose.</p>
<p>I’ve decided that for the first time ever, I’m going to try and live my life without a rug in the middle of the floor. I tried a rug. It broke up my glorious stripes and what’s the point in having stripes if you are not going to bask in them?</p>
<h2 id="thoughts-you-may-have-had.">Thoughts you may have had.</h2>
<p>This is where, through the power of future sight and time travel I will attempt to address thoughts you may have had as you read the things I wrote for you to read. For entertainment (of me mostly) I will only agree with your thoughts!</p>
<ul>
<li>YES! There <strong>will</strong> be more bullet points for no reason!</li>
<li>YES! that <strong>IS</strong> a Besom Broom you can see next to my desk.</li>
<li>YES! My wiring is terrible. And YES! I don’t care about that because pretty wiring makes for HARD maintenance for people who actually mess with PCs and don’t just post photos to /r/Battlestations</li>
<li>YES! It is a hideous carpet! I like it. OKAY! I FUCKING LIKE IT! OH-KAH-AAA-AY?</li>
<li>YES! my window frames DO look Dirty! I assure you, they are clean. Just VERY old and stained. Planning on bleaching them soon.</li>
<li>YES! There <em>is</em> a lot of shit in my office. I like it like that! Feels like home</li>
<li>YES! The office DOES look tiny on those picture. My phone (Pixel 3) has a ‘wide’ mode on the selfie camera. It gets it all on there, but the effect makes it look like a shoe box.</li>
<li>YES! Many of you will have been bored shitless by this post. You should have stopped reading… Dummy!</li>
<li>YES! I will stop fucking around with the office and get back to making YouTube videos. RIGHT NOW!</li>
</ul>
<p>Hex out! Drops mic!</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>HexShards Tape 2</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/hexshards-tape-2.html</guid>
<pubDate>Min, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<pre><code>888 888                   dP&quot;8 888 888     e Y8b     888 88e  888 88e    dP&quot;8
888 888  ,e e,   Y8b Y8Y C8b Y 888 888    d8b Y8b    888 888D 888 888b  C8b Y
8888888 d88 88b   Y8b Y   Y8b  8888888   d888b Y8b   888 88&quot;  888 8888D  Y8b
888 888 888   ,  e Y8b   b Y8D 888 888  d888888888b  888 b,   888 888P  b Y8D
888 888  &quot;YeeP&quot; d8b Y8b  8edP  888 888 d8888888b Y8b 888 88b, 888 88&quot;   8edP</code></pre>
<p>I really LIKE hex shards. Making it, that is. I find it wonderful to just have a pointless outlet for something I want to say and not have to have a reason or enough content for a whole video. People mostly, seem to like it. I took the lack of hate mail as good reason to carry on.</p>
<audio controls style="width:100%;">
<source src="http://hexdsl.co.uk/hexshards/HexShard_02-02-2020.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
</source>
Your browser does not support the audio element.
</audio>
<p><a href="http://hexdsl.co.uk/hexshards/HexShard_02-02-2020.mp3">Download</a> - Right click and save it.</p>
<p>Thanks.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Why is everything so damned good</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/why-is-everything-so-damned-good.html</guid>
<pubDate>Min, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<pre><code>                             888
                             888
                             888
 .d88b.  .d88b.  .d88b.  .d88888
d88P&quot;88bd88&quot;&quot;88bd88&quot;&quot;88bd88&quot; 888
888  888888  888888  888888  888
Y88b 888Y88..88PY88..88PY88b 888
 &quot;Y88888 &quot;Y88P&quot;  &quot;Y88P&quot;  &quot;Y88888
     888
Y8b d88P
 &quot;Y88P&quot;</code></pre>
<p><em>Content warning: this is a pointless ramble</em></p>
<p>The biggest problem I face with my entertainment is that is TOO damned good! Here are the plates I’m currently spinning… (Things I’m trying to find time for)</p>
<p><strong>Video</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>All those CW DC shows (CW)</li>
<li>Lucifer (Netflix)</li>
<li>More Star Trek TOS, that I never stop watching.</li>
<li>My Yearly Babylon 5 Re watch (DVD rips)</li>
<li>Nancy Drew (CW)</li>
<li>Picard (Amazon Video)</li>
<li>Witcher (Netflix)</li>
<li>Movies!
<ul>
<li>Bourne Movies (Never watched)</li>
<li>Frozen 2</li>
<li>Green Book</li>
<li>Hunger Games Movies (Never watched)</li>
<li>Jay &amp; Bob reboot</li>
<li>Knives out</li>
<li>Millionaires Express</li>
<li>Nancy Drew (The Staircase one)</li>
<li>Please Stand by</li>
<li>Two Popes</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Games</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>1 Screen Platformer (Steam)</li>
<li>A <em>bunch</em> of retro games I want to play more of</li>
<li>Assassins Creed: Odyssey (Stadia)</li>
<li>CastleVania Collection (Switch)</li>
<li>Final Fantasy XV (Stadia)</li>
<li>Golf Story (Switch)</li>
<li>Littlewood (Steam)</li>
<li>NiNoKuni 1 (Steam)</li>
<li>Phoenix Wright (Switch)</li>
<li>Rage 2 (Stadia)</li>
<li>Red Bow (Steam)</li>
<li>Science Girls (Steam)</li>
<li>TemTem (Steam)</li>
<li>And all the</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Books (<em>and comics</em>)</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Artemis (Audible)</li>
<li>Art of Electronics (Book)</li>
<li>E.W.Hournung Collection (Kindle)</li>
<li>John Carter - Only up to book 3 (Kindle)</li>
<li>Learning Emacs, 4rd Edition (Kindle)</li>
<li>Morningwood (Audible)</li>
<li>Old Man’s War (Audible)</li>
<li>Planned re read of X-Men Comic run 1988-now (I have a large x-men collection)</li>
<li>Sed &amp; Awk, 2nd Edition (Kindle)</li>
<li>Some Faith Books I wont bore you with (4 Books)</li>
<li>Superman and Philosophy (Kindle)</li>
<li>The Authorities (Audible)</li>
<li>The Eye of the World (Audible)</li>
<li>The Last 12 months of Batman comics</li>
<li>The Last 12 months of Flash comics</li>
<li>The Moon is a Harsh Mistress (Kindle <em>or</em> Book)</li>
<li>The Winds of Garth (Kindle)</li>
<li>Y the last man comic (re-read)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Other Hobbies</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Actual friendships and people and stuff.</li>
<li>Decorating - Literally a chore I <em>have</em> to do this month, been putting it off for way too long (Got to empty whole office, no small task)</li>
<li>Faith ‘stuff’ (Am Wiccan, need to spend more time on those things Wiccans write. Its important to me)</li>
<li>I have been messing with more and more Electronic repair over the last few months, its turning into a full blown hobby now.</li>
<li>Messing with Linux ‘stuff’</li>
<li>Pixel Art (Slamming them dots)</li>
<li>YouTube - Making</li>
<li>YouTube - Watching</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Other Essential Time sinks</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Job</li>
<li>Sleeping</li>
</ul>
<p>The reality of all this is that I’m rarely at a loss for things to do. I’ve had to start making Task-lists in Calcurse just to keep track of it all. And, I’m at the point where I actively DODGE picking up new things to be interested in because its too much.</p>
<p>This is an odd sort of satisfaction to have. While some people I know say dumb shit like “If I won the lottery I would still work, for something to do” or “I can’t have more than a few days off work. I’m at a loss for what to do with all the time”, I am constantly fighting with all the cool shit in my world and its all wonderful.</p>
<p>If books, comics, TV, Movies, Music and Games were all put on freeze right now, I would have enough stuff to do for the next 100 Years!</p>
<p>I listed all the cool shit I like in this post, on the off chance that you, dear reader may want to look some of this cool shit up. But, the reality is, I think, that you will be making some ’lol’s as you read because your list of shit you want to read/watch/play/listen/do is just as long as mine.</p>
<p>We live in an odd time where the rate of “good shit” vastly out paces the rate of “free time we got” and I fear, thinks are only going to get more dense at that ‘time’ goes on.</p>
<p>Not to mention all the cool shit Ive never even heard about yet</p>
<p>What a wonderful time.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>The Audio Thing Tape1</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/the-audio-thing-tape1.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sen, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<pre><code>888 888                   dP&quot;8 888 888     e Y8b     888 88e  888 88e    dP&quot;8
888 888  ,e e,   Y8b Y8Y C8b Y 888 888    d8b Y8b    888 888D 888 888b  C8b Y
8888888 d88 88b   Y8b Y   Y8b  8888888   d888b Y8b   888 88&quot;  888 8888D  Y8b
888 888 888   ,  e Y8b   b Y8D 888 888  d888888888b  888 b,   888 888P  b Y8D
888 888  &quot;YeeP&quot; d8b Y8b  8edP  888 888 d8888888b Y8b 888 88b, 888 88&quot;   8edP</code></pre>
<p>I have been talking about this audio idea since November. Heres the first one. I have still not decided between HexShards or HexNuggets for the title. Feedback Welcome.</p>
<audio controls style="width:100%;">
<source src="http://hexdsl.co.uk/hexshards/HexShard_13-01-2020.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
</source>
Your browser does not support the audio element.
</audio>
<p><a href="http://hexdsl.co.uk/hexshards/HexShard_13-01-2020.mp3">Download</a> - Right click and save it.</p>
<p>Thanks.</p>
<p>EDIT: It’s called HexSHARDS based on audience early feedback. Locked it in!!! (renamed the script and everything)</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>GDX DX Repair Video</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/gdx-dx-repair-video.html</guid>
<pubDate>Min, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>This post is not Linux related! (shock! horror!)</p>
<h2 id="the-problem">The Problem!</h2>
<p>I have this Android emulator handheld gaming thing. Its a GPD XD+ and I really like it. Because it gets a lot of use, it has began showing signs of its age. The hinge housing on the top part of the lower half has cracked. I think it over heated on me once or twice when I was pushing it pretty hard (Emulating a Playstation 2 to play a long session of Tony Hawk 2) and the D-Pad is not what it once was.</p>
<h2 id="solution-time">Solution Time!</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>Change Housing for new, stronger one (I think) that I brought from E-Bay.</li>
<li>Tighten Hinge so it wobbles less (always pissed me off that has.)</li>
<li>Change Thermal Paste for the good stuff I use on my PC.</li>
<li>Change D-Pad for a Nintendo DS Lite one - those are nice and I’m told it fits if i have a Rubber pressure thing from a Wii-remote. (unclear but I will harvest all the bits anyway)</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="i-am-a-man-of-action">I am a man of ACTION!</h2>
<div class="xpeng">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kATHpb_o6wE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>
</iframe>
</div>
<h2 id="how-did-it-go">How did it go?</h2>
<p>GREAT! - I now have a much improved device! - The DS D-Pad was a little lower profile than the GPD one, it feels nice. I did not have to change the plastic top, the rubber would have been enough to improve it up the DS one looks stark! (its while on a black device and I like how it looks, Janky appeals to me!) and the plastic is MUCH higher quality on the DS one.</p>
<p>The new case IS thicker plastic than the old one so will last longer HOWEVER its thicker on the outer edge. Is not as good a fit as the original. Again, I enjoy Janky so its fine for me.</p>
<p>Also the WIFI antenna was a dick and I needed to re-solder it when I put it all back together. The bad join on it must have been a long standing issue because my repair job has resulted in VASTLY improved WIFI - So, that was a win! - I also liked that I got to check continuity with my Multi-Meter. I like the beep it makes!</p>
<p>I had a nice time doing it. There was a time in my life when I would have either lived with the broken hinge or would have just thrown it out. I like fixing things.</p>
<h2 id="your-head">YOUR HEAD!</h2>
<p>Yes. I know. If I do any more of these types of videos I’ll keep my noggin out of the way more. Also, when the office re-shuffle happens in a couple of weeks I’m planning on setting up a dedicated desk for fixing shit and working on PC’s. That desk may end up with a dedicated PC and camera for these types of projects.</p>
<h2 id="can-i-have-more-less-of-this-stuff">Can I have more / less of this stuff?</h2>
<p>YES! let me know if its more or less you want!</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Audio Thing Details</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/audio-thing-details.html</guid>
<pubDate>Kam, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<pre><code> _                 _______  _______  _______ _________ _______
( (    /||\     /|(  ____ \(  ____ \(  ____ \__   __/(  ____ \
|  \  ( || )   ( || (    \/| (    \/| (    \/   ) (   | (    \/
|   \ | || |   | || |      | |      | (__       | |   | (_____
| (\ \) || |   | || | ____ | | ____ |  __)      | |   (_____  )
| | \   || |   | || | \_  )| | \_  )| (         | |         ) |
| )  \  || (___) || (___) || (___) || (____/\   | |   /\____) |
|/    )_)(_______)(_______)(_______)(_______/   )_(   \_______)</code></pre>
<p><img src="../images/hexshard.png" /></p>
<p>Quick update, so that you know for certain that its still a thing!</p>
<p>The audio blog/thoughts/thing I spoke about in a previous post. Yeah that! - Well. It took me a whole damned evening but the system for making it is all done now. Here is the work-flow…</p>
<p>Voice segments are recorded with Android “recorder” application (It’s a Google app that has some Pixel specific features, so I’m using it until I find a better option) It then saves those segments to Google Drive (because there is a button and the point of this whole thing is not fucking around!)</p>
<p>The script, mounts Gdrive, grabs the files. Converts them to the correct format (using sox) then exports them into one mp3, with an intro and a beep between every clip, then an outro. It then deletes all the junk and plops the MP3 in the correct folder for uploading to this very site! - Its basic as fuck but it literally works perfectly for what I want to do!</p>
<p>The uploads themselves will be called (either) Hex Nuggets or Hex Shards. I have to settle on a name for them but at the moment I like Nuggets best as its less pretentious.</p>
<p>The first shard/nugget will be uploaded at some point over the next few days. I expect the first one to be terrible. At the moment its a few clips of sort of half blogs. There’s not really a lot of value to any of them. But, I want this to act as voice log as much as ‘podcast bytes’ and I have to learn what works/doesn’t work with this sort of project.</p>
<p>The few after that will probably be less ‘Bloggy’ and more like half baked Linux/Gaming thoughts that may or may not lead to videos. This whole thing may be terrible and the fact that I’m nervous about that is utterly wonderful!</p>
<p>I have enjoyed thinking about something that’s not related to YouTube but is still something that I can share.</p>
<p>Long term, I would love to see this website be my main “creative” outlet, the place that people can go to read/listen to my thoughts on games and Linux. Because if I’m honest with myself, YouTube feels oppressive now!</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>New year new project</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/new-year-new-project.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sel, 24 Des 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<pre><code>                __
 __  __    ___ /\_\    ___     __
/\ \/\ \  / __`\/\ \  /&#39;___\ /&#39;__`\
\ \ \_/ |/\ \L\ \ \ \/\ \__//\  __/
 \ \___/ \ \____/\ \_\ \____\ \____\
  \/__/   \/___/  \/_/\/____/\/____/</code></pre>
<p>Here are some facts… fast facts!</p>
<ul>
<li>I schedule for videos on Mondays, Tuesday and Fridays!</li>
<li>Mondays video have always been .XPenguin.</li>
<li>.XPenguin is now over.</li>
<li>I really like Salted Peanuts. (Specifically KP, I like how the logo is a silhouette of a nut)</li>
<li>Sayonara Wild Hears was a GREAT game! - it made me cry! twice!</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="../images/sayonara.png" /></p>
<p>Not that this post is about Sayonara Wild Hearts. But on a side note I found <a href="https://backlogcrusader.com/2019/10/06/sayonara-wild-hearts-analysis/">this excellent breakdown</a> of the game and its story.</p>
<p>Look at me, distracting myself on the first paragraph. Legendary power move that was! (I assure you I chuckled while writing that.)</p>
<h2 id="no-video-on-mondays-then">No video on Mondays then?</h2>
<p>No. Maybe, I don’t know. I think I’m going to use Mondays as a “if I have something to say” day. But if I have nothing, I won’t worry about it. I mean, without doing the podcast, I could see myself having a lot to say on Mondays. Over all I think the post XP world will have as much, or more content than it did before. - so, yeah, don’t worry!</p>
<h2 id="why-does-it-say-voice-at-the-top-is-isometric-ascii">Why does it say VOICE at the top is isometric ASCII?</h2>
<p>So that you will ask that question, reminding me to tell you about the “HexDSL’s unnamed Voice log project!” Its called that because I have not settled on a name yet.</p>
<p>The project is a sort of Voice log. A VLOG but the V stands for Voice not Video. When I have a thought or an idea, I simply pull out my high quality portable audio device and ramble to myself (its my phone)</p>
<p>I take the clips when there are enough of them and put them into one audio file between each little clip, we have a BEEP for separation.</p>
<p>Then I upload it here for sharing. People can listen or not listen. Mostly it will be for me to listen to when I’m old(er) and grey (balder) but you may like it. Most times ill write an accompanying post to read along with it.</p>
<p>If you have name suggestions then please do message me. I like Mastodon, IRC or Discord. I am also not afraid of e-mail.</p>
<h2 id="whats-all-this-sayonara-wild-hearts-rambling-about">Whats all this Sayonara Wild Hearts rambling about?</h2>
<p>Its this great game I played last night, and again this morning. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1122720/Sayonara_Wild_Hearts/">Here’s the Steam Page</a>. It’s this game that’s about an hour and some change long. Its neon and purple/pink and has an amazing soundtrack. I can’t really describe it but its about fixing a broken heart and kissing bad guys on the cheek until you feel better. Yeah… Really. I loved it. All of it. It was a wonderful example of how games can be art and tell stories in ways that only games can. Also, it makes no fucking sense while totally making sense. Just play it! It’s on the Switch too! (I played in on Switch but it has PLATINUM rating on ProtonDB)</p>
<h2 id="peanuts">Peanuts?</h2>
<p><strong>YES</strong></p>
<p>Hex out. Drops Mic!</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>My FireFox</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/my-firefox.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sen, 16 Des 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>My Firefox is pretty odd looking, I know.</p>
<p>A few people now have asked about it. I uploaded the one file needed as well as a little instructional guide to gitlab.</p>
<p><a href="https://gitlab.com/hexdsl/dots/tree/master/firefox">This is the link</a></p>
<p>Just read that. I wrote it there, not here. Because it made way more sense to write that on Gitlab, where people will need it. Not here, where no-one reads, as far as I know.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Evolution</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/evolution.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sab, 14 Des 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<pre><code>XX    XX EEEEEEE NN   NN DDDDD   IIIII NN   NN   GGGG
 XX  XX  EE      NNN  NN DD  DD   III  NNN  NN  GG  GG
  XXXX   EEEEE   NN N NN DD   DD  III  NN N NN GG
 XX  XX  EE      NN  NNN DD   DD  III  NN  NNN GG   GG
XX    XX EEEEEEE NN   NN DDDDDD  IIIII NN   NN  GGGGGG</code></pre>
<p>Over the last few years, there has been an episode of .XPenguin every Saturday. Its occasionally been moved to a Sunday because of life commitments (and this one time that my net was broken) but I think its fair to say that I have never missed an episode.</p>
<p>The show has evolved wonderfully as time has passed. We have changed co-hosts and visuals and had at least three “intro” videos. The show currently looks better than it ever has. The website looks about as “on brand” as it can and the people who watch appear to <em>really</em> like the show,</p>
<p><img src="../images/xp0.jpg" /></p>
<p>With all this in mind it is with a sad disposition that I officially confirm the end of ‘regularly scheduled .XPenguin episodes’ not the forever end. To be clear.</p>
<p><strong>What?</strong></p>
<p>Over the last 3 years+ I have spent at around 10 hours a week making sure that .XPenguin is as good as I can make it. I read Linux news daily, I note down any links of articles that I may want to talk about and follow evolving stories as they happen. I force myself to hit Reddit daily (and I really hate Reddit) as well as writing show notes and inviting guests onto the show. Then there’s the actual show its self that often runs for two hours. Uploading, creating thumbnails and audio rips for Patreon. What I’m trying to say is, <em>it’s a lot of work.</em></p>
<p><strong>And?</strong></p>
<p>With this in mind, I want to ‘not do a podcast’ for a bit. I’m pretty sure that XPenguin will return in a year or so when I’m fired up to do it again, or occasionally when I really have something to say. But, for now. It’s on pause.</p>
<p><img src="../images/xp1.png" /></p>
<p><strong>How can you do this to us?</strong></p>
<p>The show is watched by around 15-20 people live, 40 people on bitchute (oddly) and 120-230 people on YouTube (usually.) I have no idea how many people listen on Spotify or RSS it really is well liked. I do feel bad but I would rather take this massive break while the show is well liked than wait for it to start dropping viewers and <em>then</em> stop it. Its better to end your show while its good than risk becoming season 5 of Ally McBeal (I know, you haven’t seen it, but I assure you it was shit)</p>
<p><strong>What are we supposed to do now?</strong></p>
<p>There are other podcasts! There are! - and going forward I will be doing regular streams on Saturdays, pretty much as usual. While they will be “bigger” and more “news filled” than my usual streams they will not be a “formal podcast” or anything like it. It will be me hanging out with friends and chatting about Linux stuff while we play games. The main difference between my regular streams and the new Saturday streams will be that it will more often than not find its way to YouTube and occasionally may show on the .XPenguin website (So to make its way to the RSS and Spotify.) I don’t want people to think I’m leaving or fading. I am 100% committed to my channel and the shit I make. Making shit has literally measurably improved my life and I’ll not be stopping.</p>
<p>The new format will be called .Hex as an homage to .XPenguin but as I said, not a formal Podcast. Because of this I won’t feel too bad if I have to cancel the odd evening when I have things to do with my Daughter or friends. Generally the whole thing will be way more relaxed.</p>
<p><img src="../images/xp2.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>You did all this alone?</strong></p>
<p>No. I need to thank the people listed below for literally enabling me to do the show for the last few years! - I did type up the reasons that I was thanking them but it got long. So here are the names of the people that deserve my thanks the most (Alphabetically listed, not in order of awesome, because that would be stressful.)</p>
<ul>
<li>AmazingMoox</li>
<li>ArchToasty</li>
<li>ChrisWere</li>
<li>CyberusUK</li>
<li>HamishTPB</li>
<li>HangmansJoe</li>
<li>Kylinx</li>
<li>LinuxPaulM</li>
<li>Ozone (SudoShred)</li>
<li>Uoou</li>
</ul>
<p>There has also been a remarkable number of guest on the show over the years and without them the show would have been much less fun to make.</p>
<p><strong>Patreon Supporters</strong></p>
<p>I intended to write this blog to you guys <em>before</em> making this public but unfortunately I sort of, err, accidentally announced the end of the show on stream the other night with Chris. Because of this, there seemed little point in holding it back.</p>
<p>Thank you very much for your support. The Patreon cash helps me pay for the servers that keep everything running (3 digital ocean droplets and 2 domain names) as well as purchase the occasional video game. Thank you!!!</p>
<p><strong>A Final Thought</strong></p>
<p>A Long time ago, when I was a baby in the Linux space I did this other ‘thing’ called QuestHard. It was that show (effort) that made me realise that I wanted to make video and bee part of this community. As I was writing all this, I thought back to that show. Turns out I had the Header still… Thought I would share it. No reason. Just a floating memory.</p>
<p><img src="../images/QH.png" /></p>
<p>Hopefully 2020 will be the start of another decade of building a community, making new friends, playing new games and, obviously. Making a LOT of new videos (and blogs…. I like blogs)</p>
<p>Thank you!</p>
<p><img src="../images/xpboot.png" /></p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>YouTube Stream tested</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/youtube-stream-tested.html</guid>
<pubDate>Kam, 12 Des 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I tested Streaming on YouTube. The VOD is set to UNLISTED but is embedded at the bottom of this post for you.</p>
<p>I played Destiny 2 (Stadia) while LinuxPaulM and ChrisWere hung out in chat. It was a good stream, I think.</p>
<p>I had a good time playing the game but setting up a stream on YouTube is a fucking chore! The chat seems laggy and has no time stamps. The final video is was lower quality than the stream was and that really odd!</p>
<p>Either way, I did not enjoy streaming via YouTube. Ill be back on Twitch Tomorrow.</p>
Here’s the video:
<div class="xpeng">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7FEZOgJ8Ae0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>
</iframe>
</div>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>gallery workflow</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/gallery-workflow.html</guid>
<pubDate>Rab, 11 Des 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>Super quick post to tell you RSS stalkers that there are not way more pictures in the thumbs gallery. I have also cobbled together a script to automate the generation of the gallery page so now its way easier for me to add to it. Going forward ill be putting some of the really old ones in there too (once I download them from YouTube)</p>
<p>I also rolled out the new gallery script on the PixelFridge.Club website too. Given that that site (in theory) is all about the images, it made sense to actually post images on there.</p>
<p>Anyway, please do check it out. I happen to think its good.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Halo Reach and one session gaming</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/halo-reach-and-one-session-gaming.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sel, 10 Des 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<pre><code> ..|&#39;&#39;||   &#39;|.   &#39;|&#39; &#39;||&#39;&#39;&#39;&#39;|     &#39;||&#39;  &#39;||&#39; &#39;||&#39; |&#39;&#39;||&#39;&#39;|
.|&#39;    ||   |&#39;|   |   ||  .        ||    ||   ||     ||
||      ||  | &#39;|. |   ||&#39;&#39;|        ||&#39;&#39;&#39;&#39;||   ||     ||
&#39;|.     ||  |   |||   ||           ||    ||   ||     ||
 &#39;&#39;|...|&#39;  .|.   &#39;|  .||.....|    .||.  .||. .||.   .||.</code></pre>
<p>Last night I played Halo:Reach. When I loaded it I had around 30 mins logged. I started a new game and exited when I had finished the campaign. I currently have 8 hours logged. I it was a very shooty night, and I stayed awake for many more hours than I really should have done.</p>
<p>The thing is, while I enjoyed the game it wasn’t compelling enough to make me play it in one hit. I was just in the right mood and had the free time. The thing is though, I think I actually enjoyed it way more because I played it in one session.</p>
<p>The shooting was solid but the level designs were confusing and there is many things in that game that can kill you with one hit, often without telegraphing the attack at all.</p>
<p>But, with that in mint it still felt like a complete story from start to finish and while the difficulty curve was a fucking roller coaster, the environmental progression was on point!</p>
<p>I really noticed how the visuals flowed through the world as I progressed in a way that I don’t think I would have done if I had played it over the period of a week like I usually do with games. I think it allowed me to see intended visual progression in a way that I usually miss.</p>
<p>The overall visual style of Halo Reach isn’t going to any awards for originality but the way is sweeps the player from a metallic military structure in the middle of a barren grass land to a very full feeling near future city (one on fire mostly) then to the fringes of a desert. It’s all quite striking.</p>
<p>The enemy forces are lush in oranges and purples against the stark browns and greys of the human structures. They look alien and interesting while the Humans look grey, mostly. I wonder if this is because they were heading for realism or if the designers just went a little nuts with making them convincingly alien.</p>
<p>I knew all of these things before playing, obviously. I have played a couple of Halo titles over the years but that was a long time ago. All these years later I think I may have developed more of an eye for these things. However, I still think it was all more apparent because I played for such a long stretch of time.</p>
<p>I think that maybe something of an insult to the game though. As I shot my way through this world, I was rarely thinking about the mechanics or the task in hand. I have no idea what was happening from a plot point of view either. The visuals while sparse were the things that kept me going through the game.</p>
<p>Regardless of my thoughts about the game as a whole though, the ‘Pillar of Autumn’ level was <em>very</em> good indeed. That one level, I was 100% on-board with the game. It did a good job of making me feel like I was battling for my life from start to finish!</p>
<p>You can see <a href="https://youtu.be/YJPzwXtHoBU">my video</a> on this over on You Tube (Technically its not released until a few days after I post this but here, have it now!)</p>
<div class="xpeng">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YJPzwXtHoBU" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>
</div>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>My creative workflow</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/my-creative-workflow.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sen, 02 Des 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<pre><code>  .,-::::: :::::::..  .,::::::   :::. ::::::::::::   ...    :::::::..
,;;;&#39;````&#39; ;;;;``;;;; ;;;;&#39;&#39;&#39;&#39;   ;;`;;;;;;;;;;&#39;&#39;&#39;&#39;.;;;;;;;. ;;;;``;;;;
[[[         [[[,/[[[&#39;  [[cccc   ,[[ &#39;[[,   [[    ,[[     \[[,[[[,/[[[&#39;
$$$         $$$$$$c    $$&quot;&quot;&quot;&quot;  c$$$cc$$$c  $$    $$$,     $$$$$$$$$c
`88bo,__,o, 888b &quot;88bo,888oo,__ 888   888, 88,   &quot;888,_ _,88P888b &quot;88bo,
  &quot;YUMMMMMP&quot;MMMM   &quot;W&quot; &quot;&quot;&quot;&quot;YUMMMYMM   &quot;&quot;`  MMM     &quot;YMMMMMP&quot; MMMM   &quot;W&quot;</code></pre>
<p><img src="../images/create.png" /></p>
<p>The terms ‘creator’ or ‘author’ even ‘artist’ are all totally bollocks. I mean it. Totally self important words that make the person who is accused of being the ‘thing’ special. It’s like bottling your own shit and then talking about the aroma.</p>
<p>The reality is that every human alive needs only three things to make a thing that other people may or may not like. None of them are special:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Desire to make stuff.</li>
<li>Opportunity to make stuff.</li>
<li>Repetition of making stuff (to ‘get good.’)</li>
</ol>
<p>There is also a 4th thing that can help in this regard and that’s:</p>
<ol start="4" type="1">
<li>Natural Aptitude.</li>
</ol>
<p>Number 4 is one of those things that most people don’t have, so it can be ignored. Also, if you do have a dose of number 4, you won’t know it. Unless your a self obsessed prick. So if you think you have number 4, then its more likely you don’t, but you are a self obsessed prick so you think you do.</p>
<p>In the following ramble its worth knowing that I (HexDSL) have had a large portion of number 1, a normal sized portion of number 2 and more of number three than most people realise (none of number 4.)</p>
<p>The video’s that I make and upload to YouTube or stream on Twitch are designed to entertain and occasionally inform. I am not claiming to know anything other than my own preferences and habits. These are what I share with you in this post. I am also not claiming that the stuff I make is good. It’s fun to make and fills a hole that used to be there in my mind.</p>
<p>Under each application suggestion I have added a link to “get it” thats nonsense obviously you should use your package manager but if you wanted to read more, then it maybe of use to have a link.</p>
<h2 id="video-capture-and-editing.">Video Capture and Editing.</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>OBS</strong>: The most integral part of making a video is recording that video. In this case I use OBS. SimpleScreenRecorder (SSR) is another good option and some people write their own scripts to layout their screen and record it with ffmpeg. There is no wrong way to record video as long as it doesn’t look shit in the end. Personally I favour OBS because I can edit a layout while recording and change scenes with shortcut keys.</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="../images/obs.png" /></p>
<p>For scene changes while I’m streaming I do not use one of those ‘Stream Decks’ as the are expensive. Instead I use a £7 wireless Number pad. It works great and as its wireless I can adjust it so its always at hand. OBS seems to get on fine with it but it does mean I can’t play Rogue likes with it while OBS it open. Not something most people care about I wouldn’t think.</p>
<p><a href="https://obsproject.com/download">Get OBS</a></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Kdenlive</strong>: This is the video editor that I like. There are many editors but I like this one. The thing that Sticks out to me is that its got a good Work-flow that is easy to learn but it also has a lot of effects and adjustments that you can add to video with very little effort. I suppose really, whatever video editor you get used to will work for most projects. Your preferences will form as you try to work with either long or complex projects. I also use an older version of Kdenlive because the newer versions have some odd GUI things going on and I decided that I would abstain for updates until I here its got over the code hump.</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="../images/kden.png" /></p>
<p><a href="https://kdenlive.org/en/">Get Kdenlive</a></p>
<h2 id="art-work">ART WORK</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>GIMP</strong>: Yes it has a stupid name. BUT an awesome mascot. I use GIMP for all my thumbnail and video asset needs. Granted by abilities are shit so I ask friend Cyberus to help (do it all) but GIMP is great. I use it to cobble together whatever my GIMP skills allow and it seems to do everything I need it to do.</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="../images/gimp.png" /></p>
<p>FYI the little mascott is called Wilber…. Apparently.</p>
<p>Also, Those people that are saying “its not as good as photoshop” you fuckers! Listen, unless you are using it at a high professional level theres a good chance that you dont actually need any of the shit Photoshop does. Just learn to use Gimp and get on with making shit. If you DO need Photoshop for more than meme motivated reasons. Go and use it and stop giving me a headache. Just piss off to windows or mac or something! for the rest of us, GIMP is bae! (I say ‘bae’ now apparently.)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gimp.org">Get GIMP</a></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Aseprite</strong>: Its an art package designed specifically to edit pixel art. Sounds stupid, I know. GIMP can do that. BUT Aseprite has cool option and the focus on Pixel art makes it a pleasure to use. I like Pixel Art but <a href="http://pixelfridge.club">I am bad at it.</a> The big down side is that while the older version is open source, its now a proprietary application. But also the git version looks the same as the one that I run via Steam to me. I had to include because I really like it but you should do way more looking into its license than I did… It was very boring.</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="../images/aseprite.png" /></p>
<p>I really do like this one. I love to draw. One day, I hope to be good.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.aseprite.org/">Get Aseprite</a></p>
<h2 id="perpetration">Perpetration</h2>
<p>Look, I know you expect some fancy office stuff here but the truth is, Locally I use NeoVim for all my working. That it. This blog was written in NeoVim and I don’t keep a word processor installed because NeoVim does it all. Actually when I have to use Microsoft Word or something at work I am always shocked at how shit it is. Writing in NeoVim is like having a supernatural connection to your computer. You don’t have to actually think about what you want to happen to the words, you just type the words and all the formatting and manipulation is done by your fingers while you are thinking of the next thing to type. Yeah. I am a Vim obsessed dude for sure.</p>
<p>You do have to learn Vim though. Learning it is the hard part. I’m not qualified to teach you either. Go to YouTube and type “vim basics” and I’m sure there will be a highly rated video that will educate you better than I could.</p>
<p>For any collaborative editing I need to do with a channel guest I use <a href="https://hackmd.io/">HackMD</a> Its a free markdown editor that’s bloody good and you can share a document by linking the URL its GREAT for editing show notes or group lists… Shame its not as good as Vim! )</p>
<h2 id="pc-setup">PC Setup</h2>
<p>Okay, I’m not going point by point here because I’m not sure there is any point. Most people just want to know the graphics package that I recommend or the capture software I use. But My PC setup is well documented on my Channel.</p>
<p>I use a shitty I7 3770 with 16GB of RAM, an NVIDIA 970 and a shitload of storage that I don’t really need. My phone is a Pixel 3 (not that anyone should care.) I have 3 Benq Monitors that are 27 inch. They are 1080 Screens. Long term I want to switch to a laptop and a dock. Given that most games I play are little Indie titles its hard to care about that 970 I have.</p>
<h2 id="os-and-desktop-choices">OS and desktop choices</h2>
<p>I run Arch. Because I like the AUR and the way it doesn’t have lots of pre-installed packages to remove. I use DWM as my Window Manager. All the config stuff is hosted on my Gitlab page in the form of DIFF files.</p>
<p>I use Zsh instead of bash because I like how it handles history and its Syntax completion is better than the alternative in my opinion.</p>
<p>My terminal of choice is URXVT (as client/server not single instances) and i use Ranger for file management. When I do need a GUI file manager (when edit artwork or video files its easier to have Drag and Drop) I use Thunar (Because I like it)</p>
<p>I use DUNST for notification and NeoMutt for Email. Oh, and Wiichat for IRC.</p>
<p>My web browser of choice is FireFox but I use lots of add-ons and tweaks to make it how i like it.</p>
<p>Thats it…. I think I Covered Everything.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>A rewarding feeling</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/a-rewarding-feeling.html</guid>
<pubDate>Rab, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<pre><code> .d8888b. 888b     d888888     888 .d8888b.
d88P  Y88b8888b   d8888888     888d88P  Y88b
Y88b.     88888b.d88888888     888888    888
 &quot;Y888b.  888Y88888P888888     888888
    &quot;Y88b.888 Y888P 888888     888888  88888
      &quot;888888  Y8P  888888     888888    888
Y88b  d88P888   &quot;   888Y88b. .d88PY88b  d88P
 &quot;Y8888P&quot; 888       888 &quot;Y88888P&quot;  &quot;Y8888P88</code></pre>
<p>One of the things that I enjoy about my online life is that it is both more organised and more productive than my real life. I often make things using my computer but never make things without it.</p>
<p>Some times I take a sit down and think about how my things are going. I have to say, at the moment things, in a creative sense, are very well.</p>
<p>Things that are going on:</p>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Visual Novel</strong> I haven’t spoken about this too much recently because I worry that I maybe deeply boring but I’m slowly chipping away at the VN, drawing a few scenes each week and adding to the plot. I have decided that even though I fully intend to voice every line, its best done in bulk when I am 100% done with the script. I love how easy Renpy is to work with and I love spending time learning to draw generally, Aseprite is still a good tool that I am enjoying a great deal.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>YouTube Channel</strong> I have literally NEVER missed an upload. 3 times a week like clockwork since I stopped doing a video a day a few years ago. Not sure if anyone else cares but I am pretty proud of that. At the time of typing this I have 6165 Subscribers and I appreciate how many people watch regularly.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Twitch</strong> I treat my Twitch streams as a hobby, not a serious commitment (I am a YouTuber firstly) and I have a blast streaming. I am sometimes low energy, sometimes high energy. Sometimes with friends. I try my best to to put on a ‘show’ so much as I try to hang out with the people that come and watch. The only time I’m fully in performance mode with streaming is the XPenguin podcast. Because of this I never stop enjoying the streaming but often life gets in my way a lot more than I would like and I have to skip evenings. I try not to beat myself up about it but it needs to be skipped some times for usually good reasons. At time of writing this I have 928 followers on Twitch. Given how relaxed and casual my streams are, I’m a little surprised that so many people press follow.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Community</strong> I love Community, making YouTube videos, streaming, hanging out in Discord/IRC - The people I have become friends with on the way have been my reward for all this stuff. Before I made the effort to begin making stuff I was pretty lonely. I spent many a night clicking away at games I didn’t care about watching TV shows to kill time. Now, all these years later, I am part of a community. I get to talk to the fiends I have met, talk to new people all the time. I get a bunch of email and comments from people and I feel like I’m constantly running out of time for things. The community of people that have come together around my video and streams have made my life measurably better. Thanks!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Patreon</strong> I find it hard to really ‘push’ the Patreon as it feels strange to be all like “Give me money… for… nothing… no, wait I mean, REASONS!” but I am going to try and mention it consistently at the end of my videos. To be honest, I mention it because I need the money for PC upgrades and other things I really can not afford (I am not a wealthy man, but I am a happy one) I hope this doesn’t bother anyone. Oh, and thank you so much to all the people who already support me. I mean it when I say that all support helps me a great deal and I really am grateful!</p></li>
</ul>
<p>Well there we have it, that’s everything I wanted to sort of mull over now I have essentially reset the Blog here. sooooo…..</p>
<p><strong>Future plans:</strong> Keep on doing what I’m doing. Have fun. Make new friends and get more views… because every new viewer could be a new friend one day :)</p>
<p>Thank you for taking the time to read (I dont proof read this…. just saying)</p>
<p>Love, Hex.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Stow a reflection</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/stow-a-reflection.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sel, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<pre><code>   _______________ _       __
  / ___/_  __/ __ \ |     / /
  \__ \ / / / / / / | /| / /
 ___/ // / / /_/ /| |/ |/ /
/____//_/  \____/ |__/|__/</code></pre>
<p>I made a <a href="https://youtu.be/vo1KUAb-ghc">Video about GNU Stow</a> a while back. The general idea behind it is that it works by using symlinks to essentially automatically manage your files. Most people use them for DOT (Config) Files.</p>
<p>Heres a super basic guide so you know how to use it…</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>install Stow (sudo pacman -S stow)</li>
<li>Make a folder in home, call its DOTS for easy remembering.</li>
<li>make a folder for each application you want to stash… store… stow.</li>
<li>in that folder mirror the location the file is found. for instance in my example I’m backing up the config for mpv. If its found in ~/.config/mpv/config.conf (its not) I would make a folder in DOTS like this ~/DOTS/.config/mpv/ and then MOVE all the shit from the old place to the new one.</li>
<li>repeat as required for all the shit you want to back up</li>
<li>Run ‘stow mpv’ (or other application name. )</li>
<li>Profit.</li>
</ol>
<p>Now you can back up your shit to a git service REALLY easy. Even I did it!</p>
<p>The reason I have been thinking a lot about stow is because I had my /home drive die the other week. Poof. 3TB gone! - sad times - Anyway… I had my Home drive die and while I did not have to reinstall my system I did have all my configs ripped out of my soul! so, I git cloned my own dot files. and then I ran my StowRestore script and I was done! Before I knew about stow, I had all sorts of shitty restore scripts and odd folder ideas. It was terrible.</p>
<p>When I find a program, and make a video about it I always wonder how much interest people will have in it. In the case of Stow, I can now say will all certainty that you SHOULD be using it because its GREAT and it saved me a LOT of work. All you have to do is remember to Stow new files as required! :)</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>By Grabthars Hammer I LOVE RSS</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/by-grabthars-hammer-i-love-rss.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sen, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p><img src="../images/grabnar.png" /></p>
<p>I have used RSS on and off for literally years now. More recently though the lack of a good desktop client with good syncing ability has killed that love a little for me but after a conversation with the wonderful Chris Were, this enthusiasm for the platform has rekindled my love.</p>
<p>The first problem I had was choosing a reader. After way less time than I expected I realised that I just love NewsBoat and wanted to use IT above the other offerings. I set it all up nice then made, <a href="https://youtu.be/B2mKiibJkhk">a video</a> The only problem I was having was that NewsBoat does not sync to any cloud service. Because of this, I was still mulling over a solution.</p>
<p>WRONG! - NewsBoat DOES have built in cloud syncing, and that MAD that is! - Turns out you can turn it on with just three lines in your Config file!!!!</p>
<p>So I made <a href="https://youtu.be/uCdxCJvja9Q">a Video</a> Explaining how!</p>
<p>Thank you SO MUCH to LinuxPaulM (From the Discord/Twitch chat) who pointed this out to me!</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>DNS is hard</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/dns-is-hard.html</guid>
<pubDate>Rab, 23 Okt 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<pre><code> ______   _        _______   _____
(  __  \ ( (    /|(  ____ \ / ___ \
| (  \  )|  \  ( || (    \/( (   ) )
| |   ) ||   \ | || (_____  \/  / /
| |   | || (\ \) |(_____  )    ( (
| |   ) || | \   |      ) |    | |
| (__/  )| )  \  |/\____) |    (_)
(______/ |/    )_)\_______)     _
                               (_)</code></pre>
<p>Okay, I know for an actual fact that basically no one reads this website. Part of that is because the DNS record over on GODADDY™ is messed up. Now I know GoDaddy is a shitty Company but I got this domain many years ago when I understood very little about these things.</p>
<p>The DNS seems to have what I think is TWO forwarders. One works properly and shows me the URL as intended. One always shows the top level domain. As to which one you get when you click. Yeah. It is left to the mighty and powerful Gods of the RNG.</p>
<p>I am going to attempt to fix this tonight. If it works the URL for this page you see right now will be correct even after a good many refreshes. I may have some down time. I don’t really understand DNS. Today however… I learn…</p>
<p>Just thought I would share this 😊</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>How to markdown</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/how-to-markdown.html</guid>
<pubDate>Jum, 18 Okt 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="how-to-markdown.">How to Markdown.</h1>
<p>Markdown is an easy to use Mark-up language that “looks” how it will render/format. It was first released in 2004 to be a simplified way to create thingsthat would be easily converted into HTML. Since that time its become quite a standard and has been adopted by Reddit, forums, a million applications, your Nan and the Gods themselves. It’s not only a good formatting system but its supernaturally easy. Once you get good at it (in about 10 mins) you can write notes, webpages, presentations, forum/reddit posts and shopping lists in it, as well as anything else you care to think of. You can even use Markdown in Discord messages if you want.</p>
<p>At this point Markdown is a sort of idea that gets bolted onto things. Because of this the rendered output maybe different depending what service you are using. When compiling/rendering it out to LaTex, Groff or HTML you should be fine because pandoc is forgiving and smart (and if you are not converting using pandoc, I need you to take a good long think about your life and… just, I don’t know… read a damned book or something because computers are not for you.) Odd website implementations on the other hand are a total crap shoot. If you are using a GUI tool for markdown, stop it right now and write an appology email to me.</p>
<p>Heres the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown">Wikipedia page</a> about Markdown. Good page that.</p>
<p>Anyway, here are the basics…</p>
<p>Horizontal Rule: <code>---</code> as above, and below</p>
<h3 id="bullets">BULLETS</h3>
<pre><code>* item
* item
* item</code></pre>
<p>looks like this</p>
<ul>
<li>Item</li>
<li>Item</li>
<li>Item</li>
</ul>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Capitalism stole reference culture</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/capitalism-stole-reference-culture.html</guid>
<pubDate>Rab, 16 Okt 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="a-critique-of-retro-gaming-or-shut-up-and-play-something-in-colour.">A Critique of Retro Gaming <em>or</em> Shut up and play something in colour.</h2>
<p><img src="../images/80s.jpg" /></p>
<p>Nerds like to reference things. When I was a kid, we would desperately try to work lines from Movies into conversations. The moment we got it out of our lips we would grin like idiots and look around seeing it anyone noticed. They always did.</p>
<p>Then, when I became an adult I did not, like my ancestors ‘put away childish things’ instead, I revelled in them. It’s an odd thing, the reverence of the past. I’m not sure it’s entirely healthy either.</p>
<p>I’m 39 years old as I write this and I have been casually obsessed with 80’s and 90’s media since, the 80’s and 90’s. I used to think that people loved the 80’s because it was a retro fix and nothing more.</p>
<p>It’s normal for any generation of people to enjoy the music, Movies and of their youth. Usually, when they hit their 50’s (ish) they get a little reluctant to experience new things and then bed down in the things that were cool when they were in their younger years. It’s not healthy but it is normal. Most people know that a fish has to keep swimming forward so it doesn’t die. People are basically just big land fish, and we have to emotionally swim to stay alive. Anyway, I digress.</p>
<p>The 80’s has proven to be oddly more attractive than simply being in the past like anyone else’s youth. It’s been embraced by people who weren’t born until it was long gone. I have satirically argued that culture peaked in the 80’s and has been getting shittier ever since. Thing is, the more I think about it the more it seems like it maybe an empirical fact.</p>
<p>I know, people reading this are now thinking that I’m being grumpy and old about it and am literally doing the aforementioned bedding into my past. But I’m honestly not. I’m a socially active person, I watch new things, play new games and I an constantly hungry for new ideas. I don’t feel like I’m slowing down or curling back into the 80’s but culture as a whole does seem to be obsessed with its own past. I have a few theories about this later in this post.</p>
<p>I should also take a moment to talk about nostalgia vs references. Most humans are nostalgic and quote movies they love, because they love them and the movies are in their brains. They like things that remind them of the comic books and games they play because they love them. The nostalgic leaks that they allow themselves to indulge in are referential as a side effect. Also, you may notice that it’s the classical Geek types that do this the most. Well, the reality is (and I speak from experience) the geeky kids watched these movies more than most because they had little else do to in a pre-internet world.</p>
<p>Here are my thoughts, in no specific order…</p>
<h2 id="the-disney-take-over">The Disney take over</h2>
<p><img src="../images/1evil.png" /></p>
<p>At some point, Disney started expanding their empire. The result is that they control everything “big” we see and hear. Even if they didn’t make it, they set the gold standard in quality and cinematic style. To make a high quality Movie is to make a Disney Movie.</p>
<p>It’s both impressive and deeply worrying that you could watch only Disney Movies for <strong>ever</strong> and pretty much see every film that matters to the general populous. This also means that Disney are in the unique position of being able to reference and pull from their own ideas while slapping everyone else with a DMCA. It’s a pretty impressive scam really.</p>
<h2 id="the-ernest-cline-method">The Ernest Cline Method</h2>
<p><img src="../images/evil2.png" /></p>
<p>Good old Ernest. An average writer that elevated his work via Referencing better things. The basic method was this,</p>
<ul>
<li>Write an average story</li>
<li>Pack it with Nostalgic/retro obsessed characters</li>
<li>Via described visuals and character dialogue pack it to the brim with 80’s references that appear to make sense within the story</li>
</ul>
<p>The reality is that simply saying a things name is not a warm loving reference. To say ‘knight rider’ is not a reference to ‘Knight Rider.’ To have a character drive a black Trans-am is not a reference. But, Having the Character Drive a Black Trans-am. One that he drives <strong>because</strong> he loves Knight Rider <strong>is</strong> a reference to Knight Rider. Mr Cline nailed this about 40% of the time during his book Ready Player One. He loved these things and it showed in the work. A work that without this would have been terrible. When Stephen “Over Rated” Spielberg made his Movie of the same work no-one on the production seemed to care much about the stuff in the Movie. Because of this it was less referential and more a ‘say the name of a thing and move on’ kind of Movie.</p>
<h2 id="retro-games">Retro games</h2>
<p><img src="../images/evil3.png" /></p>
<p>Now I have purged myself of that little rant. We get on to the meat of the conversation (it all ties in. At least, I think its does)</p>
<p>This is a controversial topic, I know. But, I assure you I too like to play older games. I’m a big fan of them actually.</p>
<p>There are two ways to play retro games. The first is the one I find the least tasteful. It is when someone only enjoys older games (they play lots of things but only enjoy old games) I can see the appeal of the 16bits. I enjoy an 8bits from time to time. A lot are genuinely fun but you literally can not claim that “old games are better” its not true. Even if you really like excite bike (and I do) you can in no way argue that it’s a better game than Mario Kart switch, Deus Ex, or dark Souls. You may prefer it. But it is not ‘better’ in any way that matters.</p>
<p>The other way of playing Retro Games is to simply enjoy lots of different games. I play loads of things. I play new games, old games. Some old games I have never played before. I enjoy lots of things and I enjoy them for what they are. I like mechanics and I like pixel-art visuals. But, I don’t think I like pixel art because its ‘retro’ I like pixel art because its to my tastes. I also really like the way Destiny 2 looks even though I haven’t played it. I recently enjoyed ‘Risk of Rain 2’ a great deal and there are no Pixels there. Overwatch is one of my favourite multi player games ever and its pretty darn modern looking. All this said, when the NES gaming service came to the Switch (NES-Flix) I played a crap load of Mario Golf (because its a great golf game) and City Connection ended up being a favourite of mine too. I had never played City Connection until it arrived on the service. The tight but simple controls hooked me from the moment I figured out what I was meant to accomplish.</p>
<h2 id="old-shit---new-shit---swimming">Old shit - New shit - Swimming</h2>
<p><img src="../images/evil4.png" /></p>
<p>With all this in mind I worry that we are obsessed with older stuff because in the modern day we are given a torrent of monetization nonsense, Franchise awareness, Brand building and worst of all unwanted follow-ups to things we loved as a kid.</p>
<p>I really think that the major reason people are so reverent of the previous decades is that you could enjoy a thing and not be beaten around the face by its merchandise, its follow ups and its fucking Micro Transactions.</p>
<p>I can play Excite bike and not have to but the new tracks. I can watch Ferris Bueller and not have to see the one movie an year and Super-bowel ad. The comparative purity of the past is attractive but that should not blind us to the great stuff we are surrounded by.</p>
<p>I think gamers get hit buy this worse. You can ignore new movies and music and no one seems to notice but gamers tend to live in the now. when you dont know what and ‘Untitled Goose Game’ is people raise an eyebrow. When you have never played Fortnight people wonder why.</p>
<p>Try things, try everything. Don’t get intimidated by the wall of modernism that you are faced with. Push past the meme culture. Im pretty sure there are lots of new things you would love.</p>
<h2 id="preaching-to-my-me">Preaching to my me</h2>
<p><img src="../images/evil5.png" /></p>
<p>The honest truth here is. That I generally speaking don’t enjoy Movies. Not just new ones. But Movies in general. Mostly I think that a 2 hour story is usually a bad one. I prefer long for story telling and you know… comic books!</p>
<p>Because I allowed myself to get into a mindset where ‘I do not like movies’ I have been missing things that I would love. Not liking movies was beginning to be a mantra that was blinding me to new things.</p>
<p>I was deciding I hated them out of habit. Oddly, it was watching something VERY new and VERY modern that broke me out of this habit.</p>
<p>I watched Spider-man: Into the Spider-Verse and it was so good it broke down my barrier. It was striking and perfect and filled to the brim with joy. So much that my cynicism was not strong enough to push through it. Over the next couple of days I realised there was a lot of things that I had hated because of pre-conception and now I’m working on myself to sift through whats actually shite and what I made myself hate because of an idea.</p>
<p>I worry that Lots of people do the game with ‘new’ games and I don’t want to stop swimming.</p>
<p>Hex.</p>]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>This is a test of a NEW BLOG SYSTEM</title>
<guid>https://podsni.github.io//posts/this-is-a-test-of-a-new-blog-system.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sel, 01 Okt 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>Today I test.</p>
<p>This is is not a post. its a test… I am testing right now…</p>
<p>The thing I’m testing is as <a href="https://gitlab.com/uoou/blop">THIS THING!</a> that Drew made :)</p>
<p>This wonderful thing means I can finally no use LB, a substandard tool that forced me to use HTML when all I wanted in life was to write in Markdown! - Anyway, thanks for reading. I hope this post went well! :)</p>]]></description>
</item>



</channel>
</rss>
